Academia Sinica's September governor's feast lecture begins
中央研究院9月知事祝賀講演会が始まる
Director Wu Chongli of the Secretariat asked us to host
事務局の呉崇利局長から私たちに主催を依頼されました。
Thank you all for coming to the governor's feast tonight
今夜の知事祝賀会にご来場いただきありがとうございます
Originally, it was because Vice President Huang wanted to come over.
もともとは黄副総統が来たいということでした。
But because he has other important matters at the moment, he can't come here
しかし、彼は今他の重要な用事があるため、ここに来ることができません
So it's just me doing the scraping here
ここでスクレイピングを行っているのは私です
Then tonight's speech should be very exciting.
そうすれば、今夜のスピーチはとても刺激的なものになるはずです。
The speaker is Mr. Li Zhende from our 11th school.
講演者は第11校の李振徳さんです。
And the theme is when history meets gender
そしてテーマは歴史がジェンダーと出会うときです
this is teacher li
こちらは李先生です
Bouncing off the fragments of the sixth-century Bhikkhu Yuanni's tombstone in the Reread collection
再読コレクションにある 6 世紀の元尼比丘の墓石の破片が跳ね返る
Then I still think Mr. Li should be familiar to everyone in the history circle.
それなら、李氏は歴史界の誰もがよく知っているはずだと私は今でも思っています。
But for me, I think I should introduce Teacher Li a little bit more.
しかし、私としては、リー先生をもう少し紹介する必要があると思います。
Teacher Li has a bachelor's degree in history from National Taiwan University and a master's degree in history from National Taiwan University.
リー先生は国立台湾大学で歴史学の学士号を取得し、国立台湾大学で歴史学の修士号を取得しています。
Went to the University of Washington in Seattle to obtain a Ph.D. in History
歴史学の博士号を取得するためにシアトルのワシントン大学に留学
Now he is working as a researcher at our Institute of History and Research
現在、彼は歴史研究研究所の研究員として働いています。
In fact, I interacted with Mr. Li in many meetings.
実際、私は李氏と多くの会合で交流しました。
He is a very gentle lady with a good personality and very knowledgeable questions.
とても穏やかな女性で、人柄も良く、質問も丁寧です。
So what she does is to explore from the perspective of gender
そこで彼女がやっているのは、ジェンダーの観点から探求することです
About the legal system between Hantang and medical care
漢唐と医療の間の法制度についてです
She has a lot of books and the explanations are very interesting.
彼女はたくさんの本を持っていて、その説明はとても興味深いです。
It's called the death of the princess. What you don't know about Chinese legal history
それは王女の死と呼ばれています。あなたが知らない中国法の歴史について
He also has another book that is also well known
彼は別の本も持っていますが、これも有名です
is a woman's history of Chinese medicine
女性の中国医学の歴史です
Health care and gender among Han tangs
漢唐の健康管理とジェンダー
In addition, he has also read many papers
さらに、彼は多くの論文も読んでいます
and edited Gender Body and Medical
ジェンダー・ボディとメディカルを編集
Academician Liang Qizhi
学者梁啓之
co-edited women and society and more
女性と社会などを共同編集
In recent years, he is also an Asia
近年ではアジア人でもある
Editor-in-Chief of the Major
メジャー編集長
Now Editor-in-Chief of New Historiography
現在、『新歴史』編集長
Because of his personal history
彼の個人的な経歴のせいで
So I'm often in many awards
だから私はよく多くの賞を受賞しています
I have seen Mr. Li's name
李さんの名前を見たことがあります
including the Distinguished Research Award from the National Science Council
米国科学会議からの優秀研究賞を含む
This is a very important indicator in our science and technology department
これは私たちの科学技術部門にとって非常に重要な指標です
In addition, it is also in the Distinguished Talent Lecture
また、優秀人材講座にもあります
It seems like two years ago three years ago
２年前３年前のような気がする
Funding is currently in progress
現在資金調達中です
Apparently it is in the current Taiwan historian circle
現在の台湾の歴史家界隈にあるらしい。
very important person
要人
Then I won't talk nonsense anymore
そうすればもう無駄なことは言わないよ
Then I will give the stick to Teacher Li
それから私はその棒を李先生に渡します
Mr. Li thank you
李さん、ありがとう
ladies and gentlemen
皆様
thank you so much everyone for tonight
みなさん、今夜は本当にありがとうございました
Just after the Mid-Autumn Festival, I worked hard to come here
中秋節が終わってから、頑張ってここに来ました
Listening to the speech is really admirable
スピーチを聞くのは本当に素晴らしいです
then i'm glad to be here today
それでは今日ここに来られて嬉しいです
Share it with everyone
みんなと共有しましょう
actually i think
実際私は思う
able to receive this knowledge
この知識を受け取ることができる
miss is to feel very honored
とても光栄に思います
Mainly every time I see
主に見るたびに
When this poster of Knowledge Missing came out
「Knowledge Missing」のこのポスターが出たとき
I feel that each of the above
上記のそれぞれのことを感じます
They are all scholars I admire
彼らは皆、私が尊敬する学者です
i was thinking
私が考えていた
Hey, what is the extent of this?
ねえ、これはどのくらいの範囲ですか？
Only then can we be told
そうして初めて私たちは言えるのです
After working here for 26 years
ここで26年間働いた後、
finally it's my turn
ついに私の番です
I feel very honored
とても光栄に思います
So what I'm going to tell you today is
そこで今日私が皆さんにお伝えすることは、
is when history meets gender
歴史がジェンダーと出会うとき
The subtitle says to use this
サブタイトルにはこれを使うと書いてあります
"The Sixth Century Collected by Futu"
「フツが集めた6世紀」
Bhikkhu Yuanning Muzhi collapsed to talk about it
元寧穆志比丘はそのことについて話すために倒れた
In fact, the main thing is to use this chip
実際、主なことはこのチップを使用することです
come be a shadow
影になって来てください
Hope to share with you
皆さんと共有できれば幸いです
some in recent years
近年ではいくつか
Sex with Women's History
セックスと女性の歴史
or historical research
あるいは歴史研究
on the relevant results
関連する結果について
this should be opened first
これを最初に開く必要があります
After opening
開封後
yes not open yet
はい、まだ開いていません
So pressing it won't work
なので押してもダメです
open?
開ける？
yes to this not to this
はい、これには反対です
I'm sorry, thank you
ごめんなさい、ありがとう
This year is Academia Sinica
今年は中央研究院です
90th Anniversary Celebration
創立90周年記念式典
It is also the celebration of the 90th anniversary of more than ten institutes
10以上の研究機関の90周年記念式典でもある
Actually 90 years ago
実は90年前
when the unit was established
ユニット設立時
in Chinese history
中国の歴史の中で
basically
基本的
Not long after the May Fourth Movement
五四運動から間もなく
probably still receiving
おそらくまだ受信中
Impact of the May Fourth Movement
五・四運動の影響
under the influence of
の影響下で
at that moment
その瞬間に
almost
ほとんど
almost 90 years ago
約90年前
From one book to today
一冊の本から今日まで
are still influential
まだ影響力がある
everyone may also read
皆さんも読んでみてください
many teenage friends
十代の友達がたくさんいる
Young friends, at least I was the same
若い友人たち、少なくとも私は同じでした
When I first came into contact with the study of women's history
私が初めて女性史研究に出会ったとき
a book that will come across
出逢える本
That was around 1926 or 28
それは1926年か28年頃のことでした
It was also a book published almost 90 years ago
こちらも90年近く前に出版された本です
Chen Dongyuan's Life History of Chinese Women
陳東元の中国人女性の生涯
In the earliest part of that book he was
その本の最初の部分で彼はこう言った
In fact, it was issued by the Commerce Department
実はこれは商務省が発行したものです
Later in Taiwan, Taiwan Business also printed
その後、台湾でも台湾ビジネスも印刷されました
I own these two
私はこの2つを所有しています
One is the first teacher of my women's envoy
一人は私の女性特使の最初の先生です
Teacher Bao Jialing gave it to me
鮑嘉玲先生が私にくれました。
When I was a freshman in National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学1年生のとき
he is my mentor
彼は私の指導者です
And he was just coming back from America
そして彼はちょうどアメリカから帰ってきたところだった
One year
課座一年
That's still assigned a tutor
それはまだ家庭教師が割り当てられています
I was lucky enough to be his tutor
私は幸運にも彼の家庭教師になれました
Then he gave me a copy
それから彼は私にコピーをくれました
this blue leather
この青い革
I'm still on that desk
私はまだその机の上にいます
Later, because of reluctance
その後、不本意な事から
keep touching because it is very old
とても古いものなので触り続けてください
So I went and bought a pink one myself
それで私は自分でピンクのを買いに行きました
Use it to browse, use it to check information
閲覧するのに使う、情報を確認するのに使う
There is a passage in this book
この本の中にこんな一節がある
I was from a very young age of nineteen
私は19歳というとても若い頃から
I was very impressed when I saw it at the age of eighteen or nineteen
18、19歳の時に観てとても感動しました
He said my book
彼は私の本を言いました
I'm not trying to support some Holy Mother
私は聖母を支持するつもりはない
I don't want to push for some empress
皇后を推すつもりはない
Female heroes vent their anger on women
女性ヒーローが女性への怒りをぶつける
Because most people
なぜなら、ほとんどの人は
girls don't matter
女の子は関係ない
i just want to point out
ただ指摘したいのですが
What kind of gaffe is the idea that men are superior to women
男性が女性より優れているという考えはどのような失言ですか
What kind of Zengsheng is the destruction of women
女性破壊とはどのような曾生ですか？
What kind of historical regression still weighs on the number of women now
どのような歴史的退行が現在も女性の数に重くのしかかっているのか
That is to say around 1926 2728
つまり1926年頃 2728
It is the May 4th movement that wants to overthrow the old tradition
古い伝統を覆そうとするのは5.4運動です
Then bring new thinking
それから新しい考え方を持ち込む
In the process of new atmosphere
新しい雰囲気の途中
In fact, women's identity, women's status, women's situation
実際、女性のアイデンティティ、女性の地位、女性の状況
scholars or intellectuals
学者や知識人
An indicator of great concern
非常に懸念される指標
So Chen Dongyuan wrote such a book
陳東元はこのような本を書きました
His purpose is to tell everyone
彼の目的はみんなに伝えることです
The lives of women in China are actually very miserable
中国の女性の生活は実際には非常に悲惨です
He wants to tell everyone the fact
彼はその事実をみんなに伝えたいと思っている
Then we need to draw everyone's attention, hoping to reform
それから私たちは改革を望んでみんなの注目を集めなければなりません
Then you can have a change of heart
そうすれば気分転換もできるよ
Right around the time this book was published
この本が出版された頃
around this time
この頃
Another thing was actually unearthed in Luoyang
実は洛陽でもう一つ出土したものがある
that's what we're going to talk about today
それが今日私たちが話すことです
Wei Gujiang
魏古江
open it
それを開く
Wei Gujiang, General Wei Gu Cheji
魏古江、魏古チェジ将軍
Safety
平安
Wen Dingxing sends his wife the preface
温定興さんは妻に序文を送った
Anyone who can finish reading can be a historian
読み終えることができれば誰でも歴史家になれる
A man who can eat a mouthful of youth can speak
若さを一口食べることができる人は話すことができる
This Mu Zhiming was about 80 or 90 years ago
この穆志明は80年か90年ほど前のことです。
Unearthed in Luoyang, Henan
河南省洛陽出土
Then he received in
それから彼は受け取りました
After being unearthed by Fujinen Makishi above
上記真喜志藤念出土後
There are collapsed pieces, that is, after falling down with this ink tile
崩壊した部分があります。つまり、このインクタイルが落ちた後です。
Then this piece is now in the collection
そして、この作品は現在コレクションにあります
Academia Sinica Lishi Research Institute
中央研究院力士研究所
It is in the Fujinian library of my unit
私のユニットの藤仁図書館にあります
Then his size is about
それから彼のサイズは約です
57×57 cm
57×57cm
So this screen actually magnifies it a little bit.
したがって、この画面は実際には少し拡大しています。
If you go to Futu to see this collapse
この崩壊を見にフツに行ったら
It's not that big
そんなに大きくないよ
That is to say, its original tombstone was not so big.
つまり、元々の墓石はそれほど大きくなかったのです。
But it's a bit big
でもちょっと大きいですね
Gravestone with a little weight
少し重みのある墓石
And then the collapse
そして崩壊
On the login of Shi Yu's office, it says
Shi Yuのオフィスのログインには次のように書かれています
Sir Yuan Ni Mu Zhiming Bing Xu
袁尼武卿志明冰徐
It's the front and the back
表と裏ですよ
There is this preface stating that such a person is buried in it
こんな人が埋もれているという序文がある。
Then the hostess that Mu Zhiming talked about
それから、Mu Zhiming が話したホステス
what kind of person is he
彼はどんな人ですか
what about his age
彼の年齢はどうですか
Because in this place for the second year of Yongan
永安二年この場所だから
So there is a seven-day holiday in November Monokage
なので11月は7連休あります ものかげ
So we know that the shepherd
それで私たちは羊飼いが
This mu, Muzi was in the second year of Yong'an, and he was in the north.
この穆、穆子は永安二年、北にいた。
It was built in 529, the second year of Yong'an
永安2年529年に建てられました。
so we can know
それで私たちは知ることができます
This, this, Mu Zhiming, was around that time
これ、これ、Mu Zhiming はその頃でした
That thing is about the same
あれもそれと同じくらいだよ
It is in this turbulent May Fourth
この激動の5月4日の中で
In the process of this trend
この流れの過程で
was found trampled
踏みつけられているのが発見された
Later, I received them from 11 libraries.
その後、11の図書館から届きました。
That's what we're talking about here
それがここで話していることです
In this bhikkhu garden
この比丘の庭で
The woman Mu Zhiming talked about
穆志明が話した女性
what kind of story is it
それはどんな話ですか
Actually I was hoping
実は期待していたのですが
if today was in my class
もし今日が私のクラスだったら
I will ask the students to read it
学生たちに読んでもらいます
break this shepherd's back
この羊飼いの背中を折る
then think
それから考えてください
Everyone can be more awake
誰もがもっと冷静になれる
Then enter the condition
次に条件を入力します
But it doesn't look like it's here
でもここにはないようだ
They all look old and have white hair and long hair, they are older than me
彼らは皆老けて見えて、白髪で髪が長くて、私よりも年上です。
I am too embarrassed to ask everyone to read this Mu Zhiming
恥ずかしくて皆さんにこの記事を読んでもらうことはできません Mu Zhiming
But so I figured it out
しかし、それで私はそれを理解しました
Type this into a normal text file
これを通常のテキスト ファイルに入力します
Hope to let you know more
もっと知っていただければ幸いです
at least understand what this is talking about
少なくともこれが何を言っているのか理解してください
Let's take a look at the nomination just now
今のノミネートを見てみましょう
He said that he is the general of car technology
彼は自動車技術の将軍だと言いました
Ping Shu Written Actions
平書文定行功
Mrs. Ji
ジーさん
Grand Jazz Monk Yuan Ning Mu Zhiming continued
グランドジャズモンク、ユアン・ニン・ムー・ジーミン 続き
So just by looking at the title, you can probably guess
タイトルを見ただけで大体想像がつくと思いますが、
the first he was a bhikkhunin
最初は比丘尼だった
That is, he is a nun
つまり彼は修道女です
And his bhikkhu ning the monastery where he became a monk
そして彼の比丘は彼が僧侶になった僧院に行きました
or the temple he belongs to is grand lord
もしくは所属する寺院が大領主か
Great Jazz of Luoyang
洛陽のグレート ジャズ
He died in the identity of the monk Ning Luoyang
彼は僧侶寧洛陽として亡くなった
But this identity is his last identity
しかし、このアイデンティティは彼の最後のアイデンティティです
not all his identities
彼のアイデンティティのすべてではない
can see ahead of him
彼の前が見える
one of his identities is
彼のアイデンティティの一つは
He is Mrs. Xing Gong Ji
彼はシン・ゴン・ジさんです。
That is to say, a certain line
つまり、ある一行
sacrifice of man
人間の犠牲
is the palace
宮殿です
In fact, we checked the information
実際に情報を確認してみたところ、
I know it's a row wheel
手漕ぎホイールだとわかっています
He is the empress of the history of Northwest University
彼はウェンディ皇后です ノースウェスト大学の歴史
a very important general
非常に重要な将軍
But it is said that he is also very personable
でもとても優しい性格だとも言われています
dashing and handsome
勇敢でハンサムな
There may also be ministerial civil servants
大臣公務員もいるかもしれない
such a patient person
そういう忍耐強い人
no matter what
何があっても
This round mud made his sacrifice, Mrs. Sacrifice
この丸い粘土が彼の犠牲となりました、夫人。
After becoming the wife of the sacrifice
生贄の妻になってから
later he died
その後彼は亡くなった
As a bhikkhu Yuanni
元尼比丘として
buried after death
死後埋葬される
that this
これは
What is this Mu Zhiming talking about?
この穆志明は何を言っているのでしょうか？
First
初め
Mrs Hui Cunda
ホイ・クンダさん
rule of law
法の支配
Grandson of Emperor Gongzong
公宗皇帝の孫
Rencheng the fifth daughter of King Kang
廉成は康王の五女。
So it looks like he belongs to the emperor's family
どうやら天皇家の一族のようですね
right
右
his father was a certain prince
彼の父親はとある王子だった
he is the prince
彼は王子です
Recognized as Kang Wang's fifth daughter
カン・ワンの五女として認められる
Then Mu Zhiming, if everyone
それでは、Mu Zhiming、もし皆さんなら
Read a little bit of Mu Zhiming's words
Mu Zhiming の言葉を少し読んでください
Or don't be Mu Zhiming
さもなければ、Mu Zhiming にならないでください
That is, if there is always the opportunity to attend a funeral
つまり、常に葬儀に参列する機会があるのであれば、
like me
私のような
then you might
そうすれば、あなたはそうするかもしれません
You'll read a lot of stories like this
このような物語をたくさん読むでしょう
People don't call shapes anymore
人々はもう形を呼びません
life story
人生の話
It's usually very well written.
通常は非常によく書かれています。
Regardless of whether this child used to
この子がかつてそうであったかどうかに関係なく、
when this person was young
この人が若い頃
how to get along with this man
この男とどうやって付き合っていけばいいのか
No matter what this person's past
この人の過去がどうであれ
naughty missile
いたずらなミサイル
But what about in Kinokana is usually good
でも、キノの名前の場合は通常良いです
Packing fish have poor jobs and poor forests
パック詰めの魚の仕事は貧しく、森林も貧弱だ
are very beautiful
すべてとても美しい
It looks beautiful and the wind is good
見た目も綺麗で風も気持ち良いです
flag from year
年の旗
rocking boat filet
搖條船魚貫魚
When he was very young and his hair was short
彼がまだ若くて髪が短かった頃
smart at a young age
若い頃から賢い
And what about his demeanor?
そして彼の態度はどうですか？
When he tied the heads of two little uncles
彼が二人の小さな叔父の頭を縛ったとき
it can already be seen
それはすでに見えています
is such a daughter
そんな娘ですか
a girl
女の子
Kang Wang loves his father more
カン・ワンは父親をもっと愛しています
It is recommended to pay attention to women
女性には注意することをお勧めします
love him very much
非常愛他
different from other daughters
他の娘たちとは違う
Long live in the arms never leave the applause
腕の中で長生きしてください、拍手が鳴り響くことはありません
But at the age of seven
しかし7歳のとき
his father died
彼の父親が亡くなった
he is very filial
彼はとても親孝行です
know without learning
学ばずに知っている
father died very loving love hurt
父はとても愛情深く亡くなりました愛が傷つきました
Qi and blood worry
気と血の心配
cry every day like
毎日のように泣く
What comes out is not tears but blood
流れるのは涙じゃなくて血だ
What I eat seems to be eating the curse karma
私が食べているものは呪いのカルマを食べているようだ
By the age of fifteen
15歳までに
Positive is when girls pull their hair up
女の子が髪をかき上げるのがポジティブです
when you can get married
いつ結婚できるか
Pastor Yan Gui married a man surnamed Mu
ヤン・グイ牧師はムーという姓の男性と結婚した
who is the pastor
牧師は誰ですか
In fact, this is from the Northern Wei Dynasty, that is Wei.
実はこれは北魏、つまり魏の時代のものです。
guard
衛
Then see General Gu Cheji
次にグ・チェジ将軍を参照
So I know he too
だから私も彼を知っています
He is both other people's
彼は両方とも他人のものです
His husband, Xinggong, has also passed away.
夫の興功さんも亡くなった。
Then this Tuoba in the Northern Wei Dynasty
そしてこの拓跋は北魏の時代に
They were originally in this ancestor's
彼らはもともとこの先祖の中にあった
His original surname was Tuoba
本姓は拓跋。
Later, because of the Sinicization of the school text
その後、学校教科書の中国化により
Change to Yuan
人民元に両替
This Tuoba and Mu
この拓跋とムー
Both are ancestors, very important
どちらも大切な先祖です
military aristocratic group
軍事貴族集団
Then the two families will Tuoba and Mu
その後、二家族は拓跋と穆になります。
Yuan Hemu
袁和木
are often married
結婚していることが多い
So when he was fifteen
それで彼が15歳のとき
she married Mu
彼女はムーと結婚した
then he was very
それから彼はとても
This is what the shepherds must have
これは羊飼いが持っていなければならないものです
very hard
とても厳しい
Female workers are very burdened
女性労働者の負担は大きい
The results of it
その結果
Mr. Mu
ムーさん
died shortly after
その後すぐに亡くなった
half
半分
Half of his body collapsed
身体の半分が崩れ落ちた
what half of the body fell down
体の半分が落ちたのは
When a woman marries each other, the two become one
女同士が結婚すると二人は一つになる
after being united
団結した後
If the husband dies, the woman will
夫が死ねば女性は
The other half of the body fell down.
体の残り半分は倒れてしまいました。
no more
もういや
so very sad
とても悲しい
he wants to be able to triple
彼は3倍になりたいと思っている
What is the so-called triple?
いわゆるトリプルとは何ですか？
repeated marriage at home
家庭内結婚を繰り返す
Repeat Resurrection Baryon
重複 複死 重子
But he had hoped so
しかし彼はそう望んでいた
But his elder brother and wife, King Wenxuan
しかし、彼の兄であり妻である文宣王は、
The wife of King Wen Xuan is called Yuan Cheng
文宣王の妻は袁成といいます。
It's Yuan Ni's brother Yuan Cheng
袁尼の弟、袁成です。
The only duoqing smoke is not allowed
デュオチンの喫煙だけは禁止です
against his morals
彼の道徳に反する
Violating Yuan Ni's morality
袁尼の道徳に反する
robbed him of his emotions
彼から感情を奪った
Just don't let him triple
ただ彼にトリプルをさせないでください
that means
つまり
must remarry
再婚しなければならない
remarry
再婚する
so who will you marry
それで誰と結婚しますか
and then the next
じゃあ次は
This is it
これだよ
Ping Shu Wen Ding Xinggong
ピン・シュー・ウェン・ディン・シンゴン
General Xiang
シャン将軍
I just said that
私はちょうどそれを言いました
Everyone thinks it's rich
誰もが裕福だと思っている
There are dancing money
踊るお金がある
Yun belongs to the relationship between Emperor Wen and Xiao Wenli
ユンは文帝とシャオ・ウェンリーの関係に属します
Very good, the air is like the rain Jun Cheng and the two are like the rain
とても良い、空気は雨のようだ ジュン・チェンと二人は雨のようだ
The joy of rain is not just for men and women
雨の喜びは男性と女性だけのものではありません
It is Mu Zhimingyan who is in the north
北にいるのはMu Zhimingyanです
You can tell it's like rain
雨のようだとわかります
Jun Sung is very compatible
ジュンソンはとても相性が良いです
like rain rain like water
雨のように雨が水のように
Mingguanshattered bone speaks good things
明関の砕けた骨は良いことを語る
Then this Yuan Ni will be his spouse
そうするとこの袁尼が彼の配偶者となる
The two of them are as good as a harp and as harmonious as a smoker
二人はハープのように上手で、喫煙者のように優しい
wisdom
智
Xunzhi, right? Lehui
荀志、そうですよね？
He Ru Xunzhi
何如荀志
Unspoken
暗黙の
It just shows how good the relationship between the two of them is.
それだけでも二人の関係がいかに良好であるかがわかります。
what does good mean
良いとはどういう意味ですか
He also has a very good relationship with her husband when he is at home.
夫が家にいるときは、夫との関係もとても良好です。
So good, how can the relationship be very good?
とても良い関係ですが、どうすればその関係がうまくいくのでしょうか？
look what he did
彼が何をしたか見てください
Of course the relationship with her husband will be very good.
もちろん夫との関係も良好になります。
The first Fenggu salute
最初の風谷敬礼
He is very hands on to his mother in law
彼は義母に対してとても親切です
Very respectful and filial to him
彼に対してとても敬意があり、親孝行です
Treat him like a gangster, Hirohito
彼をギャングのように扱いなさい、ヒロヒト
Treat him like nobody else, this girl
彼を他の誰でもないように扱ってください、この女の子
mother-in-law good
義母は良いです
to honor him
彼に敬意を表するために
on the other hand
一方で
be mediocre
平凡であること
He is the egg
彼は卵です
This Yuan Ni
この袁尼さん
This Mrs. Yuan and the egg
この袁夫人と卵
original other concubine
元のもう一人の側室
get along very well
とても仲良くなる
able to help evil
悪を助けることができる
It's a pleasure to get along with them
彼らと仲良くなれると嬉しいです
on the other hand
一方で
Son, a prostitute is a man
息子よ、売春婦は男です
Chang Shixun
チャン・シシュン
There is a shape
形があります
is one of his sons
彼の息子の一人です
Is this Yuan Ni's son?
この人は袁尼の息子ですか？
it doesn't look like
似ていません
Son Chang Shixun, a casual prostitute
子 散妓常世遜
Yuan can be stronger or stronger
人民元は強くても強くてもよい
Sheng Shan Juan En Qu was home
シェン・シャン・ファン・エン・クーは家にいた
Empathetic and Empress Dowager
共感と皇太后
out of the dragon
ドラゴンから出た
What's the meaning
どのような意味です
this is actually
これは実際に
Oval
楕円形
former wife's son
前妻の息子
Then Yuan Moumou
ソ・ユアン・モウモウ
Yuan Pure
元純妥
after marriage
結婚した後
What about the original son?
元の息子はどうなるのでしょうか？
see him when he was little
彼が小さかった頃を見てください
no mother
母はいない
so love him very much
だから彼をとても愛しています
what is the degree of love
愛情の度合いはどれくらいですか
higher than
よりも高い
more than one's own birth
自分の誕生以上のもの
Just love this season
この季節が大好きです
love their own children
自分の子供たちを愛する
more grand
もっと壮大な
below the level of
～のレベル以下
he lives here
彼はここに住んでいます
Xinranjia
新亂家
I'm talking about this part
この部分について話しているのです
Yuan Chuntuo's life after marriage
袁春佗の結婚後の生活
Then what next, he began to think
それで、次に何をするか、彼は考え始めました
how does he teach this young son
彼はこの幼い息子にどのように教えていますか
What about this season?
今シーズンはどうでしょうか？
Kim Hiran
キム・ヒラン
As long as there are poems and books in front of his eyes
目の前に詩と本がある限り
also teach this child
この子にも教えて
so beautiful
とても美しい
Director of Gongyan
ゴンヤン監督
Start function
スタート機能
Yuan Chuntuo can not only read poetry and books
袁春佛は詩や本を読むだけではない
And also work as a maid
そしてメイドとしても働きます
well done too
もよくやった
any type
いかなるタイプ
Sewing and knitting can't be difficult for him
彼にとって裁縫や織物は難しいことではない
and he wears clothes
そして彼は服を着る
not very weird
あまり奇妙ではない
to participate
参加する
What about when this idiot sweeps the closet?
このバカがクローゼットを掃除したらどうなる？
I wear clothes that have been washed many times
何度も洗濯した服を着ている
Doesn't ask to be glamorous
華やかであることを求めない
means a very economical one
非常に経済的なものを意味します
such a woman
そんな女性
Sex can be a female high school mother for a thousand years
女子高生の母親は千年セックスできる
Should be a very nice woman
とても素敵な女性になるはずです
The kind of woman who can be the mother of the world
世界の母親になれるような女性
can be a woman's guru
女性の教祖になれる
Such a person is like the guru of the female group
こういう人は女性グループの教祖のような人です
In the end, when it comes to the car record, who is it written in the car record?
結局、車の記録というと、車の記録には誰が書かれているのでしょうか？
It's messy
めちゃくちゃだ
after death
死後
when died
亡くなったとき
He is the second widowed
彼は二度目の未亡人のようだ
After his death he privately became Fude
死後は私的に筆となった
irreplaceable
業不尋替
This is how the pastor described his richness.
牧師は自分の豊かさをこう表現しました。
What does that mean
どういう意味ですか
when the husband died
夫が亡くなったとき
don't cry at night
夜に泣かないでください
only cry during the day
日中だけ泣く
Crying at night makes people feel
夜泣くと人はこんな気持ちになります
He's just missing his love
彼はただ愛を失っているだけだ
like a widow during the day
日中は未亡人のように
Still thinking about the bed
まだベッドのことを考えています
This is obviously for the husband
これは明らかに夫のためです
That is to say, he is not a very good rich man.
つまり、彼はあまり良いお金持ちではないのです。
and there is no way to show
そしてそれを示す方法はありません
husband married a
夫は結婚した
being a nice rich man
素敵な金持ちであること
So if it's a nice rich guy
それで、もしそれが素敵な金持ちだったら
when the husband died
夫が亡くなったとき
it is not allowed to cry at night
夜泣くことは許されません
can only cry during the day
日中しか泣くことができない
when crying during the day
日中泣いているとき
On the one hand, this can be avoided
一方で、これは回避できる
The one who thinks about the room all day long
一日中部屋のことを考えている人
Two words or two names
2 つの単語または 2 つの名前
On the other hand
一方で
When you cry during the day, you cry with the public
日中泣くときは、大衆と一緒に泣くことになる
Can demonstrate the virtue of the husband
夫の美徳を示すことができる
or his contributions to the public domain, etc.
またはパブリックドメインへの彼の貢献など。
but anyway
とにかく
privately
私的に
In order to be able to demonstrate the virtue of his husband
夫の徳を発揮できるように
So he is more irreplaceable
だから彼はもっとかけがえのない存在になる
recruit poor and humble
貧しく謙虚な者を募集する
then he lamented
それから彼は嘆いた
no life
生きていられない
I've been miserable all my life
私は生涯ずっと惨めだった
two more hard work
あと2回頑張れ
people leave me
みんなが私から離れていく
Altair
アルタイル
i didn't i'm ashamed
しませんでした、恥ずかしいです
I didn't keep a moral
モラルを守らなかった
what ethics
何の倫理
There is no second such conduct of his
彼のこのような行為は二度とない
It turned out that she was married to Mrs. Mu
彼女はムー夫人と結婚していたことが判明した
after death
死後
I was going to be alone and widowed
私は未亡人になって一人になるつもりだった
As a result, my brother won't let me be widowed
その結果、兄は私を未亡人にすることを許してくれません
I must be marrying
きっと結婚するはずだ
Must be after I get married
結婚してからに違いない
I become another him
私はもう一人の彼になる
I am ashamed
私は恥ずかしい
i didn't hold on
我慢しなかった
No other one of his worries
彼の心配事は他に何もない
I am ashamed
私は恥ずかしい
also very ashamed
それもとても恥ずかしい
my heart does not turn
私の心は回らない
I turned
私は向きを変えました
Because I got on well with Xingchao later on.
後になってシンチャオと仲良くなったから。
It looks like it's good, doesn't it?
良さそうですよね？
20 people are so cool, I'm really a lion
20人かっこよすぎて本当にライオンです
If you have no virtue, you will serve another
徳がなければ他人に奉仕するだろう
second husband
第二個丈夫 不心塌足
But I didn't care about his family any more.
しかし、私はもう彼の家族のことなど気にしていませんでした。
Which means, in the end, it's just emotions anyway.
つまり、結局のところ、それはただの感情です。
It turns out that the first mother, the child born to the first wife
最初の母親、最初の妻との間に生まれた子供であることが判明
This kind of happiness in life comes from suffering, and the fruit comes from the cause
この種の人生は苦しみから生まれ、果実は原因から生まれます。
Think about it, it's meaningless, don't go through it again
考えてみろ、意味がない、手放さないで
So sacrifice one's life and get tired of getting out of the body
だから自分の命を犠牲にして、体から出るのに疲れて、あなたの気質はショックで、あなたはプールの水を吸います
Looks like he's started reading Buddhist scriptures
仏教の経典を読み始めたようです
Guangtong Precepts Six Degrees of Treasure Noisy Precepts Daughter
広東戒律六度の宝物騒々しい戒律娘
Treat a thousand pieces of gold as a quarrel ring
千枚の金を喧嘩指輪として扱う
Just think of all his practice, reading the scriptures, open it
彼のあらゆる実践、聖典の読書を思い出して、それを開いてください
It's starting to look like he deserves something in return
彼には何か見返りを与える価値があるように思えてきた
It is he who is cultivating to this matter
この問題について修煉しているのは彼です
When should something be rewarded? The shadow of the twin scales wears out
いつ報われるべきか 双鱗の影が消えていく
Suddenly this practice is a temple
突然、この習慣は寺院になります
This kind of shadow of this kind of environment
こんな環境のこんな影
It was this shadow that suddenly disappeared.
忽然と消えたのはこの影だった。
What do you mean? It means he's not sick himself.
彼自身は病気ではないということはどういう意味ですか？
no way to live
生きる道がない
The third person will appear next
次に三人目が登場します
who
WHO
Wei Qing, king of Xihe
魏青、西河王
king of the river
川の王
It's called Yuan Wei Qing
ユアン・ウェイチンといいます
Priest
牧師之初
and grandson
そして孫
Do you understand
わかりますか
understand
理解
third person on stage
ステージ上の三人称
Talented Sōsei
宗世才英
Ubukata sokushin
生方即身
base
ベース
dungeon run
ダンジョンラン
Madam dead pen
夫人亡筆
Purchase Ji Miliu
ジ・ミリュウを購入する
Edom October
以東十月
Stingray Nutrition Junjie Hotel
スティングレイ ニュートリション ジュンジエ ホテル
etc.
等
What's the meaning
どのような意味です
that is
あれは
Let's talk about him first
まずは彼のことについて話しましょう
His father loved him very much when he was a child
彼の父親は彼が子供の頃、彼をとても愛していました
then at the age of seven
それから7歳のとき
father passed away
父が亡くなりました
he cried virtuously
彼は潔く泣いた
like a girl
女の子のように
Married at fifteen
15歳で結婚
The original Tuoba long-term alliance
オリジナルの拓跋長期提携
A family of the military-political alliance
軍事政治同盟の家族
Then what
じゃあ何
apparently had a daughter
どうやら娘がいたらしい
Although the front side
フロント側ですが、
No mention of having a daughter at all
娘がいるという話は一切なし
right
右
But apparently there is a daughter
でも娘もいるらしい
because of that daughter
あの娘のせいで
Later she married Yuan
その後彼女はユアンと結婚した
So that's what I just said
それが私が今言ったことです
Yuan and Mu have been married for a long time
ユアンとムーは長い間結婚していた
He married Mu
彼はムーと結婚した
gave birth to a daughter, of course the surname is Mu
娘が生まれました、もちろん姓はムーです
Later this daughter surnamed Mu married back to Yuan
その後、このムという姓の娘は元に再婚しました。
It's from his own family
それは彼自身の家族からのものです
So another child was born named Yuan Weiqing
そこで、ユアン・ウェイチンという名前の別の子供が生まれました
Yuan Weiqing when his wife was sick
妻が病気のときの袁偉清
I'm working on Xihe Wang and I'm working on a mobile phone
私は Xihe Wang で作業しており、携帯電話で作業しています
Dungeon Mengrun looks like it is in Luoyang
ダンジョン孟倫は洛陽にあるみたい
It's a very important official, the first official
非常に重要な役人です、最初の役人です
Then the pastor Xihe Wang Weiqing was the wife's grandson at the beginning.
そして、牧師の西和王偉清氏は当初、妻の孫でした。
the son of his daughter
彼の娘の息子
He is a master, how good he is
彼は達人だ、なんて上手いんだろう
Then the lady got sick when she went to live with him
その後、女性は彼と一緒に住むようになったときに病気になりました
The result is in his, in Yuan Weiqing's
結果は彼の、袁偉清の中にある
Nutritious Bacteria Sister's Annex One of his mansions
栄養菌 妹の別館 邸宅の一つ
If you die in this villa, you will die there
この別荘で死んだらそこで死ぬことになる
Dead grandson Momowa Zisu all heart
死孫毫默瓦 子素皆心
That is, no matter who is a monk
つまり、誰が僧侶であっても、
Ordinary people who have not left home
家から出ていない一般人
Everyone loves it
みんな大好きです
Because he should be able to be a female high school mother for a thousand years
千年後も女子高生の母親でいられるはずだから
how did you die
どうやって死んだの？
just cry
ただ泣くだけ
before dying
死ぬ前に
dying suddenly
突然死ぬ
Clearly lost
明らかに失われた
Don't bury his sleepy heart of cultivating Taoism
道教を修める彼の眠い心を埋めないでください
What's the meaning
どのような意味です
I've already said it
もう言ったよ
twenty minutes
20分
What's the meaning
どのような意味です
Zhu Chenyan, since you are here
朱晨燕、あなたがここにいるから
You said there's a microphone over there
あそこにマイクがあるって言ってたよね
take a look
見てください
yes
はい
He woke up on his deathbed, woke up suddenly
彼は死の床で目覚め、突然目覚めた
Looks like he died while living at his grandson's house
孫の家に住んでいて亡くなったようです
before dying
死ぬ前に
Woke up suddenly and asked to say
突然目が覚めてこう言いました
He doesn't want to follow the one in front
彼は前の人に従いたくない
Don't bury what he meant, yes
彼の言いたかったことを埋もれないでね、そうだね
Just don't marry any of the previous husbands
前の夫とは結婚しないでください
buried together
一緒に埋葬された
Don't be buried with the expert
専門家と一緒に埋もれないでください
because this
なぜならこれは
don't be buried with the pastor
牧師と一緒に埋葬されないでください
Because that was her ex-husband after all.
だって、それは元夫だったから。
Seems to make sense
意味があるようです
but no matter what
でも何があっても
He lived in the little child born to the priest
彼は司祭が産んだ小さな子供の中に住んでいた
home is his grandson's home
家は彼の孫の家です
So it's a little bit unreasonable
じゃあちょっと無理があるかな
Then don't be buried with the expert
専門家と一緒に埋もれないでください
Pedestrians buried together
一緒に埋められた歩行者
Of course, it was very different from the custom at that time.
もちろん、当時の習慣とは大きく異なりました。
At that time, many couples and funeral mothers
当時は多くの夫婦や葬儀の母親が
It's the couple buried together
一緒に埋葬されているカップルです
This means that we will always be united, etc.
これは、私たちは常に団結する、などを意味します。
but he doesn't want
でも彼は望んでいない
He specifically stated that he would not
彼はそうしないと具体的に述べた
Please don't bury his heart that he cultivated at the age of
歳で培った彼の心を埋めないでください
The results of it
その結果
Sons and daughters are respectful and dare not stop
息子や娘は敬意を持ち、あえて立ち止まることはありません
they can't stop listening to him
彼らは彼の話を聞くのをやめられない
I agreed
同意しました
It's fine after you promise
約束した後は大丈夫です
I will be buried in a certain day and a certain year
いつかいつかの年に埋もれるだろう
Buried next to Luoyang
洛陽の隣に埋葬されている
Beside Maan Hill
マーンヒルのそば
This front is the so-called narrative
この前線はいわゆる物語です
is the narrative
物語です
Because of Mu Zhiming
穆志明のせいで
This civilization is actually a famous text like a singing language
この文明は実は歌う言語のような名文である
four words four words four words
四語四語四語
Then we need to explain why there is this sequence later.
次に、なぜこの順序があるのか​​を後で説明する必要があります。
will have this name
この名前になります
so its words about
それで、その言葉について
what about the word
その言葉はどうですか
Of course, just sing him like this, how, how, how
もちろん、このように彼を歌ってください、どのように、どのように、どのように
the last word says
最後の言葉は言う
Of course, these are what we just talked about
もちろん、これらは私たちが今話した内容です
In fact, the sequence of the content is almost the same.
実際、内容の流れはほぼ同じです。
It means to tell him how he is doing, okay?
つまり、彼の様子を伝えるということですね。
but in the end
しかし、最後には
Life, birth and fortune
人生、誕生、運命
One return to trickle, no repeated injury
トリクルに一度戻るだけで、怪我を繰り返すことはありません
human life is short
人間の命は短い
The time after death is longer than the time in life
死後の時間は生きている時間よりも長い
Twin Scales In-laws Wind Cup Baiyang
双鱗の義理の風杯白陽
even so
たとえそうであっても
the man who wrote his name
自分の名前を書いた男
still hope
まだ願っています
Will lie in the blue night, there is no absolute way
青い夜に横たわる 絶対的な方法はない
that is
あれは
his people are buried here
彼の人々はここに埋葬されています
set up a cup
カップを設置する
wrote the name
名前を書きました
And it also shows that his voice
そしてそれは彼の声が
There are also flowers beside
横にはお花もあります
Although life is short
人生は短いのに
time gone
時間が経った
not alive time
生きている時間ではない
Time is much longer than living time
時間は生きている時間よりもはるかに長い
those these
それらこれら
these creams and more
このクリームなど
is the wind
風です
these trees
これらの木々
these trees next to
隣のこれらの木々
when it comes to winter
冬になると
Maybe it's frosting too
もしかしたらこれも霜が降りているかもしれない
it's cold
寒いです
The whole north wind blows up
北風が全部吹き上がる
it feels like weeping
泣きそうな気分だ
probably so
おそらくそうだろう
There's nothing wrong with the atmosphere
雰囲気的には問題ないですよ
but at the end
しかし最後に
He wants this guy who writes wood to say
彼は木を書くこの男にこう言ってもらいたいのです
Paint Wolan Wan
ペイントウォランワン
I mean these flower beds
つまり、これらの花壇のことです
paved these
これらを舗装しました
those who planted these flowers
この花を植えた人たちは
these flowers beside the wood
木の横にあるこれらの花
Hope to be forever apart
永遠に別れる事を願って
don't stop
止まらないで
can still last forever
まだ永遠に続くことができる
equal to this
これに等しい
one of the dead
死者の一人
Blessings to the future world
未来の世界に祝福を
such a world
そんな世界
In fact, this wooden name
実はこの木の名前、
You see I was hoping to invite you over here
あなたをここに招待したいと思っていたのがわかりますか
audience come
観客が来ます
to share
共有する
I read this
これを読みました
As a result, I did not expect that I would
結果的にはこんなことになるとは予想していませんでした
It took 20 minutes to finish it
終わるまでに20分かかった
Who is the author of this wooden name
この木名の作者は誰ですか
whoever wrote it
誰が書いたとしても
honestly
本音
we don't really know
私たちは本当に知りません
because he didn't
彼はそうしなかったから
In the end, there was no withdrawal and said who was so and so
結局撤回はなく、誰が誰それだと言っていた
do so so so
そうそうそうそうする
wait wait wait
待って待って待って
But you from this content
しかし、このコンテンツからあなたは
You should be able to guess
推測できるはずです
He should have been commissioned by someone from the Xingya family.
彼は興雅家の誰かから依頼されたはずだ。
Because he wrote only two or three sentences about the marriage with the pastor
彼は牧師との結婚について二、三文しか書いていないからだ。
Lian Yuan didn't even talk about having a daughter.
リアン・ユアンは娘がいることについてさえ話さなかった。
If he hadn't died in his grandson's house in the end
もし彼が最後に孫の家で死ななかったら
Maybe we'll never know that he ever
たぶん私たちは彼がこれまでに知ったことは決してないだろう
Had a child in the first marriage
最初の結婚で子供が生まれた
But the second marriage is a lot
でも二度目の結婚は大変だ
And dad doesn't just write about his own virtues
そしてお父さんは自分の美徳について書くだけではありません
How to serve this mother-in-law
この義母にどうやって仕えるか
How to follow these eggs
この卵を追跡する方法
Other concubines get along well
他の側室も仲が良い
how to teach journalists
ジャーナリストにどう教えるか
At the same time, it also discusses how the eggs will be judged and supervised.
同時に、卵がどのように判断され、監督されるかについても議論されています。
such an amazing person
とても素晴らしい人です
In fact, there are profits in the practice of egg guarding.
実際、卵の保護の実践には利益があります。
After checking, he was indeed very handsome and silly, etc.
確認してみると、確かにとてもハンサムでバカだった、などなど。
But this pastor is actually the pastor of Yuanquan Camel
しかし、この牧師は実際には元泉ラクダの牧師です
But he also brought a sum of eggs
でも彼は卵もたくさん持ってきました
said some good things about him
彼についていくつか良いことを言いました
At the same time, the news is that this son
同時にニュースは、この息子が
also said some good things
良いことも言いました
What about the other side?
反対側はどうですか？
the virtues described in
で説明されている美徳
basically looks like
基本的には次のように見えます
All belong to Chinese
すべて中国人のものです
It is the virtue after the Confucian dialect of the Han dialect of Beiwei Tuoba
北魏拓跋の漢語の儒教の言葉にちなんだ美徳です
For example, it should be Pomponla and it should be cut in half.
たとえば、それはプンポンラーであり、半分にカットされる必要があります。
Should be able to love Long even though it wasn't born by me
自分が産んだものじゃなくてもロングを愛せるはず
I love him more than I ever gave birth to myself
私は自分自身を産んだ以上に彼を愛しています
Or be able to work as a female worker and read teachers' books Li Yue
あるいは、女性労働者として働きながら、李岳先生の本を読むこともできる
From these angles it would appear that
これらの角度から見ると、
This shepherd, although we do not know who the author is
この羊飼い、作者が誰なのかは分かりませんが、
Basically, it should be the home of eggs.
基本的には、そこが卵の故郷であるはずです。
It is the people in his second husband's family
それは彼の二番目の夫の家族の人々です
Please someone write a shepherd like this
誰かこのような羊飼いを書いてください
I don’t know how you feel about this shepherd
この羊飼いのことをどう思っているのかわかりませんが、
If you've seen this shepherd, start reading with us
この羊飼いを見たことがあれば、一緒に読み始めてください
It was about the same time that this shepherd was unearthed
この羊飼いが発掘されたのとほぼ同じ時期でした
We know the age of the shepherds 1920's 30's
私たちは羊飼いの年齢を知っています 1920 年代から 30 年代
According to the life history of Chinese women we just read by Chen Dongyu
先ほど読んだ陳東宇著の中国人女性のライフヒストリーによれば、
I don't want to see some queens and heroines
女王とかヒロインとか見たくない
I think how miserable it is for a woman's male director to be inferior
女性の男性監督が劣っているというのは、どれほど惨めなことなのかと思う
Read these two things at about the same time
この 2 つをほぼ同時に読んでください
Because this thing has been kept in the father and son's library
これは父子の図書館に保管されていたものなので、
Not many people know about this blockbuster
この大ヒット作を知っている人はあまり多くありません
often in the library
図書館でよくある
In fact, until the first time I knew about this thing
実は私もこのことを初めて知るまでは
Of course
もちろん
Probably decades after it was unearthed
おそらく発掘されてから何十年も経ってから
Received on an untouched South American wooden tread
手つかずの南米産の木の踏み板で受け取られました
or in these books
またはこれらの本の中で
but no research
しかし研究はありません
really have research i see
本当に研究があるのですね
I'm probably the first
おそらく私が最初です
when I was writing my doctoral dissertation
博士論文を書いていたとき
After returning from the United States, I went to the Fox Union Library to check information
アメリカから帰国後、情報をチェックするためにフォックスユニオン図書館に行きました
then i found
それから私は見つけました
There's a wooden tread like this
こんな木の踏み板があります
This is the life of this woman
これがこの女の人生だ
when i was in college
私が大学にいたとき
The life history of Chinese women sent to me by the teacher who read Ba Zhuo
巴卓を読んだ先生が送ってくれた中国女性のライフヒストリー
So I see that women's lives actually seem to be different
女性の生活は実際には異なっているようです
so i was curious
それで私は興味がありました
i want to know
私は知りたいです
How exactly do women live their lives?
女性は具体的にどのように人生を送っているのでしょうか？
what happened
どうしたの
Does this wooden name tell us something
この木の名前は何かを物語っているのでしょうか？
In the life history of Chinese women
中国人女性の人生史の中で
Aspects that will not be touched
触れられない側面
Then in the 1990s I wrote my doctoral dissertation
そして1990年代に私は博士論文を書きました
The 90s were all 24 seasons
90年代は全24シーズンだった
in the 90s
90年代に
I finished my doctoral dissertation
博士論文を書き終えました
I used a story like this
こんな話を使いました
Recently, due to the need for more in-depth analysis
最近では、より詳細な分析の必要性から、
because you are participating in different anthologies
色々なアンソロジーに参加しているので
project translation project etc.
翻訳プロジェクトなど
I put the wooden name very carefully
丁寧に木名を入れました
read it again
もう一度読んでください
After reading it, you will find that
読んでみるとわかりますが、
When living with Chinese women
中国人女性と同居する場合
In fact, women's lives presented
実際に女性の人生を紹介
may be different
違うかもしれない
what is a different place
違う場所は何ですか
First
初め
He married twice
彼は二度結婚した
that's where we are
そこが私たちのいる場所です
May Fourth
5月4日
struggle here
ここで奮闘する
to struggle
闘争へ
one of them is
そのうちの1人は
Needle survey
針調査
offhand day problem
休日の問題
this was popular at the time
これは当時流行っていました
not popular
人気がない
a painful thing
痛いこと
That is to say, the painful thing at that time
つまり、あの時の辛かったことは
But Chinese history has not always been
しかし、中国の歴史は常にそうだったわけではありません。
What I saw on May 4th
5月4日に見たもの
their previous state
彼らの以前の状態
in what we found
私たちが見つけたものの中で
Yuanchun camel's wooden inside found
元春ラクダの木製の内部が発見される
There was a time in Chinese history
中国の歴史にはそんな時代があった
women's situation
女性の状況
or the form of his life
あるいは彼の人生の形
It's actually different
実際は違います
or the status of his marriage
または彼の結婚状況
In fact, it's not the hand festival at home
実は我が家では手祭りではないのです
no wrist
手首がない
Widowed
未亡人
get a needle survey
ニードル調査を受ける
can be at home
家にいてもいい
Does that mean he has a higher status?
ということは、彼のほうが地位が高いということでしょうか？
uncertain
不確かな
because he said he
彼が言ったから
His brother is the only one who is passionate
情熱的なのは彼の兄だけです
He wants wristbands
彼はリストバンドが欲しいです
My brother won't let him hold hands
兄は手を繋がせてくれない
we look again
もう一度見てみましょう
So it's not what he said
だからそれは彼が言ったことではない
If Won Chun asked Key to stand up today and say
ウォンチュンがキーに今日立ち上がってこう言ったら
No, in fact, I really wanted to revalue
いや、本当は再評価したかったのですが、
It's just that I can't help it if they just write it like this
ただ、こうやって書かれても仕方ないですね
I do not know
私は知らない
This will only be known after the chicken
これはチキンが終わって初めて分かることだ
How can we get the ancients to tell us the truth?
どうすれば古代人に真実を語ってもらえるでしょうか？
But even if the ancients really come back
でもたとえ本当に古代人が戻ってきたとしても
They tell the truth we don't know
彼らは私たちが知らない真実を語ります
because we are now face to face
私たちは今、対面しているので
Not necessarily telling the truth, right?
必ずしも真実を言っているわけではありませんよね？
How can you believe that the one with the chicken came back
鶏を飼った人が戻ってきたなんてどうして信じられますか
just tell the truth
ただ真実を言ってください
This is getting further and further away. Don't worry about him.
どんどん遠ざかっていきますが、彼のことは心配しないでください。
but i mean
しかし、私が言いたいのは
It is true that re-price is a norm in Raising and Zhimin
確かに、Raising と Zhimin では再価格が標準となっています。
This is a fact
これは事実です
In fact, after reading other materials, we
実際、他の資料を読んだ後、
will also find
も見つかります
The so-called widowed, widowed, needle knot, defense
いわゆる未亡人、未亡人、針の結び目、防御
These things were indeed a sore spot when the samurai
これらは武士の時代には確かに痛所でした。
But not in Chinese history
しかし中国の歴史ではそうではない
It's always been like this
いつもこんな感じだった
The second is to say
2つ目は、こう言うことです
after he was widowed twice
彼は二度未亡人になった後
He finds his life boring
彼は自分の人生が退屈だと感じている
I don't want to live like this
こんなふうに生きたくない
what can he do
彼は何ができますか
he became a monk
彼は僧侶になった
he decided to become a monk
他決定出家
Without people also head towards the pond
人影もなく池へ向かう
As far as we are concerned, women in medieval China
私たちに関する限り、中世中国の女性は
In fact, apart from getting married
実は結婚以外にも
There is another thing you can do
他にできることがある
is to become a monk
僧侶になることです
and become a monk
そして僧侶になる
like he looks like
彼が似ているように
Life is really hard like this
こうなると人生は本当に大変だ
not interesting
面白くない
Widowed twice, I became a monk
二度の未亡人を経て僧侶になった
But after leaving home it looks like
でも家を出た後はこんな感じ
he can read
彼は読むことができます
Bo collection gold account
ボーコレクションゴールドアカウント
also read commandments
戒めも読んでください
what else
ほかに何か
did you really read
本当に読んだの？
Literacy and reading
識字能力と読書
we're not really sure
よくわかりません
Because people in the past called reading
なぜなら、人々が読書と呼んでいたものは、
Sometimes someone else reads to him
時々他の人が彼に本を読んであげる
If he can understand, it means he has read
彼が理解できたなら、それは彼が読んだことを意味します
This is also a way of reading
これも読み方です
sometimes really read by yourself
時々、本当に一人で読んでいます
Sometimes you can recognize a few words
いくつかの単語を認識できる場合もあります
but some don't know
でも知らない人もいる
Then ask others to read it together
次に、他の人に一緒に読んでもらいます
In fact, the situation is not necessarily
実際には、必ずしもそのような状況になるわけではありません
but anyway
とにかく
after becoming a monk
僧侶になってから
if he is not a noblewoman
もし彼が貴族の女性でなければ
He's just an ordinary girl
彼はただの普通の女の子です
he may not have a chance
彼にはチャンスがないかもしれない
what reading teacher book
何の先生の本を読んでいますか
Li Yue
李岳
He was in this second husband's house just now
彼は今この二番目の夫の家にいました
But after all, when he was at the home of his second husband
しかし結局のところ、彼が二番目の夫の家にいたとき、
It seems that some texts have been touched
一部のテキストがタッチされているようです
After becoming a monk
僧侶になってから
He started collecting money
他開始博收金
read about Buddhism
仏教について読む
he likes himself
彼は自分が好きです
It's the interest of another world
それは別の世界の興味です
looks like
のように見える
It's also a good time
良い時期でもありますね
not enough
十分でない
Grand Jazz
グランドジャズ
But he ended up going to live in his grandson's house
しかし結局彼は孫の家に住むことになった
In fact, there are different studies
実は別の研究もある
What does that mean
どういう意味ですか
After the Tang Dynasty
唐の時代以降
the forest
森
Be it a monk or a nun
僧侶でも尼僧でも
You can't run around, bhikkhu or bhikkhu
走り回ってはいけない、比丘も比丘も
The government of the Tang Dynasty was stricter
唐の時代は統治が厳しかった
where do you become a monk
どこで僧侶になりますか
not place an order
注文しないでください
I've already said which unit I'm in
自分がどの部隊に所属しているかはすでに述べました
You must practice in that unit
その単元で練習しなければなりません
don't run around
走り回らないでください
But in the unprecedented U.S. and North Korea
しかし、前例のない米国と北朝鮮では
Because Buddhism has only just emerged
仏教はまだ出てきたばかりなので、
and still preaching
そしてまだ説教している
still looking for someone
まだ誰かを探しています
still pulling people
まだ人を引っ張っている
still in the process of becoming a believer
まだ信者になる途中です
In fact, the government does not
実際、政府はそうしていない
Also very re-entering Buddhism
仏教への再参入にも非常に興味があります
I didn't care about so many circumstances
あまりにも多くの状況を気にしなかった
You'll find what's called Big Jazz Round Clay
Big Jazz Round Clayと呼ばれるものが見つかります
The place where you run around and live is not necessarily in Big Jazz
走り回って生きる場所はビッグジャズとは限らない
Finally, when you get sick and die, you need someone to take care of you
最後に、病気になって亡くなったときは、世話をしてくれる人が必要です。
not in big jazz either
ビッグジャズにもいない
Instead, he went to live in his grandson's house.
代わりに、彼は孫の家に住むようになりました。
And he died at his grandson's house
そして孫の家で亡くなった
on the other hand
一方で
His grandson's family passed away
孫の家族が亡くなった
It is also related to our history of women's life in China
それは中国における女性の生活の歴史にも関係しています。
s got woman's
女性のものを持っています
The impression after marriage is different
結婚後の印象が違う
That is to say
つまり
why would he follow a
なぜ彼は後を追うのでしょうか
Daughter from his previous first marriage
前の最初の結婚で生まれた娘
the daughter's later son
娘の後の息子
live together
一緒に住む
According to what we have read about the life history of Chinese women
私たちが読んだ中国人女性の生活史によると、
Impressions of Chinese History
中国の歴史の印象
Chinese women's traditional Chinese women's
中国の女性の伝統的な中国の女性の
impression of this life
この人生の印象
should mean
意味するはずです
If he was Sir Johnny
もし彼がジョニー卿だったら
The government is not very strict
政府はあまり厳しくない
if he can go home
彼が家に帰れるなら
He should go back and follow the news
彼は戻ってニュースを追うべきだ
and his descendants
そして彼の子孫
right
右
Since he gets along so well with Ji Zi
彼はジ・ジととても仲が良いので、
Great righteousness makes people come out of themselves
大いなる正義は人を自分から出させる
Ji Zi loves him too
Ji Ziも彼を愛しています
two like
二人のような
good relationship
良い関係
The relationship with the experts is also very good.
専門家との関係も非常に良好です。
Then if he wants to go home
それで彼が家に帰りたいなら
or when he is sick
または彼が病気のとき
or when he is alone
または彼が一人でいるとき
Shouldn't he be going home?
彼は家に帰るべきではないでしょうか？
Obviously not
明らかに違います
he is actually
彼は実際にいます
to his original first marriage
彼の最初の結婚まで
the daughter
娘
the son born
生まれた息子
not mentioned at all
全く言及されていない
the gaze of his daughter
娘の視線
so it's possible in
だからそれは可能です
When Yuan Chuntuo was widowed for the second time
袁春佛が二度目に死別したとき
His own daughter may have died
自分の娘も亡くなったかもしれない
may not know
知らないかもしれない
It's also possible that his daughter lived with his son.
娘が息子と同居していた可能性もある。
That is, living with Yuan Chuntuo's grandson
それは袁春佗の孫と暮らすこと。
So when he went to find his grandson
それで彼が孫を探しに行ったとき
In fact, to find the daughter he gave birth to
実は自分が産んだ娘を探すために
But that is to say, although in the so-called patriarchal ethics
しかし、それは、いわゆる家父長制の倫理ではあるが、
A wife should always focus on her husband
妻は常に夫に集中しなければなりません
Husband's mother is my mother
夫の母は私の母です
My husband's son is my son
夫の息子は私の息子です
My husband's family is my family
夫の家族は私の家族です
But Yuan Chuntuo is obviously not like this
しかし、袁春佛は明らかにそうではありません
He is closer to the one he was born with
彼は持って生まれたものに近づいている
This leads us to the mother-child relationship
それが母と子の関係につながります
Or mother-daughter relationship or parent-child relationship
母娘関係とか親子関係とか
In the age we see
私たちが見ている時代には
This is the era in which Yuan Chuntuo appeared
袁春佛が登場した時代です
What kind of parent-child relationship is it?
どのような親子関係なのでしょうか？
Is it the kind mentioned in the Chinese women's living room later?
後ほど中国人女性のリビングルームで言及される類のものでしょうか？
A parent-child relationship that seems to be based on the patriarchal family
家父長制家族に基づくと思われる親子関係
The parent-child relationship in this era
この時代の親子関係
or what it means to be a mother
あるいは母親になることの意味
It has also aroused the curiosity of historians
歴史家の好奇心を呼び起こした
At the end of the interesting part, I will tell you a little more at the end
興味深い部分が終わったら、最後にもう少し詳しく説明します
Why do you say Dungeon Maker?
なぜダンジョンメーカーと言うのですか？
Just now I said that Xihe Wang Yuanweiqing was the successor of Luoyang.
先ほど、西和王元為清が洛陽の後継者であると言いました。
very important
とても重要な
In fact, this time is already the end of the year in the north.
実はこの時期、北国ではもう年末なんです。
not long
長くない
Probably not a few years later the North will perish
おそらく数年も経たないうちに北朝鮮は滅びるだろう
In fact at this time
実はこの時も
Zu Yong'an is the year name of Emperor Xiaoming in the north
祖永安は北の孝明帝の年号です。
But in fact, when Emperor Xiaoming was in power,
しかし実際には、孝明皇帝が権力を握っていたとき、
Basically he is not in charge
基本的に彼は責任者ではない
it's his mother
それは彼の母親です
This is the Queen Mother
こちらは皇太后です
that is a heroine
それはヒロインです
a political queen
一個社政太后
So, when Yuan Cunda lived in this age
つまり、ユアン・クンダがこの時代に生きていたとき、
In fact, China is historically
実は中国は歴史的には
women can remarry
女性は再婚できる
Whether he wants to or not
彼が望むか否かに関わらず
Anyway, he doesn't have the obligation to keep the chastity.
いずれにせよ、彼には貞操を守る義務はない。
At the same time, besides his marriage
同時に、結婚以外にも
There is also the opportunity to become a monk
僧侶になるチャンスもある
On the other hand, he may have a relationship with his parents and children.
一方で、親子関係もあるかもしれない。
very tight
とてもきつい
what it means to be a mother
母親になるということは何を意味するのか
very important
非常地重大
another one is
もう一つは、
This is actually an era ruled by a heroine
実はここはヒロインが支配する時代だった
not a male emperor
男性天皇ではない
In public opinion, he is the male emperor
世論では彼は男性天皇である
But the real ruler is actually this
でも本当の支配者は実はこの人なんだよ
emperor's mother
皇帝の母
That means the role of mother
それは母親の役割を意味します
In fact, it is very important in this era
実は今の時代、とても大切なことなのです
from here
ここから
we found out
私たちは知った
This is basically talking about the period from the Qin and Han Dynasties to Shishi
基本的には秦漢から獅子までの時代の話です。
It's what we call medieval history
それは私たちが中世の歴史と呼ぶものです
but i'll get to that later
でもそれについては後で説明します
Probably not exactly limited to this time
おそらく今回に限らず
Because of the different aspects of Chinese history
中国の歴史にはさまざまな側面があるため、
change, time, ups and downs
変化、時間、浮き沈み
It is not necessarily possible to use the political tide to stop and stop
政治の流れを利用して止めたり止めたりすることは必ずしも可能ではありません
If we look at Yuan Cuntou's life story, we will find that
袁君頭の生涯を見てみると、次のことがわかります。
In fact, the so-called respect for the seven generations of the husband or respecting the husband
実は、いわゆる七代の夫への敬意、あるいは夫への敬意。
that is, by law
つまり法律によって
legally
法律上
The core is the idea that the husband is the main axis
核となるのは夫が主軸であるという考え方
There may be something different in this day and age
今の時代だと何か違うのかもしれない
On the other hand, mother and son
一方、母と息子は、
May reveal a new fertility culture
新たな生殖文化を明らかにするかもしれない
This is also a historian
この人も歴史家です
pondering place
思索の場
Then there is
それから、
widowed monk
未亡人の僧侶
Widowed women may also become ordained
夫を亡くした女性も叙階される可能性がある
never married girl
結婚したことがない女の子
Maybe he became a monk in his teens
おそらく彼は10代で僧侶になったでしょう
Said he was leaving home
彼は家を出ると言った
It is possible in this era
この時代ならそれが可能だ
So scholars of the history of religion have also been inspired by this
したがって、宗教史の学者もこれに触発されています。
start doing research
研究を始める
on the other hand
一方で
Chen Dongyuan says
陳東源氏は言う
I don't want to talk about female emperors and heroines venting their anger on women
女性天皇やヒロインが女性に怒りをぶつける話はしたくない
Because these people have nothing to do with ordinary women
この人達は普通の女性とは何の関係もないから
What is the meaning of talking about female Wu Zetian
女性の武則天について語る意味は何ですか？
no use at all
まったく役に立たない
Actually still useful
実は今でも役に立ちます
see what you say
あなたが言うことを見てください
If you take Wu Zetian as saying that she is venting her anger for a woman
武則天が女性に対する怒りをぶつけていると言っていると受け取るなら
Of course it's useless
もちろん駄目だよ
But if Wu Zetian's appearance
でも武則天の登場なら
placed in a series of historical developments
一連の歴史的発展の中に置かれる
In the context of political history
政治史の文脈で
Why is there such a female emperor?
なぜこのような女性天皇が存在するのでしょうか？
The only one in Chinese history
中国史上唯一の
Scholars of political history may have something to say
政治史の学者は何か言いたいことがあるかもしれない
it makes sense to talk about
について話すのは理にかなっています
It is the characteristic of national culture
それは国民文化の特徴です
or interracial contact
または異人種間の接触
Or a change in the concept of class
あるいは階級概念の変化
When these things are added together
これらを合計すると
In fact, it’s all because historical research didn’t want to learn from women
実際、それはすべて歴史研究が女性から学びたくなかったからです
or gender perspective
またはジェンダーの視点
But if from a gender point of view
しかし、性別の観点から見ると、
rethinking legal history
法の歴史を再考する
When medical history is compared with religious history or political history
医療史を宗教史や政治史と比較する場合
we may see something different
何か違うものが見えるかも知れません
The pure wood is just right
無垢材がちょうどいい
All fit. Let's look at something like this
すべて当てはまります。次のようなものを見てみましょう
If the law makes us talk about basically
法律が私たちに基本的なことについて話させるなら
Chinese law probably started after the Tang Dynasty
中国の法律はおそらく唐の時代以降に始まった
It has been established that the so-called Five Blessings are used to punish people
いわゆる五福は人々を罰するために使用されることが確立されています
What's the meaning
どのような意味です
what is five blessings
五福とは何ですか
does anyone know
誰か知っていますか
Does anyone know what Wufu is?
五福って何か知ってる人いる？
Can you see it here?
ここで見えますか？
If there is a self here, have you seen yourself?
ここに自分がいるとしたら、あなたは自分を見たことがありますか？
own father died
自分の父親が亡くなった
I have to serve him for three years
私は彼に3年間仕えなければなりません
own brother died
自分の弟が亡くなった
I have to serve him for a year
私は彼に1年間仕えなければなりません
own grandfather died
自分の祖父が亡くなった
Take nourishing reminder for one year
1年間の栄養補給のリマインダーを取る
Tang Brothers Passed Away in September
唐兄弟が9月に死去
Don brothers' child dies
ドン兄弟の子供が死亡
I mourn for him
私は彼のことを悼みます
Fu Xiaogong May
服小功五月
grandson of tang brothers dies
唐兄弟の孫が死去
I served his dead horse for three months
私は彼の死んだ馬に3か月間仕えました
sound like proper nouns
固有名詞のように聞こえる
what the hell is this talking about
これは一体何を話しているのでしょうか
Cut and blow the broken sound
カットブロー壊れた音の単語
It doesn't matter if you cut it inside
中を切っても問題ない
cut blow means
カットブローの意味
very tattered sackcloth
とてもボロボロの荒布
The sackcloth is torn to the bottom
荒布が底まで破れている
no seams
縫い目なし
like cut it
切ったような
rotten
腐った
very very bad sackcloth
とてもとても悪い荒布
And the edges are not sewn
そして端は縫われていない
Wearing this sackcloth for three years
この荒布を3年間着続ける
Why
なぜ
because my father died
父が亡くなったので
very very painful
とてもとても痛い
father is a man's day
父は男の日です
This is in Yili Shangfu
ここは伊里尚府にあります
This whole chart is from Yili Shangfu
この全体図はYili Shanfuからのものです
the relationship between the traditional family
伝統的な家族間の関係
how to define
定義方法
by
に
that person died
あの人が死んだ
I wounded for him
私は彼のために傷を負った
how long to take
どのくらいかかりますか
wear rotten sackcloth
腐った荒布を着る
to define the distance between me and him
私と彼の間の距離を定義するために
Intimacy
親密
so if
それで、もし
i don't know now
今は分かりません
if you go to a funeral
葬儀に行くなら
get a reply
返事をもらう
But now everything is electronic
しかし今ではすべてが電子化されています
I do not even know
私も知らない
Is there anything else I can get?
他に何か入手できるものはありますか?
If a woman dies
女性が亡くなったら
Sometimes his husband comes out to do funerals for him
時々夫が葬式のために出てくることもある
Husband and wife
夫婦
Wife is the meaning of a year here
妻はここでの一年の意味です
I read the word "Blowing"
「吹く」という言葉を読みました
You can miss your wife if you want
望むなら妻がいなくてもいいよ
mean to say
言う意味
The death of a brother is not as serious as the death of a father
兄弟の死は父親の死ほど深刻ではない
still very sad
まだとても悲しい
But what about the sackcloth with the clothes on?
しかし、服を着た荒布はどうでしょうか？
It can be sewed, so the wife dies
縫えるから妻が死ぬ
And the time to serve in the warehouse is less than three years
倉庫での勤務期間は3年未満です
just one year is enough
1年だけで十分です
That means the father is supreme
つまり父親が至高だということ
he is my most respected person
彼は私の最も尊敬する人です
So when he passed away, I beheaded him for three years
それで彼が亡くなったとき、私は彼の首を3年間斬首しました
brother of course
もちろん兄さん
But it didn't reach the level of supreme
でも至高のレベルには達しなかった
So the sackcloth is a bit better for sewing
なので、荒布のほうが裁縫には少し適しています。
Not even three years
3年も経たない
Just one year
たった1年
just a little less
ほんの少し少ない
One year, also called wife
1年、妻とも呼ばれる
that is
あれは
During that period, practice making chicken
その間、鶏肉作りの練習をする
but no matter what
でも何があっても
It means taking a year of injury
それは1年間怪我をすることを意味する
come down the other
もう一方から降りてください
Dagong is linen
ダゴンはリネンです
But it's thicker linen
でも厚手のリネンなので
slightly thicker like
少し厚いような
That rotten cloth
その腐った布
Then he just needs to obey
それなら彼は従うだけでいい
Nine months and a little further away
9ヶ月と少し先
Minor
マイナー
better again
再び良くなりました
Just take it for five months
5ヶ月だけ飲み続けてください
Relatives who are far away wear Sima
遠く離れた親戚がシマを着ている
Sima is actually quite dense.
シマは実際には非常に密集しています。
Even without the crappy clothes
ダサい服を着なくても
The sackcloth is good but it is good
荒布もいいけどいいよ
Pretty good sackcloth
かなり良い荒布
how long to wear for three months
3ヶ月どれくらい着れるのか
Therefore, take five servings according to etiquette
したがって、マナーに従って5回分をお召し上がりください。
Just take five servings
5回分だけ摂取するだけ
three years one year nine months
3年 1年9ヶ月
five months three months
5ヶ月 3ヶ月
Paired with bad Zhancui
悪いZhancuiと組み合わせた
slightly rotten
少し腐った
But not the worst Zhi Cui
でも最悪のジー・クイではない
Then come back to the great and the small
それから大きいものと小さいものに戻ってください
five different clothes
5 つの異なる服
this type
このタイプ
different linen clothes
さまざまな荒布の服
the dead live for the dead
死者は死者のために生きる
what to wear for mourning
喪に服するもの
Use this method to show the relationship between a family
この方法を使用して家族間の関係を示します
relationship of intimacy
親密な関係
Well, this intimacy and inferiority are related to the Tang Dynasty
さて、この親密さと劣等感は唐時代に関連しています
It becomes placed in Tang Lv Shuyi
唐のLv Shuyiに置かれることになる
recognized by law
法律で認められている
If you have a murder, a murder, a fight at home
家で殺人、殺人、喧嘩が起きたら
When someone is injured or someone dies
誰かが怪我をしたとき、あるいは誰かが亡くなったとき
If you want to serve him for a year
一年間彼に仕えたいなら
Then you hit him and hurt him
それからあなたは彼を殴って傷つけました
You will be punished more than when two passers-by get into a fight
2人の通行人が喧嘩した場合よりも罰せられることになります
It's worse to hurt someone
人を傷つけるほうが悪い
if i hit him he hurts
私が彼を殴ったら彼は痛い
But he's for me if I die
でも、私が死んでも彼は私の味方です
He served me for three years
彼は3年間私に仕えてくれました
For example, Zicui, Dagong is ready in September, just give me an example
たとえば、Zicui、Dagong は 9 月に完成します。例を挙げてください。
It means that he serves me
つまり、彼は私に奉仕するということです
Heavier than what I put on him
私が彼に着せたものよりも重い
He came and beat me
彼はやって来て私を殴りました
then i hit him
それから私は彼を殴りました
Then I shall be punished more than
そうすれば私はそれ以上の罰を受けるでしょう
Generally, two passers-by kill each other and hurt each other lightly.
一般に、二人の通行人が殺し合い、軽く傷つけ合う。
do you understand me
あなたは私を理解していますか
That is to say, the parent-book preparation relationship in a family uses this talisman
つまり、家族における親と本の準備関係はこのお守りを使用します
So after the Tang Dynasty we saw that in fact
唐の時代以降、実際に次のことがわかりました。
China has probably always said when judging cases
おそらく中国は事件を裁く際にいつもこう言っているだろう。
case official system
案官符制
This case involves symbols
このケースには記号が含まれます
When someone in the family hurts each other
家族の誰かがお互いを傷つけたとき
Then I'll put it between him and him
それなら彼と彼の間に置きます
What kind of relationship should it be in the five symbols?
5つのシンボルはどのような関係にあるべきでしょうか？
Who is more respectful and who is more sad
誰比較尊 誰比較悲
Who's more dear who compares books
本を比べるのは誰がより大切なのか
Sentencing only after confirmation
量刑は確認後にのみ
The penalty for fighting with two passers-by is different
2人の通行人と戦う場合のペナルティは異なります
meaning that
という意味です
This set of concepts of all traditional Chinese etiquette
この一連の中国の伝統的なエチケットの概念
put it into the law to implement
それを法律に入れて実行する
do you know what i mean
あなたは私を理解していますか
but you can see
しかし、あなたは見ることができます
look here
ここを見て
All men and no women
全員男性で女性は無し
how could this be
これはどうやってできるの
what's going on
どうしたの？
because
なぜなら
What about me if my wife dies?
妻が亡くなったら私はどうなりますか？
Remind him for a year
1年間彼に思い出させてください
But we didn't see that if we are female
でも私たちが女性だったらそんなことは分からなかった
What if the husband dies?
夫が亡くなったらどうしますか？
same as son
息子と同じ
This wound that the wife served for her husband
妻が夫のためにつけたこの傷
It's the same wound that the son took for his father
それは息子が父親のために負ったのと同じ怪我だ
it means
その意味は
when a woman marries
女性が結婚するとき
if she is at home
彼女が家にいるなら
she is a living woman
彼女は生きている女性です
her father died
彼女の父親が亡くなりました
She will take the worst injury
彼女は最悪の怪我をするだろう
for her father
彼女の父親のために
once she is married
彼女が結婚したら
her worst injury
彼女の最悪の怪我
for her sir
彼女のために
so-called widow
いわゆる未亡人
originally your father
もともとあなたのお父さん
Originally your father was your god
もともとあなたの父親はあなたの神でした
now once married
現在一旦結婚之後
husband is your god
夫はあなたの神です
so the wife died
それで妻は亡くなった
The husband only needs to serve his wife for one year
夫は1年間だけ妻に仕えればよい
wearable sackcloth
着用可能な荒布
But if the husband dies
でも夫が亡くなったら
The wife will serve her husband for three years
妻は夫に3年間仕えることになる
and the worst
そして最悪の
sackcloth
荒布
means to show
示すという意味
Husband honors his wife and mourns
夫尊妻悲
what about my son
私の息子はどうですか
when dad died
お父さんが亡くなったとき
serve him for three years
彼に3年間仕える
Zhancui three years
展翠三年
What about the mother's death?
母親の死についてはどうですか？
one year
一年
mother died
母が亡くなりました
Take the reminder of a year's injury
一年間の怪我を思い出してください
that is why
それが理由です
Because although my mother is a close relative
なぜなら、私の母親は近親者であるにもかかわらず、
But not higher than the Supreme
ただし至高以上ではない
inside a home
家の中で
the most respected person
最も尊敬される人
can't be taller than him
彼より背が高くなることはできない
The premise is
前提は
Dad is still there, right?
お父さんはまだそこにいるんですよね？
So the Supreme is still there
だから至高者はまだそこにいる
Although the dearest relative died
最愛の親戚が亡くなったのに
You can't be right for him
あなたが彼にとって正しいはずはない
So I can only take it for a year
だから1年しか耐えられない
But if my mother dies
でももしお母さんが死んだら
my dad has passed away
私の父が亡くなりました
I'm not here anymore
もうここにはいない
what to do
何をすべきか
Eloquent
理性的に
you can serve for three years
3年間勤務できます
but can't
でもできない
Can't wear sharp clothes
派手な服は着れない
Only wear self-proclaimed clothes
自称した服しか着ない
just your sackcloth
あなたの荒布だけ
can't be chopped
切り刻めない
Because although your Supreme is dead
なぜなら、あなたの至高者は死んでも、
He will always be your king
彼はいつもあなたの王様です
So even though your loved one died
だからたとえあなたの愛する人が亡くなったとしても
you are very sad
あなたはとても悲しいです
You want to serve him for three years
あなたは彼に3年間仕えたいと思っています
Can
できる
but the clothes can't arrive
でも服が届かない
worst level
最悪レベル
must be between parents
両親の間でなければなりません
There must be a division
分裂があるはずだ
Otherwise, you can't tell the difference
そうしないと違いがわかりません
who is supreme
誰が最高ですか
I can't say that it doesn't count if you're dead.
死んだら意味がないとは言えません。
He is still supreme
彼は今でも最高です
so what
だから何
you can know
あなたは知ることができます
such a concept
そのような概念
This way of distribution
この配布方法
If you put him in the law
彼を法律の中に入れたら
If you use this thing to sentence
これを文章に使うと
that is to say
つまり
If a son hurts his father and his mother
息子が父親と母親を傷つけた場合
Or if a father hurts a child
あるいは父親が子供を傷つけた場合
or the mother hurt the child
あるいは母親が子供を傷つけた
or
また
mom hurt dad
お母さんはお父さんを傷つけた
child saw
子供は見た
In fact, the sentence will be based on
実際、この文は以下に基づいています。
who is respect and who is sorrow
誰が尊敬で誰が悲しみなのか
to deal with it, right?
それに対処するためですよね？
After the Tang Dynasty
唐の時代以降
It's actually like this
実際はこんな感じです
Then since the wife is the husband
じゃあ妻は夫だから
it's his god
それは彼の神です
after the wife passed
妻が亡くなった後
The most important thing for him is to take this husband's family
彼にとって最も重要なことは、この夫の家族を連れて行くことです
for his core
彼の核心のために
his main task
彼の主な仕事
It is said in the so-called ceremony
いわゆる式典で言われます
Guangsaiji Temple
祖宗愧 廣祭寺
i can't find much
あまり見つかりません
The picture of Guangji Temple is difficult to draw here
広済寺の絵をここで描くのは難しい
but anyway
とにかく
You can watch the cooking
調理風景を見ることができます
This is a planing plan
企画プランです
This is a hot chicken picture
ホットチキンの写真です
This is a Buddhist Nine Pose Mother
これは仏教の九つのポーズのお母さんです
Guizi mother has many children and grandchildren
グイジの母親にはたくさんの子供と孫がいます
Then this is a picture of casting Buddha and praying for four horses
それから、これは仏陀を鋳造して四頭の馬を祈っている写真です
mainly just to tell you
主にあなたに伝えるためだけに
wife if married
結婚していれば妻
a woman married like this
このように結婚した女性
After the husband's house, he takes his family as the core
夫の家の後は家族を中心とする
The whole point of his family is to
彼の家族の要点は、
Responsible for three meals and sacrificial offerings. Roast pigs, cattle and sheep. Roast duck and fish for three meals.
三食の食事と犠牲の供物を担当し、豚、牛、羊のロースト、鴨や魚のローストを三食担当します。
Then the other thing is to have more sons for him
それからもう一つは、彼にもっと息子を産むことだ
so that the family can continue
家族が続けられるように
In this case, the sacrifice of the good man
この場合、善人の犠牲は
If it is according to the martial arts disciples of this sect, as we just said,
もし、この宗派の武道の弟子たちの言う通りであれば、今言ったように、
Even if a loved one dies
たとえ愛する人が死んでも
your significant other your husband died
あなたの大切な人、あなたの夫が亡くなりました
This is what Yuan Chuntuo said about the half body request
袁春佗は半身の要求についてこう言った。
Half of my body should have collapsed
身体の半分が崩れ落ちたはずだ
That kind of context is right
そういう文脈は正しいよ
But if we look at other documents that were actually unearthed at that time
しかし、当時実際に発掘された他の文書を見ると、
You'll find that actually in what we've seen
実際に私たちが見てきたことからそれがわかるでしょう
Except that Mu Ziming of Yuan Chuntuo saw him at home
袁春佗の穆子明が家で彼を見かけたことを除いて
We can see it in many other unearthed materials
他の多くの発掘資料でもそれを見ることができます
Once the husband dies, the wife or the case
夫が亡くなったら妻か事件か
The case of Zou Yanshu is
鄒燕舟の場合は、
A wife when her husband is watching for her husband
夫が夫を見守る妻
next to that hand with another man
その手の隣で別の男と
someone fucked
誰かが犯された
It was discovered by my mother-in-law
義母に発見されました
This is all dug out Jane
これはすべて掘り出されたものです、ジェーン
We didn't know there was such a story before.
こんな話があったとは知りませんでした。
I don't know if it's love or a story from Han Dynasty
愛なのか漢の物語なのか分からない
so what
だから何
As for the mother-in-law, she will sue the officer
義母は警察官を訴えるつもりだ
Then a group of officials
それから関係者のグループが
Then start judging this
それからこれを判断し始めてください
widow's punishment
寡婦の罰
I always said how to beat him
私はいつも彼を倒す方法を言っていた
how to shut him
彼を黙らせる方法
What about various prison sentences?
さまざまな懲役刑についてはどうですか？
Corporal punishment, wait
体罰、待ってください
There are various discussions
いろいろな議論があります
When it's almost time to test
テストの時間が近づいてきたら
Suddenly there is an official who did not attend
突然出席していない職員が現れた
back from business trip
出張から帰ってきました
Tell me which case you are discussing
どの事件について話し合っているのか教えてください
I will also participate
私も参加します
after participating in the discussion
ディスカッションに参加した後
the official said
役人は言った
When alive, two are one
生きているときは二つは一つ
when dead
死んだとき
According to our Han out
私たちのハンアウトによると
Is this love or a legal order from Han?
これは愛なのか、それともハンからの法的命令なのか？
dead and gone
逝ってしまわれた
Can't handle it anymore
もう耐えられない
So what about this lady
それでこの女性はどうですか
she only
彼女だけ
if you want to find her check
彼女を見つけたいならチェックしてください
If you want to report her for any crime
彼女を何らかの犯罪で通報したい場合
It can only be said that she is not satisfied with closing the curtain.
満足せずに幕を閉じたとしか言いようがない。
No respect for this hand hurt venue
この手を傷つけた会場には敬意を払わない
you can't use adultery
不倫は使えないよ
because it's the same way as adultery
不倫と同じだから
to judge her
彼女を裁くために
The mother-in-law is very angry. When the mother-in-law and daughter-in-law hold hands together
義母がとても怒っている 義母と嫁が手を繋ぐとき
The mother-in-law suddenly found out that the daughter-in-law was with someone else
義母が突然、嫁が他の男と一緒にいることを知った
Linjiu's backside is messing around
リンジウのお尻がめちゃくちゃになってる
So I took her to the police
それで私は彼女を警察に連れて行きました
What about the result? The result of the discussion later
結果はどうですか?話し合いの結果はまた後ほど
It was the official who obeyed
従ったのは役人だった
According to a legal judgment at the time when the situation was still in Han Dynasty
まだ漢の時代の法的判決によると
I think that when a man is alive is after his wife dies
男が生きているのは妻が亡くなった後だと思う
just people who don't matter
関係ない人たちだけ
So mother-in-law is not eligible
だから義母は対象外
I don't have the capacity to sue this daughter-in-law
私にはこの嫁を訴える資格がない
This is the most recent colleague of ours is the academician of Industry Field
これは私たちの最近の同僚で、産業分野の学者です。
I just did some research and found out that there is such a thing
ちょっと調べてみたらそういう事があるのを知りました
Then the other one is
それからもう一つは、
In 2006, it was discovered in 2006 that the park had been built for 20 years.
この公園が建設されてから20年が経過していたことが2006年に判明した。
That's household registration
それが戸籍です
it's also late
それも遅いです
Only friends of academic level can do the research
研究できるのは学力レベルの友達だけ
found out that the girl got married
その女の子が結婚したことを知った
if after death
もし死後に
He won't stay at her husband's house either
彼は夫の家にも泊まらない
He went back to his mother's house
彼は母親の家に帰りました
And no longer bear the husband's surname
そして夫の姓を名乗らなくなりました
restore his original natal status.
元の出生状態を回復する
Just live with my mother's family
母の家族と一緒に暮らすだけ
why would you know
なぜ知っているのですか
Because the urgent obstacle is the transfer registration of household registration
差し迫った壁は戸籍の移転登録だから
we found out like this
私たちはこのように知りました
a custom of
的一個習俗
so it can be seen
それが見えるように
In fact, if there is a so-called
実際、いわゆる
Well
良い
what i just said
私が今言ったこと
Wufu's set
五福セット
In the Tang Dynasty, it was indeed
唐の時代には確かにそうだった
in law
法定上の
laid down
寝かせた
But in this process, there are five blessings
しかし、このプロセスには5つの祝福があります
The Five Blessings
五つの祝福
During the Tang Dynasty
唐の時代
Although I just said
今言ったばかりなのに
forgot to say this
これを言うのを忘れていました
267 years
267年
I already said when I got in
入ったときにも言いました
In the future, the Five Blessings must be approved to rule the law
将来、法を統治するには五つの祝福が承認されなければなりません
is to be stipulated in this way
このように規定されることになる
So in the Tang Dynasty
それで唐の時代には
Only then can we really write the meaning of Tang Law's calligraphy
そうして初めて、唐法の書の意味を本当に書くことができるのです。
But from 267 to the establishment of the Tang Dynasty in the seventh century
ただし、267 年から 7 世紀の唐の成立まで
During these four hundred years
この四百年のあいだに
In fact, we have seen in many other materials
実際、私たちは他の多くの資料で見てきました。
Wufu can't help
五福には選択の余地がない
really into the law
本当に法律の中に
people's living habits
人々の生活習慣
In fact, with his mother's family
実は母親の家族と一緒に
Girls usually
女の子は普段
maintains a fairly close relationship with his natal family
彼の出生家族とかなり緊密な関係を維持している
and legally
そして法的に
won't last forever
永遠には続かない
so-called concubine
いわゆる側室
or the husband died
もしくは夫が亡くなった
must be consistent
一貫性がなければなりません
this kind of attitude
このような態度
In fact, in the data we have seen
実際、私たちが見たデータでは、
are very few
とても少ないです
on the other hand
一方で
you can see
見ることができます
inside the business suit
ビジネススーツの中
It's also very clear, didn't we just talk about it?
それも非常に明確です、それについて今話しませんでしたか？
if one knows oneself
自分自身を知っていれば
only know my mother
私の母しか知らない
don't know my father
私の父を知りません
actually not
実際にはそうではありません
Because this whole uniform
なぜならこのユニフォーム全体が
It's all about the father
すべては父親のことだ
to regulate
規制する
What about when the law decides a case?
法律が事件を決定する場合はどうなるでしょうか？
In fact, the whole process
実際、プロセス全体が
From the business service to the Tang Dynasty
ビジネスサービスから唐の時代へ
determined in the middle
途中で決まる
There are many different cases
さまざまなケースがあります
have been through debates and quarrels
議論や口論を経験してきた
dispute
紛争
one of them was a
そのうちの1人は
what i just said
私が今言ったこと
when a son finds his mother
息子が母親を見つけたとき
killed his dad
彼の父親を殺した
if this is the case
このような場合は
Does the son need to sue the police?
息子は警察に訴える必要があるでしょうか？
According to the Confucianism of the time
当時の儒教の考え方によると
influenced by Confucianism
儒教の影響を受けた
the influence of these
これらの影響
official statement
公式声明
must be sued
訴えられなければならない
because dad is your king
お父さんはあなたの王様だから
Although mother is your dearest relative
お母さんはあなたの大切な親戚なのに
if you sue
訴訟を起こせば
ok
Ok
couple
夫婦
my parents domestic violence
私の両親の家庭内暴力
beated
殴られた
fight
喧嘩
beat to a degree
ある程度勝つ
mom can't stand it
お母さんはそれを我慢できない
dad killed
お父さんが殺された
son saw with his own eyes
息子は自分の目で見た
Should my son go at this time?
息子はこの時期に行くべきでしょうか？
sue the officer
告出官
It was an issue they were debating
それは彼らが議論していた問題だった
influenced by Confucianism
儒教の影響を受けた
Or officials who believe in military uniforms say
あるいは軍服を信じている当局者は言う。
Of course you should sue the officer
もちろん警察官を告訴すべきです
Because your Supreme has been killed
あなたの至高者が殺されたからです
How can you keep silent
どうして黙っていられますか
But officials who don't believe in this set think that
しかし、このセットを信じていない当局者は次のように考えています。
mother is your close relative
母親はあなたの近親者です
You saw him kill your Supreme
あなたは彼があなたの至高者を殺すのを見ました
You go to report on your next of kin again
あなたはまた近親者に報告しに行きます
In the end your next of kin were killed
結局あなたの近親者は殺されました
was seized by the government
政府に押収された
and then sentenced to death
そして死刑判決を受けた
So didn't you kill your loved ones?
それで、あなたはあなたの愛する人を殺しませんでしたか？
so there's no way to tell
だから伝える方法がない
this can't be sued
これは訴えられない
what to do
何をすべきか
Both sides are officials for the benefit of this law
双方ともこの法律の利益のために役人である
Should I sue
訴訟を起こすべきですか
sparked debate
議論を巻き起こした
was debating the sixth century
6世紀について議論していた
while still debating
まだ議論している間
an official said
関係者は言った
of course to sue
もちろん訴訟する
Because the House of Elishang has already said
エリシャン家がすでに言っているからです。
know mother but not father
母親は知っているが父親は知らない
The savages are easy to enjoy
野蛮人は簡単に楽しめます
It's the so-called resistance
いわゆる抵抗ですね
What does it mean to block
ブロックするとはどういう意味ですか
Mavericks
マーベリックス
Do calves and cows have a deep love?
子牛と牛には深い愛情があるのでしょうか？
Resisting affection is the meaning of affection
愛情に抗うことが愛情の意味
Yeah
うん
Clam
蛤
if you only knew cows
牛しか知らなかったら
you only know cows
あなたは牛しか知りません
don't know bull
知らない雄牛
Then you are a beast
じゃあ君は野獣だよ
For all the beasts know
すべての野獣は知っているから
love my mother
私の母を愛しています
Only civilized animals like humans
人間のような文明化された動物だけ
I learned to respect my father
私は父を尊敬することを学びました
So if you only know how to love your mother
だからもしあなたが母親を愛する方法だけを知っているなら
I don't know how to respect my father
父親をどう尊敬していいのかわかりません
Shibi Savage
シビサベージ
Exotic Beasts
エキゾチックビースト
Your morality is at the level of animals
あなたの道徳心は動物レベルです
almost
ほとんど
That another official is objecting
別の当局者が反対していること
the official said
役人は言った
this is no way to accept
これは受け入れられません
This way of talking is unacceptable
この話し方は受け入れられない
Why
なぜ
only with parents
両親だけで
born of the same breath
同じ息から生まれた
Zhong Tian Mi repays love in the wild
鍾天美、野生で愛に報いる
The love for parents should be the same
親への愛は同じでなければなりません
exclamation on its dignity
その尊厳に対する感嘆の声
change its pros and cons
長所と短所を変える
Why do you suddenly say that the father respects the mother?
なぜ突然、父親は母親を尊敬していると言い出すのですか？
Parents are good and mothers are bad
親は良くて母親は悪い
If the mother kills the father
母親が父親を殺したら
must sue
訴訟を起こさなければならない
If the father kills the mother without suing
父親が告訴せずに母親を殺害した場合
Mother should not sue father for killing father
母親は父親を殺した罪で父親を訴えるべきではない
so suddenly
本当に突然
push salary
給料を押し上げる
anti ancient fearless
反古代の大胆不敵
In fact, he said that anti-ancient fearlessness is wrong.
実際、彼は反古代の恐れを知らないのは間違いだと言いました。
Because Anti-Ancient is fearful
アンチエンシェントは怖いから
Because Yili Shangfu is clearly like this
なぜなら、Yili Shanfuは明らかにこのようなものだからです
But don't believe this
でもこれを信じないでください
And think mother and father
そして、お母さんとお父さんのことを考えてください
In fact, they are all the same breath
実は、それらはすべて同じ呼吸なのです
born together
一緒に生まれた
Such an official cannot accept
そんな役人は受け入れられない
So the law didn't change
だから法律は変わらなかった
That is to say, the father killed the mother
つまり、父親が母親を殺したということです。
Like discovering a domestic violence case at home
家庭内暴力事件を自宅で発見するようなもの
no son
息子はいない
I can't bear it
我慢できない
can't do it
それはできません
So everyone can guess
だから誰もが推測できる
Domestic violence cases at that time probably had no solution
当時の家庭内暴力事件はおそらく解決策がなかった
appeared
現れた
it just won't work
それはうまくいきません
Because basically the law can't bear it
基本的に法律は耐えられないから
Tell this kid to sue
この子に訴訟を起こすように伝えてください
any father or mother
父親でも母親でも
This is because of my mother
これは母のせいです
love and kindness between mother and child
母と子の愛と優しさ
challenged
挑戦した
It turns out we were just
結局のところ、私たちはただだった
The whole set of Eli Sanford
イーライ・サンフォードの全セット
in this day and age
この時代に
In fact, there are many, many
実際には、たくさんあります
amendments to laws
法律の改正
for example
例えば
tree is a person
木は人です
weak child
弱い子
if he be his father's heir
彼が父親の相続人であれば
The so-called son of the tree is the queen of the father
いわゆる木の息子は父親の女王です
That is, if a boy
つまり男の子だったら
became the father's heir
父の相続人になった
It's just that his father didn't
ただ父親がそうしなかっただけだ
During the first period, no children were born
最初の期間には子供は生まれませんでした
All that was born of him
彼から生まれたものすべて
later became
後になりました
heir
相続人
Then according to the regulations of business clothes with etiquette, that is to say
次に、エチケットのあるビジネス服装の規定に従って、つまり
If the number of sons is the father
息子の数が父親の場合
The son of the concubine became the heir of the father
側室の子が父の相続人となった
to himself the mother who bore him
彼を産んだ母親を自分自身に
Because that mother is a concubine, right?
だってそのお母さんは妾なんですよね？
Isn't it the real wife?
本当の奥さんじゃないの？
nothing to wear
着るものは何もない
wear very very light
非常に軽い着用感
It seems that I haven't taken it or take it for three months
3ヶ月も飲んでいなかったり飲んでいなかったりするようです
but in this era
しかしこの時代では
As far as we are talking about the era of Yuan Cuntuo
袁存丞の時代について言えば、
Because many sons are reluctant to part with their mothers
多くの息子は母親と別れるのを嫌がるからです
Since my concubine uncle gave birth to my good son
側室の叔父が良い息子を産んでから
I managed to become my father's heir
私は父の跡継ぎになることができました
How could I not honor my own mother
自分の母親を尊敬できないわけがない
so when my mother died
それで母が亡くなったとき
Although he is a concubine
側室ではあるが
I still take a heavy wound for him
私はまだ彼のために大きな傷を負っています
It's like he's my aunt
まるで彼は私の叔母さんのようです
many people like this
多くの人がこれが好きです
After many sons do this
多くの息子たちがこれを行った後、
Later the law was changed
その後法律が変わりました
just accept
ただ受け入れてください
Counting sons as fathers and then mothers
息子を父親、次に母親と数えます
It's the mother who is the concubine
妾は母親です
can also take serious injuries
重傷を負う可能性もある
besides
そのほか
If according to the ethics of the patrilineal family
父系家族の倫理に従えば
son
息子
one who gave birth to a son
息子を産んだ人
even the main wife
本妻でさえも
once his husband died
一度夫が亡くなったら
he becomes a widow
彼は未亡人になる
If a widow remarries into another family
未亡人が他の家族と再婚した場合
people
人々
As far as my family is concerned
私の家族に関する限り、
well done
素晴らしい
In terms of original depository, shepherds
元の保管所に関しては、羊飼い
already another
すでに別の
completely other people
全くの別人
It has nothing to do with my family
私の家族とは関係ありません
so what
だから何
The child born in the original home
本来の家に生まれた子は
Once my widowed mother goes out
未亡人の母が出ていくと
marry someone else
他の人と結婚する
after she died there
彼女がそこで亡くなった後
I will not mourn her
私は彼女を悼みません
This is stipulated under Yishangfu
これはマナービジネスユニフォームで定められています
But in the age we're talking about
しかし、私たちが話している時代では
These sons are reluctant
これらの息子たちは消極的です
It's her parent-child relationship
それは彼女の親子関係です
You'll know it after watching Yuan Cun Tuo Muzhi
『袁存佗木志』を見れば分かるだろう
even if widowed
たとえ未亡人であっても
There is contact with the original child
元の子との接触がある
if there is contact
連絡があれば
when you dress according to etiquette
エチケットに従って服を着ているとき
you are not allowed to mourn
あなたは悲しむことを許されていません
Knowing that the mother who gave birth to me died
私を産んでくれた母親が亡くなったことを知り、
died elsewhere
別の場所で亡くなった
I still can't help it
まだどうしようもない
So there are a lot of people in mourning
だから喪に服している人がたくさんいる
something happened
何かあった
Later the law was changed
その後法律が変わりました
acceptable
許容できる
can mourn
悲しむことができる
besides
そのほか
stepfather
同母義父
according to etiquette
礼儀作法に従って
This question of the Supreme Father seems to be
至高の父のこの質問は次のようです。
stepfather
同母義父
people who don't matter at all
全く関係ない人たち
because that's sex
それがセックスだから
It's not that I don't believe it
信じていないわけではないのですが、
I don't believe in pastoralism
私は牧畜を信じません
neither believe in pastor nor practice
牧師も実践も信じていない
right
右
But
しかし
It is because we look at the example of Yuan Chuntuo
それは袁春佛の例を見ているからです。
Of course there are many other examples
もちろん他にも例はたくさんあります
I just use Yuanchunto to make a shadow
袁春湯を使って影を作るだけです
you will know
あなたは知るだろう
Brothers and sisters between the same mother and adoptive father at that time
当時の同じ母と養父との間の兄弟姉妹
may be related is related
関連するかもしれない 関連する
not unrelated
無関係ではない
then if at the time of death
それから死亡時に
Originally, I was dissatisfied with the business clothes with etiquette
もともとエチケットのあるビジネス服に不満があった
But they all
しかし、彼らは皆、
A lot of people are supervising doctors, too.
医師を指導している人もたくさんいます。
The royal family is fine, the royal family is fine
王室、王室
Supervisor
都監持服
result to the end
最後までの結果
the law was changed
法律が変わりました
so that they can mourn each other
彼らがお互いを悼むことができるように
There is also the so-called
いわゆる
nephew mourning for mother
母を悼む甥
Mujiu is mother's brother
ムジュウは母の弟です
It's actually another family.
実は別の家族なんです。
He's different from me
彼は私とは違う
the same reason
同じ理由
in other words
言い換えると
Because of this mother
この母親のせいで
contacted a lot of original
たくさんのオリジナルに連絡しました
Looks like it's in the patrilineal family
父系家族のようです
ok person
大丈夫な人
And these people who don't matter
そして、関係のないこれらの人々
become related to each other
お互いに関係を持つようになる
This is in our section
これは私たちのセクションにあります
the study of legal history
法制史の研究
Research done by scholars later found that
後に学者によって行われた研究により、
Because of the kindness of mother and son
母と息子の優しさのおかげで
Patriarchy
家父長制
and modified the then
そしてそれを修正しました
etiquette and law
礼儀と法律
Mother
母親
really the importance
本当に重要なこと
The so-called king of Xihe did not sleep
いわゆる西河王は眠らなかった
Mrs. Grandson of the Beginning of Vision
ビジョンの始まりの孫夫人
sons and parents have different habits
息子と親は習慣が違う
so to speak
いわば
daughter is still
娘はまだ子供です
son to parents
息子から両親へ
It's homosexuality
同性愛だよ
no way to call him
彼に電話する方法がない
Then of course the daughter has no way to ask him to share.
そうなると当然、娘は彼に分けてもらうよう頼むことはできません。
what about this era
この時代はどうですか
In fact, when we look at it this way, we find that
実際、こうして見てみると、次のことが分かります。
Fertility is the matter of giving birth to a child and being a mother
不妊とは子供を産んで母親になることです
indeed in this one
確かにこれでは
In the age of the Middle Ages we are talking about
私たちが話しているのは中国の中世の時代です。
on this reproductive culture
この生殖文化について
There is a step forward
一歩前進です
how to say
どのように言って
in the fifth century
5世紀に
It is about a hundred years earlier than this Yuanchuntuo Belt
この元春沱帯よりも100年ほど古い。
There is a book called Xiaopin Fang
Xiaopin Fangという本があります
There used to be a saying in Xiaopinfang called
ファン・シャオピンにはこんな格言がありました。
Going to the ground to make grass is as old as dead
草を作るために地面に行くのは死んだも同然だ
What's the meaning
どのような意味です
we were
私たちはいた
When I read this sentence
この文を読んだとき
I can't read it
読めません
Why is it called childbirth?
なぜ出産と呼ばれるのでしょうか？
call down the ground to make grass
地面を呼び起こして草を作る
Wonderful
素晴らしい
The spirit is born on the ground and the law is like the old dead
精神は地上に生まれ、法は古い死者のようなもの
when this woman is about to give birth
この女性が出産するとき
to get down to the ground and sit on the grass
地面に降りて草の上に座る
like waiting to die
死ぬのを待っているような
Because it is actually very dangerous to produce
実際に生産するのは非常に危険であるため、
But why is it called the grass under the ground?
しかし、なぜ地面の下の草と呼ばれるのでしょうか？
I for this reason
私はこの理由で
read this thing
これを読んでください
feel very curious
とても好奇心を感じる
to check all kinds of information
いろいろな情報をチェックしに行ってみましょう
it turns out
それが判明
these are western
これらは西洋です
Here is a Japanese
こちらが日本人です
you will find
見つけるだろう
I used to have a baby
昔、赤ちゃんがいました
It's not the same as what you see now
今見ているものと同じではありません
still the same
まだ同じ
Now it's old again
今ではまた古いです
use now
又用現在
Again in this vertical way
もう一度この垂直方向に
giving birth
出産
This is a Greek peach
これはギリシャの桃です
look at the people behind
後ろの人たちを見てください
prop up his cutting nest
彼の巣を支えてください
there is a child here
ここに子供がいます
about to fall
落ちそうになる
This is a Roman relief
これはローマのレリーフです
look at
見る
there is a person here
ここに人がいます
prop up his cutting nest
彼の巣を支えてください
Then he put his hand here
それから彼はここに手を置きました
ready to pick up the baby
赤ちゃんを迎えに行く準備ができています
this roman relief
このローマのレリーフ
and then this is
そしてこれは
14th century England
14世紀のイギリス
Right, Mr. Shen
そうですね、シェンさん
A Miserable Woman's Handbook in England
イギリスの悲惨な妻のハンドブック
You can take a look
見てみることができます
here is a rope
ここにロープがあります
Then someone fell
すると誰かが倒れた
pull the rope
ロープを引っ張る
This man is teaching him how to push hard
この男は彼に激しくプッシュする方法を教えています
If the child in your stomach
お腹の中に子供がいたら
if this shape
この形なら
That's natural birth, right?
それは自然なお産ですよね？
It should be born smoothly, right?
順調に生まれてくるはずですよね？
if like other olympics
他のオリンピックと同じなら
Olympic gymnasts
オリンピックの体操選手
Posture words
姿勢の言葉
that's probably
それはおそらく
Difficult
難しい
unlikely to survive
生き残る可能性は低い
But in this wave shoveling manual, he will be taught
しかし、この波かきマニュアルでは、彼は教えられます
how do you make it smooth
どうやってスムーズにしますか
even a child in the belly
お腹の中の子供でも
Is it the hands on top, the head on top, or where are the feet?
手は上ですか、頭は上ですか、それとも足はどこですか？
how to massage your belly
お腹をマッサージする方法
how to go around
どうやって回るか
There is still a way to get this kid
この子を手に入れる方法はまだある
turn into this
これに変わる
Then let the child be born smoothly
それでは無事に子供が産まれますように
Then look again
それからもう一度見てください
this his pose
これが彼のポーズです
he's not lying in bed
彼はベッドに横たわっていません
he is standing he is sitting
彼は立っています 彼は座っています
he is standing with standing
彼は立ったまま立っている
Again, this is an Arabic manuscript from the 14th century
繰り返しますが、これは 14 世紀のアラビア語写本です。
manuscript look
原稿の見た目
Same thing, hold up his pigeon spider
同じこと、ハトグモを持ち上げてください
the way he sits
彼の座り方
find a way to get the child
子供を引き取る方法を見つける
Mr. that is in another room
別の部屋にいるミスター
Very nervous, I can't tell
すごく緊張して何も言えない
but anyway
とにかく
He is a vertical product
彼は垂直製品です
this is safe
これは安全です
Shin'an Dynasty's Japan
新安朝的日本
Inside of a demonic ultra near the twelfth century
12世紀頃のグールウルトラの内部
you can see
見ることができます
This man is having a baby
この人は赤ちゃんを産んでいる
The devil is waiting here
悪魔がここで待っている
If someone dies hard to hide
誰かが隠すのが難しい死を迎えた場合
This evil spirit can come to the mad ghost
この悪霊は狂った幽霊のところに来る可能性があります
then something to eat
それから何か食べるもの
the point is not it
重要なのはそれじゃない
Although this is a Buddhist saying
これは仏教の言葉ですが、
but what am I interested in when I see
しかし、それを見て私は何に興味があるのですか？
it's time for this person to give birth
この人が出産する時期が来た
he didn't lie flat
彼は横たわりませんでした
Someone behind him is supporting his den
彼の後ろには彼の巣穴を支えている人たちがいる
Someone in front is going to give birth to the next child
目の前の誰かが次の子供を産む予定です
This is the so-called grass
いわゆる植え草です。
When people used to give birth
かつて人が出産していた頃
The era that we originally lived in
私たちがもともと生きていた時代
I found out that it was written in the art
アートに書かれていることを知りました
You don't lie flat when you're about to have a baby
赤ちゃんが生まれそうなとき、横になることはできません
It is a vertical production experience
垂直生産体験です
Then we continue to find all kinds of information
それから私たちはあらゆる種類の情報を見つけ続けます
vertical production experience
垂直生産の経験
Indeed many civilizations
確かに多くの文明は
ancient and modern
就古今中外
Except by
ただし、
It is the ancient Chinese and foreign
それは古代中国人と外国人です
You can find such a vertical production experience
こんな垂直生産体験が見つかる
This one is from the fourteenth century
これは14世紀のものです
Vienna Herbs Inside
ウィーンハーブの内部
you can see
見ることができます
Someone behind him is supporting his den
彼の後ろには彼の巣穴を支えている人たちがいる
to squat vertically
垂直にしゃがむ
half done pose
中途半端なポーズ
There's another woman here
ここに別の女性がいます
Holding the medicine is like making medicine and stuffing it in
薬を持つのは薬を作って詰め込むようなもの
Let her skid smoothly
彼女をスムーズに滑らせてください
give birth quickly
早く産んでください
so what
だから何
we can discover the whole process of being a mother
私たちは母親になるプロセス全体を知ることができます
It turned out that no one actually studied it.
実際には誰も研究していないことが判明しました。
Because children have been born by women until now
今まで子供は女性が産んできたので
right
右
Has a man ever given birth?
男は出産したことがありますか？
Except Arnold Schwarzenegger
アーノルド・シュワルツェネッガーを除く
people about my age
私と同じくらいの年齢の人たち
Should have seen Arnold Schwarzenegger have a baby
アーノルド・シュワルツェネッガーの出産を見るべきだった
I am now in class if I say
と言ったら今授業中です
arnold schwarzenegger
アーノルド・シュワルツェネッガー
they say the governor of california
彼らはカリフォルニア州知事と言っています
child retired who
子供が退職したのは誰ですか
actually not
実際にはそうではありません
women are giving birth
女性は出産している
Because women give birth
女性は出産するから
so no history
だから履歴がない
historical research is
歴史研究は
Confucianism is the study of normal and unchanging things
儒教は正常で不変のものを学ぶ学問です
normal stuff
普通のもの
often
頻繁
History is interested in change
歴史が興味があるのは変化です
something changed
何かが変わった
we have
我々は持っています
Only historians are interested
歴史家だけが興味を持っている
This is from Sima Qian
司馬遷からです
That's what our Master Master said at the beginning
我らのマスターマスターが冒頭でそう言った
What did Sima Qian say?
司馬遷は何と言ったでしょうか？
Through the ancient scriptures
古代の経典を通して
On the occasion of salvation
救いの際に
some are gods
ある者は神である
some are
いくつかは
the boundary between man and sky
人と空の境界線
Historians need to find it out
歴史家はそれを解明する必要がある
If it is a matter of God, for example
たとえばそれが神のことなら
It's God's business for a woman to have a baby
女性が子供を産むのは神の仕事です
No man has children
子供を産む男はいない
So this is not a human thing
だからこれは人間の事ではない
women give birth
女性は出産する
But what is the human part?
しかし、人間的な部分とは何でしょうか？
how do women give birth
女性はどうやって出産するのか
there may be changes, right?
変化があるかも知れませんね？
It's a day for a woman to give birth
女性が出産する日です
It may still be days until now
まだ数日かかるかもしれない
Although in the 1970s
1970年代ですが
even earlier in the 60s
60年代以前にも
when women exercise
女性が運動するとき
There was hope to use that artificial sub-worker
その人造副労働者を使用する希望がありました
put it over there
そこに置いてください
Then after conceiving in it,
そして、その中で妊娠した後、
let him take the child
彼に子供を連れて行かせてください
It can come out like this
こういうのが出てくるんですね
But so far no success
しかし、これまでのところ成功はありません
Even as a surrogate mother
代理母としても
or women give birth
あるいは女性が出産する
Alright, between heaven and man
そう、天と人間の間で
There is a divide between heaven and man
天と人間の間には隔たりがある
Historians must first understand
歴史家はまず理解しなければならない
what are the gods
神々とは何ですか
we don't have to touch
私たちは触れる必要はありません
because it doesn't change
それは変わらないから
are certain
確かです
common sense
常識
what are human things
人間的なものとは何か
It's how a woman lives
それが女性の生き方です
This matter may be subject to change
この事項は変更される可能性があります
Tai Shigong said
太世貢は言いました
When historians are looking for heaven and man
歴史家が天と人間を探しているとき
What about the human part?
人間的な部分はどうでしょうか？
Changes through the ancient scriptures
古代経典による変化
you look early
あなたは早いようです
How to give birth in ancient times
古代の出産方法
How to give birth in modern times
現代の出産方法
You compare ancient childbirth with modern childbirth
あなたは古代の出産と現代の出産を比較します
make him this change, figure it out
彼にこの変化を与えて、それを理解してください
then write it out
それからそれを書き出す
It's called the words of a family
それは家族の言葉と呼ばれるものです
what historians do is
歴史家がやっていることは
On the occasion of salvation
救いの際に
Changes through the ancient scriptures
古代経典による変化
Then after writing out
それから書き出した後、
into a family
家族に
Maybe someone ignores you and doesn't believe what you say
もしかしたら誰かがあなたを無視し、あなたの言うことを信じないかもしれません
It's okay, this is my family
大丈夫、これは私の家族です
what about family talk
家族の話はどうですか
Descendents of Changzhu Minshan
常州岷山の子孫
someone will find out later
後で誰かが知るだろう
These people are waiting for me
この人たちは私を待っています
That is to say
つまり
They have put this information
彼らはこの情報を載せました
I don't know it's been two thousand years
2000年も経ったのか分からない
no one ever noticed
誰も気づかなかった
Going down to the ground to practice grass is like saving lives
グラウンドに降りて芝生の練習をするのは命を救うようなもの
I watched Yuan Chuntuo
袁春佛を見ました
Such a close relationship with his parents and children
彼の両親と子供たちとの非常に密接な関係
The role of this mother is so important
この母親の役割はとても重要です
But no one has studied
でも誰も勉強してないよ
When I was interviewing at Dr. Luo
Dr.Luoで面接していたとき
I was doing legal history at that time
当時私は法務史を勉強していました
Just said the first paragraph
最初の段落を言いました
All are fragrant and fragrant
どれも香ばしくて香ばしいです
hit a ball
ボールを打つ
The oral examination committee said
口頭審査委員会はこう述べた。
every time a woman wants to live
女性が生きたいと思うたびに
why is it bloody
なぜ血まみ​​れなのか
They're all murderers?
彼らは全員殺人者ですか？
Women are not the most important vocation
女性は最も重要な職業ではない
Is it just to have a baby?
ただ子供を産むためなのでしょうか？
why nothing good
なぜ何も良いことがないのか
Whatever the relationship between husband and wife
夫婦関係がどんな関係であっても
These things are in your thesis
これらのことはあなたの論文の中にあります
At that time, of course I had to graduate in order to get a Ph.D.
当時、博士号を取得するには当然卒業する必要がありました。
I say because of art
芸術のせいだと言う
Because there is no data to study
研究できるデータがないから
So we didn't study it
だから私たちはそれを勉強しませんでした
That's because there is a new Zhangjiashan Han sister
それは、新しい張家山の漢の姉妹がいるからです
the master check out
マスターがチェックアウトする
So let's look at it from a legal point of view
それでは法律的な観点から見てみましょう
then they all listen to me
そうしたらみんな私の言うことを聞いてくれる
Just let me get my doctorate and come back
博士号を取得して戻ってこさせてください
is working with
と一緒に働いています
But when I came back, I found out
でも帰ってきて気づいたのは、
In fact, there is no information
実は情報がないんです
because we have no gender awareness
私たちには性別の意識がないから
That is, when we are doing medical history research,
つまり、病歴研究を行うとき、
Didn't think of thinking about medical history from a woman's perspective
女性の視点で病歴を考えるという発想はなかった
Our previous medical history research was basically
私たちのこれまでの病歴調査は基本的に
civilian medical research
民間の医学研究
Emperor or Democracy Studies
天皇学あるいは民主主義学
Emperor Neijing Shennong Materia Medica
内京神農皇帝マテリアメディカ
all the way down
ずっと下まで
Then go to Li Shizhen Materia Medica Gangmu
次に、李時珍マテリアメディカガンムーに行きます。
who is modern now
今現代人は誰ですか
Otherwise, it's not civilian medicine, it's democracy
そうでなければ、それは民間医療ではない、それは民主主義だ
Otherwise, it is the legend of the great man
そうでなければ、それは偉人の伝説です
Otherwise it is the history of progress
そうでなければそれは進歩の歴史だ
It's just been making great progress
まさに大きな進歩を遂げています
More and more progress, and finally today
どんどん進んで、ついに今日
How our medicine prospers
私たちの医学はどのように発展するのか
Without the perspective of the recipient being the user
受け手であるユーザーの視点が欠けている
especially not writing medical books
特に医学書は書かない
but was taken care of by medical books
でも医学書にはお世話になりました
or being taken care of by others
または他人に世話をされる
or someone else who acts as a caregiver
または人の世話をする他の人
The kind that does not enter medical books
医学書には載らないタイプ
pure woman
純粋な女性
Women participate in birth, aging, sickness and death health care
女性は出産、老化、病気、死亡の医療に参加します
really everywhere
本当にどこでも
But because of our medical history
しかし、私たちの病歴のせいで
no such consciousness
そんな意識はない
So don't do this kind of research
だからこういう研究はしない
Going to the ground to make grass is as old as dead
草を作るために地面に行くのは死んだも同然だ
such a sentence
そのような文
has been around since the fifth century
5世紀から存在している
No one studied it in 1500
1500年には誰もそれを研究しませんでした
I found it very strange when I saw it
それを見てとても不思議に思いました
I want to know what it means
それが何を意味するのか知りたい
found out
見つけた
In fact, there are all kinds of ancient and modern Chinese and foreign
実際、古代から現代まであらゆる種類の中国や外国のものが存在します。
Images of this type tell us
このタイプの画像は私たちに伝えます
previous production pose
以前の制作ポーズ
is a vertical production position
垂直生産位置です
besides the person born because of this
このために生まれた人以外にも
other people supporting him
彼をサポートする他の人々
is very very important
とてもとても重要です
I am due to time today
今日は時間があるので
show you pictures
写真を見せてください
In fact, there are such explanations in medical books.
実際、医学書にもそのような説明があります。
It's the so-called refusal of female parents
いわゆる女親拒否ですね。
When you are about to give birth, there are many
出産が近づくと色々なことがありますが、
One wants to help him hold a pig
ある人は彼が豚を抱くのを手伝いたいと思っています
one to help him tie his hair
1 つは髪を結ぶのを手伝うため
one to help him
一つは彼を助けるため
if passed out
気を失った場合
I still have to struggle with him
私はまだ彼と闘わなければなりません
Spray him with water
彼に水をスプレーしてください
splash him wake him up
彼に水を掛けて彼を起こしてください
There are various
いろいろあります
there will be many different women
いろんな女性がいるだろう
while helping a woman
女性を助けながら
give birth to a child
子供を産む
And this woman who is about to give birth
そして出産を控えたこの女性は、
won't lie on a boat
ボートの上では寝ないよ
Let the doctor see him and give him a finger
医師に診察してもらい、指をさしてもらいましょう
or open two fingers
または 2 本の指を開きます
or open three fingers
または3本指を開いてください
he will walk around
彼は歩き回ります
because he figured out
彼はわかったから
Make it easier for the child to get down
子どもが降りやすくするために
So I will keep walking in the room
だから私は部屋の中を歩き続けます
Then he keeps walking through the room
それから彼は部屋を歩き回ります
The people next to him have been following him around like this.
隣の人たちはこうやって彼の後を追ってきました。
So the health care provider
そこで医療提供者は、
or maternity caregiver
または産科介護者
or married woman
もしくは既婚女性
or live-in
または住み込み
In fact, the person born with
実は、持って生まれた人は、
is one
1であります
Physical labor
肉体労働
find a way to give birth to a child
子供を産む方法を見つける
stay with us
私たちと居て
late twentieth century
二十世紀末
Later in France
その後フランスで
this scene
このシーンを見てください
It's actually a bit like
それは実際には少し似ています
but we
しかし、我々
not in our impression
私たちの印象ではありません
if you ask me today
今日聞いたら
impression of having a baby
赤ちゃんを産んだ感想
you wouldn't think
あなたは考えないだろう
A photo like this, right?
こんな写真ですよね？
because we have entered into
に入ってしまったので
after modern
現代以後
all lying in the hospital
全員が病院で横たわっている
let the doctor
医者に任せてください
the height of that bed
そのベッドの高さ
almost
ほとんど
The height of the doctor's convenience
医師の利便性の高さ
You won't come down casually
気軽に降りてくることはないよ
If it hurts and you can't give birth
痛くて産めないなら
That might be the mother-in-law
それが義母かもしれない
mother-in-law to a degree
ある意味義母
In fact, people have
実際、人々は
born this person
この人に生まれた
no longer conscious
もう意識がない
Actually I have a lot
実は私は持っています
some friends were born by in-laws
何人かの友人は義理の両親によって生まれました
after birth
誕生後
He said he didn't remember at all
彼は全く覚えていないと言った
The moment he suddenly became a mother
突然母親になった瞬間
he has no impression
彼には何の印象もありません
feel very sad
とても悲しいです
of course of course
もちろんもちろん
want this myself
これは自分でも欲しい
consciously say
意識的に言う
I suddenly become a mother
突然母親になってしまった
the pain is severe
痛みがひどい
when i was in class
私が授業中に
will tell the students
生徒たちに言います
go back and ask mom
あなたは戻ってお母さんに尋ねます
How painful was that time
あの時はどんなに辛かっただろう
squatting or squatting
しゃがむかしゃがむか
still sitting
まだ座っている
how much pain
どのくらいの痛み
But my students come back
でも生徒たちは戻ってくる
Most of the answers are
ほとんどの答えは、
Mom said it hurts to give birth to you
お母さんはあなたを産むのが痛いって言ってた
not as good as later
比不上以後
come to hurt my heart
私の心を傷つけに来て
Then there's no way
それなら仕方ないよ
this totally leaves
これは完全に残ります
my original topic
私の元のトピック
but anyway
とにかく
you can know
あなたは知ることができます
This form of production
このような生産形態
In fact, it was like this in ancient times
実は昔もこんな感じでした
in the middle of the twentieth century
20世紀半ばに
Because the whole world is the same
世界中が同じだから
the relationship of scientism
それは科学主義の関係です
Make the mother-in-law's birth rate too high, too high
義母の出生率を高すぎる、高すぎる
So the French obstetrician
そこでフランスの産科医は、
This is a French obstetrician
こちらはフランスの産科医です
decided to
決定要
nostalgia
ノスタルジー
Get inspired by historical plot databases
歴史的なプロットのデータベースからインスピレーションを受ける
How to help women who come to his clinic to give birth
彼のクリニックを訪れる女性の出産をどのようにサポートするか
It is possible to have an experience of the process of being a mother
母親になる過程を体験できる
if they want
彼らが望むなら
If you are not in good health, of course you can't try it casually
体調が優れない場合はもちろん気軽に試すことはできません
sometimes it's dangerous
時々それは危険です
It's really dangerous
本当に危険です
not without danger
危険がないわけではない
But if you still can
でも、まだできるなら
she will have a husband by her side
彼女には夫がそばにいるだろう
licensed nurse
認定看護師
plus this obstetrician
それにこの産科医
help this maternity
この出産を助けてください
Use the Vertical Production Position
垂直の生産位置を使用する
Bone Fang left the little ones
ボーンファングは小さな子供たちを残しました
What about her way of life?
彼女の生き方はどうですか？
After I came out, I was actually challenging the time
出てきてから実はタイムに挑戦していました
France or Europe
フランスとかヨーロッパとか
In fact, or around the world in the 1970s
実際、1970年代には世界中で
This kind of mother-in-law birth rate is very, very high
この種の義母の出生率は非常に高いです
The custom of letting Qi intervene in the female body
女性の身体に気を介入させる風習
So some obstetricians were very upset about her
そのため、一部の産科医は彼女のことに非常に腹を立てていました
I think she's blocking people's money.
彼女は人々のお金をブロックしていると思います。
because if you give birth
なぜなら、出産したら
In the early stage, there were indeed more
初期段階では確かにもっとありました
What's more, she said that when you give birth there, it's a normal delivery.
しかも、そこで出産する場合は普通分娩だそうです。
That's why we can use the vertical production position you just mentioned
だからこそ、先ほどおっしゃった垂直生産姿勢を活用できるのです。
It is even more impossible if the childbirth is reversed
逆出産ならさらに無理
Then this doctor Michel Auden said
すると、この医師ミシェル・オーデンはこう言いました。
No I also have a buttock on my side
いいえ、私も横にお尻があります
If you look at it today, of course it's counterproductive.
今見ると、もちろん逆効果です。
It's not normal. The butt comes out first.
普通じゃないですよ、お尻が先に出てしまいます。
But if you're willing to massage it slowly
でも、ゆっくりマッサージしてあげるなら
In fact, this child is still born naturally or stretched out
実はこの子はまだ自然に産まれたり、伸びて産まれたりしています。
As far as the buttocks are still stretched out like this
お尻もこのまま伸ばしたままで
So you know that in this context
この文脈ではそれがわかります
A resident is actually very, very important
住人は実はとてもとても大切な存在です
Not only those doctors who write medical books are important
医学書を書く医師だけが重要なわけではない
The whole process of getting a woman to be a mother
女性が母親になるまでの全プロセス
In addition to the fact that this person is very important
この人はとても大切な人であるという事実に加えて、
The person next to you is very important
あなたの隣にいる人はとても大切な人です
This is the picture on the poster and the cover of my book
これはポスターと私の本の表紙の写真です
It is because after I read these books
それは、これらの本を読んだ後だからです。
I did research and I found
調査して見つけました
This is really a big family from Sichuan
これは本当に四川省から来た大家族です
A moment for parents to pay attention to men's repayment
男性の返済に親が注意すべき瞬間
you can see
見ることができます
Here is a woman in a vertical birth position
こちらは垂直出産の女性です
Someone behind him supports his height
彼の後ろにいる誰かが彼の身長を支えている
Someone up front donated their sleeves
前線で誰かが袖を寄付してくれました
give birth to him
彼を産んでください
Who is this next to you?
あなたの隣にいるこの人は誰ですか?
Since the Buddha said that parents should pay attention to men
お釈迦さまは、親は息子に報いる優しさがあると言っているので、
Of course, if this is the mother, then this is the father.
もちろん、これが母親なら、これは父親です。
This is definitely not an obstetrician
この人絶対産婦人科医じゃないよ
not an obstetrician
産科医ではありません
this is father
これは父です
But this father is very interesting
しかし、この父親は非常に興味深いです
He's holding something like a test, like a book
彼はテストのようなもの、本のようなものを持っています
In fact, this is a very good explanation
実際、これは非常に良い説明です
Framing of our later study in the medical room
その後の医務室での研究の枠組み
from the perspective of your culture of birth
あなたが生まれた文化の観点から見ると
Let's see how to have a baby
赤ちゃんを産む方法を見てみましょう
Then give birth to a female tetrasomy
その後、女性のテトラソミーを出産します
is to help each other
お互いに助け合うことです
Born and cared for Helping people take care of each other
生まれ、世話される 人々がお互いを思いやるのを助ける
give birth to the child
子供を産む
Rather, these things are actually in medical books.
むしろ、これらのことは実際に医学書に載っています。
There is a different way of saying
違う言い方もあるよ
Just this man next to him is a father figure
隣にいるこの男性だけが父親のような存在です
If he is in courteous clothing
彼が礼儀正しい服装をしていれば
It's a very important role, right?
とても重要な役割ですよね？
But here he is taking a book and saying
しかしここで彼は本を手に取りこう言っています
Listen to me, he's still anxious
聞いてください、彼はまだ不安です
Because he's going to be a father
彼は父親になるから
But what about these three people?
しかし、この3人はどうでしょうか？
I don't have time for him
彼のための時間がない
They worked so hard to get this baby born
彼らはこの赤ちゃんを産むために一生懸命働きました
And where does his authority come from?
そして彼の権威はどこから来るのでしょうか？
not from his hands
彼の手からではなく
but in his hand
しかし彼の手の中で
something like a book comes
本のようなものが来る
What does that mean
どういう意味ですか
In fact, in medical books
実は医学書では
very much recorded
非常に多く記録されている
How do you feel about having a baby?
赤ちゃんが生まれることについてどう思いますか？
in what i do we just talk
私がしていることはただ話すだけです
Yuan Cuntuo is the age of Yuan Cuntuo
袁存侠は袁存侠の時代です。
The matter of childbirth is gradually being treated by doctors
出産の問題は医師によって徐々に治療されています
full involvement
全面介入
before Yuan Cuntuo
袁存陀以前
It's the Han Dynasty or earlier
漢の時代かそれ以前です
we see occasionally
私たちは時々見ます
Medical books will appear related to childbirth
出産関連の医学書も登場します
Mostly after pregnancy
ほとんどが妊娠後
or after birth
または出産後
Afraid of dystocia or poor health after giving birth
難産や出産後の体調不良が怖い
how to take care of
どのように世話をするか
But in the fifth to seventh centuries
しかし5世紀から7世紀にかけて
This is the era of Yuan Cuntuo
袁存乇の時代です
It’s the era I’m working on, and the problem hasn’t been explained yet.
それは私が取り組んでいる時代ですが、問題はまだ説明されていません。
The doctor gradually began to write from the time of seeking a child
医者は子乞いの頃から徐々に書き始めた
That is, we want to be able to know
つまり、私たちは知りたいのです
how can i get pregnant
どうすれば妊娠できますか
So there are all kinds of suitors
だからあらゆる種類の求婚者がいる
And earlier, the begging party
そして先ほどの物乞いパーティー
They are basically in the middle of the room
基本的に部屋の真ん中にいます
Just use the book in the room
部屋にある本を使うだけ
That is, a man who wants to have a child
つまり子供が欲しい男性
have son temple
息子寺がいる
Then you know the room
それなら部屋はわかります
The truth of the time period is happy at the same time
この時代の真実は同時に幸せだ
There is a son who thinks he is good and old, Shou Ye
自分はいい年をしていると思っている息子がいます、Shou Ye
Memorize the secrets of childbearing
出産の秘密を覚えよう
words in the book in the room
部屋にある本の言葉
When you have sex you want to make your partner wife happy
セックスするなら相手の妻を幸せにしたいですよね
You are only happy when she is happy, you don’t want to live your own happiness
彼女が幸せならあなたも幸せ、あなたは自分の幸せを生きたくない
If you only want to be happy, you will not be able to have a good son
幸せになりたいだけなら良い息子は産めないよ
The principle of the time period is happy at the same time, follow her principle
期間の原則は同時に幸せであり、彼女の原則に従います
She thinks the reason is up, the time is up, then follow her reason
彼女は理由が終わったと考え、時間切れ、そして彼女の理由に従います
Happy at the same time, she is happy, so are you
幸せであると同時に、彼女も幸せです、あなたも幸せです
What will happen in the end?
結局何が起こるのでしょうか？
Having a son will be capable, kind, and live a long life
息子がいると有能で優しくて長生きするだろう
This is in the book in the room
これは部屋にある本にあります
Who are the default readers of the book in the room? They are basically men
部屋にいる本のデフォルトの読者は誰ですか? 彼らは基本的に男性です
Because he is the truth of the world, she told you to do this
彼は世界の真実だから、彼女はあなたにこうするように言いました
Only your partner can give birth to a good son for you
あなたにとって良い息子を産んでくれるのはあなたのパートナーだけです
The ball pointers we saw before the fifth century were basically of this type
5世紀以前に見られたボールポインターは基本的にこのタイプでした
But after the seventh century we discovered
しかし、7世紀以降に私たちは発見しました。
between the fifth and seventh centuries
5世紀から7世紀の間
There are a lot of ball pointers that are late for wives
妻には遅いボールポインターがたくさんあります
late for women
女性には遅い
Qianjin Fang Sun Simiao is a great doctor
前金方孫シミャオは素晴らしい医師です
Inside the Thousand Gold Prescription of Sun Simiao, a great doctor in the Tang Dynasty
唐の時代の名医、孫思妙の千金処方箋の中身
The first volume in the front is about accumulating energy, which is about the basic principles
前編はエネルギーの蓄積について、基本原理についてです。
From the beginning of the second volume, all ball fingers
2巻冒頭からボールフィンガー全員
What should I eat? In fact, there are some medicines in it.
何を食べればいいですか? 実は薬が入っています。
It used to be medicine for sheep in Fangzhong
方中の羊の薬だった
But now I put it in the woman's ball medicine to eat
でも今は女性のボール薬に入れて食べています
That is to say, a woman can be a mother
つまり、女性は母親になれるのです
Concubine or a legitimate wife
側室または正室
The role of the aunt
叔母の役割
It is very, very important in this society of aristocratic families
この貴族社会では、それは非常に重要です
you can see
見ることができます
These sides of the ball
ボールのこれらの側面
Doctors also started to enter
医師も入り始めた
The woman in the medical book gradually became complete
医学書の中の女性は徐々に完成していきました
Not only after having a baby or getting pregnant
出産や妊娠後だけでなく、
itch
痒
tickle or
くすぐったり
Itchy babies, these
かゆい赤ちゃんたち、これ
but from the beginning
でも最初から
Ask for a pregnancy and a child and ask for a man
妊娠と子供を求めて男を求める
Asking for pregnancy is a son's business
妊娠を求めるのは息子の仕事だ
It also appeared in medical books this year
今年は医学書にも掲載されました
So the woman party becomes an independent party
それで女性党は独立した政党になる
and born from conception
そして構想から生まれました
How to fine tune after giving birth
産後の微調整方法
Make his menstruation normal
彼の月経を正常にします
Then the whole body can be born again
そうすれば体全体が生まれ変わることができる
this set of ideas
この一連のアイデア
It began to develop from the fifth century to the first book in China in the thirteenth century
5世紀から発展し始め、13世紀に中国で最初の本が出版されました。
The so-called rehabilitation
いわゆるリハビリテーション
Re-examination book
復科書
It's the book about independent subjects
それは独立した主題についての本です
The two sides of Furen University appeared
扶連大学の二面性が見えてきた
The way Furen University compares the two parties is
府連大学が両党を比較する方法は次のとおりです。
Golden generation
黄金世代
payment in advance
先調金
set the gold
ゴールドをセットする
can
できる
Then the red and white bag is solved so that there is no bad discharge
その後、赤と白の袋が解決され、悪い分泌物が発生しません
then you can conceive
そうすれば妊娠できるよ
How to give birth to a baby after the pregnancy is over
妊娠が終わった後に赤ちゃんを産む方法
Continue to transfer gold after giving birth
出産後もゴールドを送金し続ける
back again and again
何度も戻って
A living dragon is wrong because it's about women
生きたドラゴンは女性のことだから間違っている
Another female body that can reproduce
生殖可能なもう一つの女性の身体
So the whole set actually starts with
したがって、セット全体は実際には次から始まります
The fifth century is what we're doing
5世紀は私たちがやっていることです
gradually began to develop
徐々に発展し始めた
life begins to enter
人生が入り始める
Come to understand the whole female body
女性の身体全体を理解する
Then what
じゃあ何
There are a lot of details in these processes
これらのプロセスには多くの詳細があります
I won't talk much because of time constraints
時間の関係で多くは語りません
including birth
出産も含めて
how to which direction
どうやってどの方向へ
Coating the placenta of the child after delivery
出産後の子供の胎盤のコーティング
Where should it be buried?
どこに埋葬すればいいのでしょうか？
This child's life will not be
この子の人生はそうならないだろう
so it won't break
だから壊れないよ
Because it was said before that if the placenta is bitten by a dog
胎盤が犬に噛まれると前にも言われたので
children may seek death
子どもたちは死を求めるかもしれない
I don't know if you guys have heard this kind of story
このような話を聞いたことがあるかどうかはわかりませんが、
like this
このような
folk customs
民俗
There are still many
まだたくさんあります
But what about these things?
しかし、これらのことはどうでしょうか？
In the past, they all had their own pictures.
昔は、みんな自分の写真を持っていました。
we are in the age of authors
私たちは作家の時代です
between the fifth and seventh centuries
5世紀から7世紀の間
Gradually these pictures
だんだんこういう写真が
Including the orientation of raw and the orientation of embedding
生の方向と埋め込みの方向を含む
And the location of the delivery room, etc.
そして分娩室の場所など。
all together
みんなで一緒に
become dependent
依存するようになる
and needs tidying up
そして整理整頓が必要です
need to know knowledge
知識を知る必要がある
there is
がある
Where is the blood
血はどこにありますか
how many months pregnant
妊娠何ヶ月ですか
Which blood can't be dregs
どの血がカスにならないのか
If it is scum, it may be aborted
カスだと落ちてしまう可能性があります
Actually in other words
実は言い換えると
if he wants an abortion
彼が中絶を望むなら
Just fuck that tire, right?
そのタイヤなんてクソだよね？
So there is actually a whole set of knowledge that exists
つまり、実際には一連の知識が存在します
just to see who is using
誰が使っているかを見るためだけに
But mastering the art
しかし、芸術を習得することは、
basically male
基本的に男性
what we see now
私たちが今見ているもの
The knowledge of art is probably like this
美術の知識ってこんな感じかも
So around this time
それでこの頃
developed
発展した
those tires
そのタイヤ
Where are these blood levels?
この血中濃度はどこにあるのでしょうか？
with today's
今日の
some may be different
いくつかは異なるかもしれません
this of course leave
これはもちろん残します
what we say
私たちが言うこと
this part of the birth
誕生のこの部分
But just go into medical history
しかし、病歴を調べてみましょう
After being challenged by the influence of gender
ジェンダーの影響による挑戦を経て
actually
実際
That is to say, the so-called twelve catties of wheat internal organs
つまり、いわゆる小麦の内臓12斤です。
In fact, there is a historical evolution
実は歴史的な進化があるんです
not fine
大丈夫じゃない
not forever
永遠ではない
It originally changed from eleven catties to twelve catties
当初は11斤から12斤に変更されました
how to match
どうやって合わせるか
Then a smell of blood on top
そして上から血の匂いがする
In fact, there are different changes in different eras
実は時代ごとに様々な変化があり、
After using these later found data, we
これらの後で見つかったデータを使用した後、
Combine it with today's and you'll find
今日のことと合わせてみれば分かるよ
In fact, these have evolved
実はこれらも進化しているんです
Then we just said
それから私たちはこう言いました
These require a vertical production
これらには垂直生産が必要です
walking around that room
その部屋の周りを歩き回る
impossible for him to be alone
彼が一人になるのは不可能だ
There must be someone nearby to help
助けてくれる人が近くにいるはずです
So the caregiver becomes a very important person
だから介護者はとても大切な人になる
The study of previous medical history
過去の病歴の調査
Basically because it's all great people research
基本的にそれはすべて素晴らしい人々の研究だからです
Progress History Research
進歩史研究
So it is not very good to help those who do not write medical books
したがって、医学書を書かない人を助けるのはあまり良いことではありません
medical participant
医療関係者
But if we have a sense of gender
でももし私たちがジェンダー意識を持っているなら
In fact, participate in medical activities
実際に医療活動に参加する
health care activities
ヘルスケア活動
but no chance to write a medical book
でも医学書を書く機会はない
or leave your own gesture phrase
または独自のジェスチャーフレーズを残す
Basically mostly women
基本的に女性が多い
For many women involved in health care
ヘルスケアに携わる多くの女性にとって
But they have the opportunity to write something
しかし、彼らには何かを書く機会がある
we're going to use other data
他のデータを使用するつもりです
For example, time data
たとえば、時間データ
or sculpture data
または彫刻データ
This is what Buddha said just now in Parents N
これは今、お釈迦さまが『親N』でおっしゃったことです。
Another one is
もう一つは、
The so-called push photo residence time
いわゆるプッシュ写真の滞留時間
mother taking care of baby
赤ちゃんの世話をする母親
If a child is in the middle of the night
子どもが夜中にいたら
kill the piss
小便を殺す
mom puts herself
お母さんは身を置く
push the baby to a dry place
赤ちゃんを乾いた場所に押しやる
sleep in the wet
濡れたまま寝る
so as not to put the child
子供を置かないように
if you are
あなたがいる場合
when killing urine
尿を殺すとき
slap you
あなたを平手打ちします
call out
叫ぶ
this is not maternal love
これは母性愛ではありません
because of maternal love
母性愛のせいで
so gently
とても優しく
Piss-killing son pushes aside
バブル小便の息子を脇に押しのけ殺す
let him sleep dry
彼を乾いたまま眠らせてください
I will continue by myself
自分で続けていきます
sleep in wet places
濡れた場所で寝る
is the expression of maternal love
母性愛の表現です
So
それで
Babies are caregivers too
赤ちゃんも世話人です
very important role
とても重要な役割
then we are in
それなら私たちはいます
other materials
他の素材
also see
こちらもご覧ください
Actually nanny
実はナニー
is a very important role
とても重要な役割です
No one has studied before
これまで誰も勉強したことがない
then with this
それからこれで
After the study of parent-child concept
親子概念の学習後
or caregiver
または介護者
as a mother figure
母親の姿
After this research
この研究の後
image of mother
母親のイメージ
Mother's subject
母親の話題
also become negotiable
も交渉可能になります
The so-called milk becomes a mother
いわゆるミルクがお母さんになる
who is called mother
誰がお母さんと呼ばれていますか
Although they are all called mom
みんなお母さんって呼ばれてるのに
Some are Zheng's wives
鄭氏の妻もいる
is the aunt
おばさんです
some tree mothers
いくつかの木の母親
some are loving mothers
愛情深い母親もいる
some thick mothers
太い母親もいる
Some are foster mothers
養母になっている人もいる
There is another kind called mother
母親と呼ばれる別の種類があります
If a mother counts as a mother
如母算不算母
This is actually in Wei Jin's Mei Dynasty
これは実際には魏晋の明王朝のものです。
that's what i did
それが私がやったことです
This era of Yuan Cunda
ユアン・クンダのこの時代
Doctor Shi debated very fiercely
Shi医師は非常に激しく議論した
Some world doctors think
世界の一部の医師はこう考えています
Mom has milk like a mother has milk.
母親がミルクを持っているように、ママもミルクを持っています。
You grow up by eating his milk
君は彼のミルクを食べて成長する
Of course when he died
もちろん亡くなった時も
Are you going to kill him for three months?
3ヶ月も殺す気か？
least least
少なくとも少なくとも
Are you going to serve him privately for three months?
3ヶ月間彼に個人的に仕えるつもりですか？
But some world doctors say
しかし、世界の医師の中にはこう言う人もいます。
Rumu is basically born of compassion and Bodhisattva
Rumuは基本的に慈悲と菩薩から生まれます
Born as a sad daughter in the family
悲しい家族の娘として生まれました
He just so happens to have tits for wild kids
彼はたまたま野生児向けのおっぱいを持っているだけだ
That's why I came
だから私は来たのです
how can that be
どうやってそれができるの
I am the precious son of the family
私は一家の大切な息子です
how can i come for a slave woman
どうすれば奴隷の女性を迎えに来ることができますか
He's dead and I'll take his wounds
彼は死んだ、そして私が彼の傷を引き受ける
what is this like
これは何ですか
Who is the mother of the word mother?
「母」という言葉の母は誰ですか？
If you have milk, you are a mother
ミルクがあればあなたは母親です
The one who gave birth to you is the mother
あなたを産んだのはお母さんです
Or dad's wife is your mother
それともお父さんの妻があなたのお母さんです
This is actually what we do
これが実際に私たちがやっていることです
The era of Yuan Cunda
ユアン・クンダの時代
there's a lot of debate
たくさんの議論があります
Then Fujinian library except
それから藤仁図書館を除く
and ours
そして私たちの
Cultural Heritage Exhibition Hall of Shiyusho
誌遊所文化財展示館
Except what I just said
私が今言ったことを除いて
That Yuan Cunda wooden outside
屋外が木造のユアン・クンダ
There is also a very famous wooden
非常に有名な木製もあります
It is Su Dongpo's nurse's wooden
蘇東坡の看護師の木製です
Seki Na
母関名など
this was me
これは私だった
I also like to find Chinese reading
中国語の読み方を探すのも好きです
but today is not enough time
でも今日は時間が足りない
I'm also embarrassed to teach you how to read
読み方を教えるのも恥ずかしいです
you can see
見ることができます
Zhao Jun Su Shizi's sister is like a mother
趙君蘇詩子の妹は母親のような存在
Ren Shiming Cailian, have you seen it?
レン・シミン・カイリアン、見たことがありますか？
Su Shi Su Dongpo's nanny is called Ren Cailian
蘇史蘇東坡の乳母はレン・カイリアンと呼ばれる
This Ren Cailian is following Su Dongpo's mother
このレン・カイリアンは蘇東坡の母親を追っている
married into Su Dongpo's father's house
蘇東坡の父の家に嫁ぐ
Come to their house for 35 years
35年間住んでいる家に来てください
Miyahashi is diligent and thrifty, he treats the elderly, it is very good if he does not dump him
宮橋さんは勤勉で倹約家で、お年寄りにも優しく、捨てられなければとても良いです
Not only did he feed Su Dongpo's milk
彼は蘇東坡に乳を飲ませただけではない
Also fed the milk of Su Dongpo's sister Ba Niang
蘇東坡の妹、バニアンにもミルクを与えた
And also helped Su Dongpo take care of her own son
また、蘇東坡が自分の息子の世話をするのにも役立ちました
sushi's son
お寿司の息子
Sell ​​on behalf
代理販売
It is equal to the three generations that nurse Ren Cailian helped to take care of
看護師レン・カイリアンさんが世話をした3世代に相当します
As a result, Su Dongpo, because of party disputes,
その結果、蘇東坡は党争のせいで、
When he was demoted to Huang Gang
黄崗に左遷されたとき
He followed him and folded in yellow
彼は彼を追って黄色に折り畳んだ
in the process of being demoted
降格される途中
When the nanny went with Su Dongpo
乳母が蘇東坡と一緒に行ったとき
Yuanfeng three years
元豊三年
This is 1080
これは1080です
Died at Su Dongpo
蘇東坡で死去
Some people have children and sometimes they have children that are not their own
子供がいる人もいれば、自分の子供ではない子供がいる場合もあります
It is not necessary to benefit from death
死から恩恵を受ける必要はない
dead must be buried
死者は埋葬されなければならない
But not necessarily buried in his own box
しかし、必ずしも自分の箱に埋もれているわけではありません
I follow it from thinking about it
考えてから従う
Its spirit is everything
その精神がすべてだ
I come to worship you
あなたを崇拝するために来ました
I hope you come to eat
食べに来ていただければ幸いです
in the future if i leave here
将来、私がここを離れたら
i will send you to you
あなたに送ります
I worship you in different places
さまざまな場所であなたを崇拝しています
I hope your soul follows me too
あなたの魂も私に従ってくれることを願っています
come and eat forever
来て永遠に食べてください
Su Dongpo is a great writer
蘇東坡は素晴らしい作家です
The nanny is a member of his mother's family
乳母は彼の母親の家族の一員です
The sad girl followed and married
悲しい少女は追いかけて結婚した
The great writer not only helped him write his name
偉大な作家は自分の名前を書くのを手伝っただけではありません
And this is Su Dongpo's words
これは蘇東坡の言葉です
Just make money by writing
本を書いてお金を稼ぐだけ
earn your own money write your own
自分でお金を稼ぐ 自分で書く
Then ask someone to engrave such a famous name
それから誰かにそのような有名な名前を彫ってもらいます
A woman born from grief
悲しみから生まれた女性
Get the name of a great writer
偉大な作家の名前を調べてください
and write by yourself
そして自分で書いてください
Why
なぜ
because of the mother's name
母親の名前のせいで
There are mothers and milk TV mothers
ママもいるしミルクTVママもいる
This Shepherd's name is in our library
この羊飼いの名前は私たちの図書館にあります
It's been a long time
おひさしぶりですね
also in the 21st century
21世紀にも
Our scholars are only beginning to notice this
私たちの学者たちはこのことに気づき始めたばかりです
because realized
気づいたから
and also see
そしてまた見てください
from the name of shepherd
羊飼いの名前から
Su Dongpo
蘇東坡
This feeling when being flattened
ぺしゃんこになったときのこの感じ
right
右
It is not necessary to be born because of nourishment
栄養があるから生まれる必要はない
It is not necessary to stand after death
死後に立つ必要はない
Who knew Su Dongpo
蘇東坡を知っている人は誰ですか
maybe you feel like
たぶんあなたは次のように感じています
Maybe he died in Huanggang
もしかしたら黄崗で亡くなったのかもしれない
not impossible
不可能ではない
if i go back
戻ったら
I hope your soul will follow me
あなたの魂が私に従ってくれることを願っています
I will continue to worship you again
これからもまた拝み続けます
Fengyang
鳳陽
so
それで
from different angles
さまざまな角度から
When I look at the medical room again
改めて医務室を見ると
what we saw
私たちが見たもの
medical classic famous doctor story
医療の古典的な有名な医師の物語
this kind of medical room
こんな医務室
from the point of view of health care
ヘルスケアの観点から
come in
お入りください
different stories
さまざまな物語
on the other hand
一方で
we also found
私たちも見つけました
Women in the role of health care
ヘルスケアの役割を担う女性
Actually very diverse
実際には非常に多様です
and frequently
そして頻繁に
Not only female doctors
女性医師だけではありません
Women's medical room is hard to do
女性診療室は大変です
Find a female doctor
女性医師を探す
In fact, just like this history of women's literature
実はこの女性文学の歴史と同じように、
Hu Xiaozhen, Director of the Institute of Culture and Philosophy
胡暁鎮、文化哲学研究所所長
he just
ちょうど彼
He returned to Taiwan almost at the same time as me
彼は私とほぼ同じ時期に台湾に帰国しました
and then work together in the Institute
そして研究所で一緒に働きます
When he was doing history of women's literature
女流文学史をやっていた頃
I also find it very interesting
私もとても面白いと思います
Because he was a talker for women in the Ming and Qing Dynasties
彼は明清時代の女性の話し手だったからです。
women's articles
女性の記事
but you know we used to do
でも、私たちがかつてそうしていたことは知っています
in the history of Chinese literature
中国文学史の中で
I also find it difficult to do.
私もやりにくいと思います。
It's hard for women
女性には大変ですね
Because Tang Poetry Sends Lyrics to Ming and Qing Dynasties
唐の詩が明と清の時代に歌詞を送ったからだ
There are not many female poets of Tang poetry
唐の詩には女性詩人が少ない
talk about that
それについて話してください
That's the priestess
それが巫女さんです
Nv Ji Nv language selection machine or Xuetao
Nv Ji Nv 言語選択マシンまたは Xuetao
There are not many people who send words and talk about them.
言葉を送って、それについて話す人はあまり多くありません。
It's the truth of accommodation, Qing Zhao
それが宿泊の真実です、チンジャオ
Ming and Qing novels
明と清の小説
Little Writers Without Women in Ming and Qing Dynasties
明・清時代の女性のいない小さな作家たち
so there is nothing to write
だから書くことは何もない
That is, if you use the original
つまり、オリジナルを使用すると、
Existing classification
既存の分類
Tang Poetry Sending Lyrics Ming and Qing Novels
唐の詩を送る歌詞 明と清の小説
Then you say I want to be a woman
それからあなたは私が女性になりたいと言います
Then you come to see the little female writers of the Ming and Qing Dynasties
次に、明と清の時代の小さな女性作家に会いに来ます。
you'll find it hard to do
あなたはそれをするのが難しいと思うでしょう
But Teacher Hu Xiaozhen
しかし胡暁鎮先生
just use another way
別の方法を使ってください
what does he use
彼は何を使っていますか
this difference
この違い
He seems to be the same as last year
彼は去年と同じようだ
Knowledge testing is here to talk about this
知識テストはこれについて話すためにここにあります
right
右
what he wrote from women writers
彼が女性作家から書いたこと
to reschedule
スケジュールを変更する
You don't have to be limited by Tang poetry, Song Ci, Ming and Qing novels
唐の詩、宋慈、明、清の小説に縛られる必要はありません
women in the Ming and Qing Dynasties
明・清時代の女性たち
She still writes poetry
彼女は今でも詩を書いています
So although it is Tang poetry, Song Ci, Ming and Qing novels
つまり、唐の詩、宋慈、明、清の小説ではありますが、
But the female writers of the Ming and Qing Dynasties
しかし、明清時代の女流作家たちは、
with poetry long poetry
詩と長い詩
to express the so-called talk of her story
彼女の物語のいわゆるトークを表現する
So there is no need to be limited by the original
したがって、オリジナルに制限される必要はありません
We can't find this predicament that women can do
女性にできるこの苦境は見つからない
when we have this awareness
この認識を持ったとき
When you look at the medical history, you will also find that
病歴を見てみるとこんなことも分かります
The role of female single medical care is very large
女性の単独医療の役割は非常に大きい
We used to be called Sangu and Liupo
私たちは以前はサングとリウポと呼ばれていました
It's a curse word
呪いの言葉だよ
As a result, you look carefully
その結果、よく見てみると、
actually what is it talking about
実際、それは何について話しているのですか
nun taoist hanging aunt pharmacist
尼僧、道士、叔母、薬剤師
Mei Po, Steady Po, Tooth Pot, Shiva, Ex-Woman
プラム、ステディ、トゥース、シヴァ、元妻
medicine woman
医者の女性
A stable woman is a miserable woman
安定した女性は不幸な女性だ
In fact, women's medical caregivers
実は女性の医療従事者は、
health caregiver
医療従事者
what about others
他の人はどうですか
Nun, Taoist, hanging aunt, Shiva, ex-wife
修道女、道士、ぶら下がっている叔母、シヴァ神、元妻
It's all about religion
それはすべて宗教に関するものです
and sometimes involved in so-called religious medicine
いわゆる宗教医学に関わることもあります
In fact, because of the relationship between single medical care, women
実は単独医療の関係で、女性は
health care
健康管理
If she often participates in birth, old age, sickness and death
彼女が生老病死を頻繁に経験する場合
He really can't survive taking care of
彼は本当に世話をしては生きていけない
just can't give birth
ただ出産できない
mother and son king
母と息子の王様
Or the baby in care dies
あるいは、世話中の赤ちゃんが死亡する
Or the serving mother-in-law died
あるいは、仕える義母が亡くなった
The story of healing youth
癒しの青春物語
The Tang Dynasty also started with a girl's story
唐の時代も少女の物語から始まった
It's the mother-in-law he took care of
お世話になった義母です
nothing can cure
何も治すことはできません
He has no money for medical treatment
彼には治療のためのお金がない
He just takes the meat of his own thigh
彼は自分の太ももの肉を食べるだけです
Cut it off and feed it to my mother-in-law
切り取って義母に食べさせます
A story that also became very famous
こちらもとても有名になったお話
So when women who are health caregivers
したがって、医療従事者である女性が
his story didn't make it into the medical room
彼の話は医務室には伝わりませんでした
In fact, there are many medical faces of death
実際、医学的には死に直面することがたくさんあります
is invisible
見えない
when you see women in
女性を見かけると
after the medical room
医務室の後
You will find that women often
女性はよくあることがわかります
There is no rush to take care of
急いで対処する必要はありません
When he has to take care of many people at the same time
同時に多くの人の世話をしなければならないとき
there is no way to take care of
世話をする方法はありません
I once read in the new Tang book "Legend of the Huntress"
私はかつて唐の新書「狩人の伝説」を読んだことがあります。
A story called Li Miaofa is
リー・ミャオファという物語は、
he has married
彼は結婚しました
marry somewhere else
どこか別の場所で結婚する
I heard that my mother's father was sick
母の父が病気だと聞きました
dying
死んでいる
He can't go back and take care of his father
彼は戻って父親の世話をすることはできない
he is a filial daughter
彼は親孝行な娘です
so he is sad
だから彼は悲しいです
I really want to go home
本当に家に帰りたいです
when you can't go back
戻れないとき
I heard that my father
お父さんがそう聞いた
has passed away
亡くなった
Then he gave birth to another baby, can't go away
それから彼はまた赤ちゃんを産んだ、離れられない
He really wanted to go back to the funeral
彼は本当に葬儀に戻りたかった
Because I heard that my mother is tired of taking care of my father
母が父の介護に疲れていると聞いたので
sick too
病気もある
if he doesn't go back
彼が戻らなかったら
maybe the mother died too
もしかしたら母親も亡くなったのかもしれない
he won't be able to go back
彼はもう戻れないだろう
but when he left
しかし彼が去ったとき
his one year old child
彼の1歳の子供
just keep crying keep crying keep crying keep crying
ただ泣き続けて泣き続けて泣き続けて泣き続けて
Ouyang Xiu is very powerful
欧陽秀は非常に強力です
author of new tang book
新唐書の著者
You must never believe what he wrote
彼の書いたことを決して信じてはなりません
But what he wrote clearly shows
しかし、彼が書いたことははっきりと示しています
The Dilemma of Women as Health Caregivers
医療従事者としての女性のジレンマ
What
何
Li Miaofa saw his son crying
リー・ミャオファさんは息子が泣いているのを見た
I want to go back and take care of my mother
帰って母の世話をしたい
So he bleeds
それで彼はハトを吸った
What's the meaning
どのような意味です
Cut off one breast and give it to my son
片方の胸を切り取って息子に与えてください
then stay later
それなら後で残ってください
and then he left
そして彼は去っていきました
It means that he wishes to be able to
それは彼ができることを望んでいることを意味します
take care of both sides
両側を大事にする
The ones here still need milk
ここにいる人たちはまだミルクが必要です
Those over there need his care
あそこにいる人たちは彼の世話が必要です
How to do it
どうやってするの
cut off one breast
片方の胸を切り落とす
leave it to his son
彼の息子に任せてください
Then he went back to take care of his mother
それから彼は母親の世話をするために戻った
This is the Legend of the Huntress in the New Book of Tang Dynasty
これは唐時代の新しい本「狩猟少女伝記」です。
Biography of Li Miaofa
リー・ミャオファの伝記
Look at these frankincense
このフランキンセンスを見てください
The history written makes people put a big question mark
書かれた歴史は人々に大きな疑問符を付ける
But what?
でも何？
he clearly showed
彼ははっきりと示した
so-called candle
いわゆるキャンドル
burn both ends
両端を焼きます
On Women's Participation in Birth, Aging, Sickness and Death Health Care
出産、老化、病気、死亡の医療への女性の参加について
Often catching golden arrows and walking away both sides will not please
多くの場合、金の矢を捕まえて両側から立ち去ることは喜ばしいことではありません
no way to succeed
成功する方法はない
In this case someone must die
この場合誰かが死ななければならない
But in fact, some have left their own children to take care of
しかし実際には、自分の子供の世話を任せている人もいます。
his brother's child
彼の兄弟の子供
Because otherwise he is afraid that people will talk about him
そうしないと、人々が自分のことを話題にするのを恐れているからです
Or his love can't bear it
それとも彼の愛が耐えられないのか
Seeing that my younger brother has become extinct
弟が絶滅したのを見て
If you die again, there will be no more
また死んだらもうないよ
So he had to put only one milk
それで彼はミルクを1つだけ入れなければなりませんでした
Just don't feed your own baby
自分の赤ちゃんに食事を与えないでください
Just feed my brother's child
兄の子供に食べさせるだけ
As a result, his son died
その結果、息子は亡くなってしまいました
This is all written in the benefit biography
これはすべて特典の経歴に書かれています
if you don't
そうしないと
we don't know he does this kind of thing
彼がこんなことをするのか私たちは知りません
Then write in the benefit biography
次に、特典の経歴を記入します
If he did it, we'd be sad to see it.
もし彼がそれをしたなら、私たちはそれを見て悲しむでしょう。
Because he is a candle that burns at both ends
彼は両端が燃えるロウソクだから
So someone is bound to die
だから誰かは必ず死ぬ
Women have religious expectations
女性は宗教的な期待を抱いている
is normal
は普通
He will seek the intervention of another world
彼は別の世界の介入を求めるだろう
hope to have another chance
またの機会があることを願っています
so what
だから何
history of religion
宗教史
look at
見る
Primordials are also a good example
原始も良い例です
He's widowed twice and he can't take it
彼は二度未亡人になったが、それが耐えられない
where is he going
彼はどこへ行くのですか
become a monk
出家
I don't want to be a mother in this city
この街では母親になりたくない
role of wife
妻の役割
I don't even want to be buried like before
以前みたいに埋もれたくない
any one buried together
一緒に埋葬された人
I want to get the heart of cultivation that he needs
彼に必要な修煉の心を手に入れたい
So the subject of religion actually has a gender awareness
つまり、宗教という主題には実際にジェンダー意識があるのです
In fact, there are also very interesting phenomena
実はとても興味深い現象もあります
For example, the one on the far left, these three are all Avalokitesvara statues
例えば、一番左の三体はいずれも観世音菩薩像です。
The one on the far left is north
一番左が北です
The one in the middle is from the Song Dynasty
真ん中は宋代のもの
The one on the right is from the Ming Dynasty
右は明代のもの
you will feel special
あなたは特別な気分になるでしょう
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
more and more like a girl
ますます女の子らしくなりました
We now see the statue of Avalokitesvara
今、観世音菩薩像が見えています
Seems like it's a female image
女性的なイメージがあるような気がします
In fact, Guanyin should have no male and female
実際、観音には男性と女性は存在しないはずです。
is it a bodhisattva
菩薩ですか？
But when people come close to it
でも人が近づくと
In fact, there is a historical evolution
実は歴史的な進化があるんです
Early Avalokitesvara was like a male statue
初期の観世音菩薩は男性像のようだった
Avalokitesvara can be seen in the era of Songzi Guanyin in Ming Dynasty
観音菩薩は明代の宋子観音の時代に見られる
Already like a girl
もう女の子みたい
female admirers have a saying
女性ファンには格言がある
this is not my research
これは私の研究ではありません
But some scholars have studied
しかし、一部の学者は研究しました
During the process from Beiwei to Song and Ming Dynasties
北魏から宋、明の時代へ
Female worshipers to Guanyin
観音を崇拝する女性たち
It is the increase in the amount of worshiping Guanyin
観音信仰の増加です
Make the image of Avalokitesvara gradually
徐々に観世音菩薩の像を作っていく
From male to female
男性から女性へ
That is to say
つまり
and proximity make the person taking the photo
親近感が写真を撮る人を惹きつける
Doesn't it mean that Bodhisattva has changed into a human being?
それは菩薩が人間に変化したということではないでしょうか？
No, still the same Bodhisattva
いや、やはり同じ菩薩だ
but to create this image
しかし、この画像を作成するには
A craftsman or entertainer of the image of a Bodhisattva
菩薩像の職人または芸能人
decided to make him appear as a woman
彼を女性として登場させることにしました
Make this person who comes to worship him easier to get close to
参拝に来るこの人をもっと近づきやすくする
So a change like this
そこでこのような変更
The study of the history of religion
宗教の歴史の研究
I'm doing it gradually
徐々にやってます
So, the relationship between women and religion
さて、女性と宗教の関係
really very close
本当にとても近い
You can see the example of Yuanchun Camel, which is a good example.
元春ラクダの例がその好例です。
But he's not the only one
でも彼だけではない
we were at about the same time
私たちはほぼ同じ時間にいました
Until the Tang Dynasty, some herdsmen
唐の時代まで、一部の牧畜民は
will see when the widowed mother dies
未亡人の母親が死ぬときを見るだろう
Sudden dying said I don't want to be buried with your father
突然死した人は、あなたの父親と一緒に埋葬されたくないと言った
Then this son will be very difficult
そうしたらこの息子はとても大変になるだろう
Because it's customary
慣例だから
Whether Confucian norms or expectations
儒教の規範か期待か
Parents' burial together is actually very important to this filial son.
この親孝行な息子にとって、両親の合葬は実はとても大切なのです。
reputation is important
評判は重要です
But this mother has been widowed for so long
しかし、この母親は長い間未亡人でした
and then fix until
そして次まで修正します
Then either go out or not go out
それなら出かけるか出ないかのどちらかです
Practice at home or practice as a monk
自宅で練習するか、僧侶として練習するか
Anyway, when he finally died, he told his son.
とにかく、彼がついに死んだとき、彼は息子にこう言いました。
That means I don't want to talk to my dad
つまり、お父さんとは話したくないのです
I don't want to grow up with your father
私はあなたの父親と一緒に成長したくない
At this time, this son's Mu Zhiming
このとき、この息子のMu Zhimingは
if you see
見たら
The Tang Dynasty is the period from the Northern Wei Dynasty to the Tang Dynasty when this kind of Mu Zhiming
唐の時代は、このような穆志明が活躍した北魏から唐の時代です。
You'll see the hardships of that son
あの息子の苦労が分かるだろう
Because he wants to be a dutiful son
孝行な息子になりたいから
But he can't let his mother be buried with his father
しかし、彼は母親を父親と一緒に埋葬させることはできません
So he will be in this Mu Zhiming
だから彼はこのMu Zhimingにいるでしょう
in this preface
この序文の中で
A lot of thinking and emphasizing the hardships of being a widowed mother
夫を亡くした母親であることの困難について多くのことを考え、強調する
How to pull him up
彼を引き上げる方法
So in the end, his sons and daughters are respected and dare not stop
結局のところ、彼の息子や娘たちは尊敬されており、あえてやめることはありません
The relationship between women and religion
女性と宗教の関係
The way he died actually showed a lot
彼の死に方は実に多くのことを示していた
to another world
別の世界へ
or his attitude towards religion
または宗教に対する彼の態度
This is also about the age we are doing
これも僕らがやってる年齢なんだよな
In fact, burning life is included in the main case of bhikkhunis.
実際、燃える命は比丘尼の主な場合に含まれます。
Women burn raw offerings to Buddha
女性たちは仏陀に生の供物を燃やします
Hope to be reincarnated and reincarnated as a man
生まれ変わって男に生まれ変わりたいと願っています
Only in the next life can I become a Buddha again
来世でのみ仏になれる
Because of course it involves the issue of big students and small victories
もちろん、大きな生徒と小さな勝利の問題が含まれるため、
It's just that some people think that
そう思う人もいるというだけです
There is no way for women to get directly from this life
女性がこの世から直接得られる方法はない
Because it is born of misunderstanding, it will directly become a Buddha
誤解から生まれるからそのまま仏になる
Must be transformed into a man in the next life
来世は男に変身しなければならない
Only by cultivating as a boy can you become a Buddha
少年時代に修煉してこそ仏陀になれる
because there is such a relationship
そういう関係があるから
So some female practitioners feel
一部の女性施術者はこう感じています。
Then I'll get out of this life
そしたらこの人生から抜け出すよ
because this is disgusting
これは嫌なことだから
I can't even become a Buddha directly
直接仏になることもできない
So there is burning body to make offerings to the Buddha
仏陀に供物を捧げるために体が燃えるのです
There is also a Mr. Lu
もう一人のルー先生
This is also our colleague
これも私たちの同僚です
My predecessor, Mr. Liu Shuheng made it
私の前任者、Liu Shuheng 氏が作ったものです。
It is women who want to make offerings to the Buddha
仏様にお供え物をしたいのは女性です
Is to give myself to my children
自分自身を子供たちに捧げることです
he wants to be in the forest
彼は森に入りたいと思っています
put the body in the forest
死体を森に置く
or in a cave
あるいは洞窟の中
Just don't bury it anyway.
とにかく埋めないでください。
Let the birds and beasts eat
鳥や獣に食べさせましょう
Because this is to provide for all living beings
それはすべての生き物を養うためのものだから
In fact, it is making offerings to the Buddha
実は仏様にお供え物をしているのです
is the same reason
同じ理由です
So with this idea
そこで、このアイデアで
In fact, in the same era
実は同じ時代に
There is a so-called concept of doomsday
いわゆる終末概念
that is
あれは
Law will disappear one day
法律はいつか消える
will cause this dharma
このダルマを引き起こすだろう
no way to go on
続ける方法はありません
Three groups are the most dangerous
最も危険なのは 3 つのグループです
most annoying
最も迷惑な
most in need of correction
最も修正が必要なところ
be well supervised
よく監督される
one is the monarch
一人は君主です
the king may be
王様かもしれない
Because at that time the law of destruction
なぜなら当時は破壊の法則があったからです。
There was also the Northern Dynasty, and there was also the Tang Dynasty
北朝もあった、唐もあった
There are so-called kings who exterminate Buddha
仏陀を滅ぼすいわゆる王がいる
don't believe in buddha
仏を信じないでください
or believe
あるいは信じる
or because buddhism absorbs too much of their taxes
あるいは仏教が税金を吸い上げすぎるから
Or because saints are all monks
それとも聖人はみな修道士だから
Don't join the army, don't pay taxes, etc.
軍隊に入らない、税金も払わないなど。
So there are monarchs who exterminate Buddhas
仏陀を滅ぼす君主がいるということ
So there is a saying in this life group
この人生グループにはこんな格言があります
These are the Buddhist intellectuals
彼らは仏教知識人です
will talk about the so-called destruction
いわゆる破壊について話します
Three very serious effects
3 つの非常に深刻な影響
one of them is the monarch
そのうちの一人が君主です
bad monarch may
悪い君主かもしれない
So it is very important to correct and supervise the monarch.
したがって、君主を正し、監督することが非常に重要です。
The other is the corruption within the Shengtuan itself.
もう一つは聖団自体の腐敗である。
It may also result in a penalty
ペナルティが課せられることもある
The last one is the blackening of a woman's body
最後は女性の体の黒ずみ
So if a woman becomes a monk
それで女性が僧侶になったら
It will reduce Buddhism and politics by 500 years
仏教と政治を500年縮めるだろう
500 years or 800 years 500 years
500年か800年 500年
so at first
だから最初は
Shakya's aunt
シャカの叔母
When Da Yi is going to leave home
ダーイーが家を出るとき
Sakyamuni didn't want it
釈迦牟尼はそれを望まなかった
But then there was an economic
しかしその後、経済不況が起こり、
various discussions
さまざまな議論
Finally let him leave the house
最後に彼を家から出させてください
But when you leave home, you must pay special attention.
ただし、家を出るときは特に注意が必要です。
female practice
女性の練習
don't let him misunderstand the body
彼に体について誤解させないでください
to influence other monks
他の僧侶に影響を与える
In fact among our colleagues
実際、私たちの同僚の間では
It is in the research done by Teacher Liu Shufen
それはLiu Shufen先生が行った研究によるものです。
You will find that there are some monks in this item
このアイテムには何人かの僧侶が含まれていることがわかります
Will write that it's a good thing he's not a monk woman
彼が僧侶の女性でなくて良かったと書きます
or next to his lament
あるいは彼の嘆きの隣で
inside famous saying
有名な言葉の中に
this is my lock
これは私のロックです
is where the burial
埋葬されている場所です
how far away from women
女性からどれだけ離れているか
How far away from Bhikkhuni
比丘尼からの距離
Yuan Chuntuo is very hopeful
袁春佛は非常に期待している
Don't hide his sleepy heart
眠い心を隠さないで
Of course he wants to be with other students
もちろん彼は他の生徒と一緒にいたいと思っています
you hide together
あなたは一緒に隠れます
Do you want to hide with your husband layman?
夫の一般人と一緒に隠れたいですか？
But what?
でも何？
Sheng didn't want to hide with him
シェンは彼と一緒に隠れたくなかった
Because after all, the female body
だって、やっぱり女性の身体は
under this context
この文脈の下で
not good enough
十分じゃない
So there are women like this
こういう女性もいるんですね
The Body Becomes a Religious Study
身体が宗教の研究となる
or a subject for discussion in the history of religion
または宗教史における議論の対象
Well, in order for women to get out of this
さて、女性がこの状況から抜け出すためには、
a voice of misunderstanding
誤解の声
Or get out of this pain
それともこの苦しみから逃れるのか
He may have had various activities during his lifetime
彼は生涯にさまざまな活動を行った可能性があります
For example he might visit a temple
たとえば、彼は寺院を訪れるかもしれません
he may visit holy key
彼は聖なる鍵を訪れるかもしれない
In addition, he may form the so-called women's society
また、いわゆる婦人会を結成することもある。
This is also the age we are doing
私たちがやっているのもこの時代です
from China until about modern times
中国から近世まで
fifth to twelfth centuries
5世紀から12世紀
There are probably such data showing
おそらくそのようなデータが示されています
women in the name of religion
宗教の名の下に女性たち
form a group
グループを形成する
Pay each other money
お互いにお金を払い合う
It's the same as dating, but it's not economical
デートと同じだけど経済的ではない
For example, sometimes it is led by nuns
たとえば、修道女が主導することもあります。
The women of this village in this village
この村のこの村の女たち
How much to invest together
合わせていくら投資するか
then put it together
それからそれを組み立てます
if someone dies
誰かが死んだ場合
Let's help her with the funeral together
一緒にお葬式を手伝いましょう
If someone in the family is married
家族の誰かが結婚している場合
when you need help
助けが必要なとき
Let's use this money to help her together
このお金を使って一緒に彼女を助けましょう
or someone to help her
または彼女を助けてくれる人
People give people money
人は人にお金を与える
a religious woman
宗教的な女性
All-female religious groups
女性だけの宗教団体
to serve women special
女性に特別なサービスを提供する
needs of birth, old age, sickness and death
誕生、老年、病気、そして死のニーズ
This has also been unearthed.
これも発掘されました。
This is relatively recent
これは比較的最近のことです
some are from the past
いくつかは過去のものです
Some are recently discovered historical materials
最近発見された史料もある
if it is
もしそれが
What you just said is that you are married
あなたが今言ったことは、あなたは結婚しているということです
then widowed
その後未亡人になった
Then there are these social life
それから、これらの社会生活があります
if not
そうでない場合
if she was young
彼女が若かったら
just want to get married
ただ結婚したいだけです
In fact, we are in the Bhikkhuni Biography
実際、私たちは比丘尼伝記の中にいます。
will see
見ます
not easy
不太容易
even parents would still want
親でさえまだ望んでいるだろう
he can marry
彼は結婚できる
so what
だから何
The first forbidden solution in the Biography of Bhikkhuni
比丘尼の伝記における最初の禁断の解決策
The First Biography of a Bhikkhuni
比丘尼の最初の伝記
It is a forbidden solution in modern times
それは現代では禁じられた解決策です
he is already widowed
彼はすでに未亡人です
he married
彼は結婚した
then widowed
その後未亡人になった
On his own, he should have read the book
彼は自分でその本を読むべきだった
fearless overcooked daughter
大胆不敵な熟れ娘
He relied on his own poetic talent
彼は自分の詩的才能に頼っている
can play the piano
ピアノを弾くことができます
I went to different aristocrats' homes to work as tutors.
私は家庭教師としてさまざまな貴族の家に行きました。
Feed themselves
自分自身に餌を与える
This is the story of the fourth century
これは4世紀の話です
The Second Story A Second Example of a Bhikkhuni Biography
第二の物語 比丘尼伝記の第二の例
not a widow
未亡人ではない
The second example is a living female
2番目の例は生きている女性です
unmarried girl
未婚の女の子
she wants to become a monk
彼女は僧侶になりたいと思っています
Her father said tradition says
彼女の父親は言い伝えでこう言っている
Triple, repeat again
トリプル、もう一度繰り返します
get married repeat repeat son repeat son
結婚する 繰り返す 繰り返す 息子 ダブル息子
why do you want to become a monk
なぜ僧侶になりたいのですか
What is the weight of getting married? I have never heard of it.
結婚の重みはどのくらいですか? 聞いたことがありません。
No such thing, don't let her become a monk
そんなことはない、彼女を僧侶にさせないでください
The daughter told her
娘は彼女に言った
Why bother triple then reason
なぜわざわざトリプルにするのか、その理由は
why
なぜ
Because what she wants to do is walk the walk
彼女がやりたいのは、歩いて歩くことだから
jealous of everything
妒脫一切
I don't care about my parents
両親のことは気にしない
don't care about parents
親のことは気にしない
Because the purpose of my leaving home is to
なぜなら、私が家を出る目的は、
Hope to save all sentient beings
すべての衆生を救いたいと願います
help everyone
みんなを助けて
let alone parents
両親どころか
So you don't have to get married
だから結婚する必要はないよ
triple
トリプル
doesn't have to be triple
不一定要三重
is a reasonable approach
合理的なアプローチです
But her father still didn't want to
しかし、彼女の父親はまだそれを望んでいませんでした
So then
それで、後でどうするか
Father, of course, has many stories.
もちろん、父にはたくさんの物語があります。
no more
もういや
My father went to ask the Fotu City
父はFotu Cityに聞きに行きました
a big monk
一個大和尚
The great monk will give him one
偉大な僧侶が彼にそれを与えるだろう
the story is too complicated
話が複雑すぎる
talk too much can't talk
話しすぎて話せない
Anyway, it's right to convince his father.
とにかく、父親を説得するのが正しい。
He put sesame oil on his hands
彼は手にごま油を塗りました
tell him to go back
彼に戻るように言ってください
After my father went back, he took a look on the sesame oil
父が帰った後、ごま油を調べました
In the end, my father applied sesame oil to his palms.
最後に父はごま油を手のひらに塗りました。
Because I saw a big monk in the bonus
おまけで大僧侶を見たから
then this
それからこれ
Fotucheng told his father
仏城は父親にこう言った。
You see, what you see is a bit like clairvoyance
ほら、あなたが見ているものは千里眼に似ています
hand becomes a screen
手がスクリーンになる
Then I saw a big monk inside the bonus
するとおまけの中に大きな僧侶がいた
Then this Fotu City told his father
それからこのFotu Cityは父親に言いました
The big monk here is your daughter's previous life
ここの大僧侶はあなたの娘の前世です
He was already a great monk in his previous life.
彼は前世ですでに偉大な僧侶でした。
In this life, I should have left home
この世で、家を出るべきだった
so you still have to leave home
だからあなたはまだ家を出なければなりません
it will do you no harm
それはあなたに害を与えません
After my father heard it, because of a magic trick
父がそれを聞いた後、手品のせいで
The hand has become a screen
手がスクリーンになった
so believe it
だから信じてください
Just let my daughter leave the house
娘を家から出させてください
As a result, after her daughter became a monk,
その結果、娘が出家した後、
Because this father is in
このお父さんがいるから
Shila's men
シーラの部下
It is actually very heavy when it is tiger and hot
暑くて暑いときは本当に重いです
the king of happiness
幸福の王様
After his daughter became a monk, this father actually
実はこの父親、娘が出家した後、
The monarch is happy that of course his daughter is ordained
君主はもちろん娘が叙階されたことを喜んでいる
So dad gave him a promotion too
それで父も彼に昇進を与えた
so this
したがって、この
The final meaning of this biography of the bhikkhuni is that
この比丘尼の伝記の最終的な意味は次のとおりです。
Why bother to triple and then be a gift
なぜわざわざ3倍にしてプレゼントになるのか
In fact, to help parents, it is not necessary to get married
実際、親を助けるために結婚する必要はない
If you become a monk, you can help your father get promoted
僧侶になれば、お父さんの昇進を手伝うことができます
Because marriage was very important at that time
当時は結婚がとても重要だったので
Marriage exchange?
結婚交換？
Those who are married can help each other and become officials so that they can climb up
結婚している人はお互いに助け合って公務員となり、登っていくことができます。
But this daughter relied on the way of becoming a monk
しかしこの娘は僧侶になる道を選んだ
Make my father promoted to the top
父をトップに昇進させてください
There are actually many more stories.
実際にはもっとたくさんの話があります。
for example
例えば
And the daughter wants to become a monk
そして娘は僧侶になりたいと思っています
But mom has already set him up for a kiss
でもママはすでに彼にキスの準備をしていた
So after the engagement, the fiancée over there has already made an engagement
婚約後、向こうの婚約者はすでに婚約しているのですね
The dowry has come
持参金が来た
We just talked about the Taishi Law
先ほど大師法の話をしました。
This is the Tai Shilu in 267
これは267年の太実録です。
That is, if the offer has been accepted,
つまり、オファーが受け入れられた場合、
Even if you are already married, you cannot remarry
すでに結婚していても再婚はできない
what to do at this time
このとき何をすべきか
if you want to get married
結婚したいなら
We must return their employment to others
私たちは彼らの雇用を他の人に還元しなければなりません
So in biography of bhikkhuni
比丘尼の伝記では
There will also be great monks
素晴らしい僧侶も登場します
just take
ただ取ってください
The window head is washed with water. What is the window head?
窓頭は水洗いします 窓頭とは何ですか？
In fact, it is the slave stele wrapped in this black cloth scarf
実はこの黒い布スカーフに包まれた奴隷の石碑なのです
It means that the monk is actually very rich.
つまり、そのお坊さんは実は大金持ちだということです。
He has slaves to run his treasures and human resources
彼は自分の財宝と人的資源を管理するために奴隷を持っている
When he thinks that the debtor is going to become a monk, the debtor lady will follow
債務者が出家するのかと思うと、債務者の女性も後を追う。
when he is willing to accept him as an apprentice
彼が彼を弟子として受け入れる意思があるとき
He can give one of his own servants to the betrothed husband's family
彼は婚約中の夫の家族に自分の使用人を一人与えることができる
As a companion to the original bride price
オリジナル花嫁価格の付属品として
You will know why the monarch will destroy the Buddha at that time
そのとき君主がなぜ仏陀を破壊するのかがわかるでしょう
Do you think that the money in this temple is actually very, very rich in manpower and material resources
この寺院の資金は、実際には非常に豊富な人的資源と物質的資源にあると思いますか?
There will also be sayings in the bhikkhuni village
比丘尼村にも言い伝えがあるでしょう
Hey, the girl is engaged again
おい、あの娘はまた婚約したんだ
He wanted to become a monk but his mother got him engaged
彼は僧侶になりたかったが、母親が彼を婚約させた
After getting engaged, the son-in-law
婚約後、婿は
Even the engaged son-in-law refuses to let go
婚約中の義理の息子さえも手放そうとはしない
Be sure to chase after, the girls have already gone to live in the temple
必ず追いかけてください、少女たちはすでに神殿に住んでいます
He's going to run to him and harass him for trouble
彼は彼に駆け寄って、トラブルを起こして嫌がらせをするつもりです
As a result, again
その結果、またしても
This son-in-law was killed by a cow when he was about to go out to harass him
この義理の息子は、嫌がらせに出かけようとして牛に轢かれて亡くなった
like this type
このタイプのように
There are actually a lot of stories in this episode
このエピソードには本当にたくさんの物語があります
That is to say, widowed women become monks
つまり、夫を亡くした女性は僧侶になるのです。
she has her way and her problems
彼女には自分のやり方と問題がある
Besides, if you want to become a monk, she has her own way and problems.
それに、僧侶になりたいのなら、彼女には彼女なりのやり方と問題がある。
What will happen after leaving home?
家を出た後はどうなりますか？
In the north, there are mud drills in the south
北には泥んこ訓練があり、南には
There were so-called herdsmen in the Northern Dynasties
北王朝にはいわゆる牧畜民がいました
As we just talked about, people like Yuan Cun Tuo Zuo
先ほど話したように、袁村佗作牧志のような
In fact, there are also many monks and herdsmen
実際、修道士や牧畜民もたくさんいます。
For example, this bhikkhu mud
たとえば、この比丘の泥。
A shepherd was unearthed
羊飼いが発掘された
can see
見える
Not only can he
彼はできるだけでなく、
The Demon of the Empress Dowager of Civilization
文明皇太后の悪魔
Go inside the palace to get the bonus
宮殿の中に入ってボーナスを獲得しましょう
The so-called insider bonus
いわゆるインサイダーボーナス
Everyone recognizes the Empress Dowager Civilization
誰もが認める皇太后文明
Emperor Xiaowen's
孝文帝の
dark backup is grandma
ダークバックアップはおばあちゃんです
But my mother when I was in the north
でも、私が北にいた頃の母は
Later, grandma's concept seems to be a little confused
その後、おばあちゃんの概念は少し混乱しているようです
but anyway
とにかく
He is raising the empress dowager of civilization and raising Xiaowen emperor
彼は文明の太后を育て、孝文帝を育てています
Raising Emperor Xiaowen like this
孝文帝をこう育てる
This one was later sinicized
これは後に中国化されました
Empress Dowager Civilization herself is surnamed Buddha
文明皇太后自身の姓は仏陀です
he asked for this
彼はこれを頼んだ
This girl goes to the palace bonus
この少女は宮殿へ行く ボーナス
this life
この人生
he has many mentors
彼にはたくさんの指導者がいる
this disciple
この弟子
We don’t have time to talk about Tusun Network
Tusun Network について話す時間がありません
But the names are lined up with well-known intellectuals and officials at that time
しかし、当時の著名な知識人や官僚の名前が並んでいる
What about a person like this?
こういう人はどうでしょうか？
We're not really sure where he came from.
彼がどこから来たのかはよくわかりません。
But after he entered the palace
しかし、彼が宮殿に入った後、
After he got a bonus in the palace and got acquainted with these concubines
彼が宮殿でボーナスを獲得し、これらの側室と知り合った後
He suddenly said
彼は突然こう言いました
Actually, I have a pretty nice niece.
実は私にはとても優しい姪っ子がいるのです。
You are talented, you have good virtues and surnames
あなたは才能があり、良い美徳と名字を持っています
Later, the Empress Dowager Wenming was an emperor in the north.
その後、文明太后は北方の皇帝となった
When the prince accepted his niece
王子が姪を受け入れたとき
Later Queen Mother Lin
後の林太后
So you can know that after the relationship between the entry bonus and the stinky concubine is established,
つまり、エントリーボーナスと臭い側室の関係が確立された後、
He can also send his niece to the palace
彼は姪を宮殿に送ることもできる
who is empress dowager lin
林太后とは誰ですか
Empress Dowager Lin is what we just talked about
林太后については先ほど話した通りです
The heroine when Yuan Chuntuo was alive
袁春佛生前のヒロイン。
That is, when his son was emperor
つまり、彼の息子が皇帝だったときのことです。
he is the de facto ruler
彼は事実上の統治者だ
In other words, Sunny because of faith, religion
言い換えれば、信仰、宗教のおかげで晴れたということです。
Especially the concubine who is like a female mud
特に雌泥のような側室
when he has no way to touch the outside
外に触れる方法がないとき
What the girl said when she went in
部屋に入ったときに女の子が言ったこと
In fact, it will be influential
実際、影響力はあるだろうね
It's not that there is no such thing in the Southern Dynasties
南朝時代にそのようなことがなかったわけではない
Southern Dynasties also have
南朝時代にも
There is a subtle influence in the Bhikkhuni Biography
比丘尼伝には微妙な影響がある
Appointment of envoy Kim Thu
その後、キム・トゥの使者が任命される
In fact, it later affected the political situation of the Six Dynasties
実際、それは後の六朝の政治状況に影響を与えました。
We don't have time to talk about this anymore
もうこれについて話す時間はありません
but anyway
とにかく
if you are a talented girl
あなたが才能のある女の子なら
or you were born fine
それともあなたは元気に生まれましたか
or you like to read
または読書が好きですか
or you don't want to get married
それとも結婚​​したくないの？
If you do things like the Zhuzonghui and Guangji
中宗会や広済のようなことをすると
During the Northern Dynasties of the Wei and Jin people
魏晋北朝時代
have a very good baked
とても素敵に焼きました
is to become a monk
僧侶になることです
If you don't take you after you become a monk, you may go everywhere for bonuses
僧侶になった後に連れて行ってもらえなければ、ボーナスを求めてどこにでも行くことができます
Because they have to live in a temple
彼らはお寺に住まなければならないからです
Just like the Tang Dynasty, didn't we just talk about it?
唐の時代のように、ただ話したばかりではありませんか？
he can go anywhere
彼はどこにでも行くことができます
So the Empress Dowager Civilization invited him
そこで皇太后文明は彼を招待した
I might ask him to give a speech in Pingcheng
彼に平城でのスピーチを頼んでみようかな
Came to Luoyang after bonus
ボーナス後に洛陽に来ました
Maybe ask him for a bonus
たぶん彼にボーナスを要求するでしょう
So in this case
したがって、この場合には
This bhikkhuni also travels everywhere
この比丘尼はどこまでも旅するために生まれてきた
And you can also recommend your niece
姪にも勧めてください
After entering the palace, it became another
宮殿に入ると、また違った雰囲気になりました
The heroine is a social and political queen mother
ヒロインは社会的・政治的な女王の母である
The relationship between these people is basically like this
この人達の関係は基本的にこんな感じです
Yuan Chunta is here
ユアン・チュンタが来た
He first married Mu Shi
彼は最初にMu Shiと結婚した
later married new lou
その後新しいルーと結婚
news
ニュース
Mu Shi gave birth to a daughter
ムーシーが娘を産んだ
married to yuan
ユアンと結婚
In fact, the surname Yuan
実は袁という姓は
Yuan Chuntuo
袁春佗
you look
あなたは見てください
still the same family
まだ同じ家族
Yuan Weiqing was born
袁偉清誕生
It was later that he died in
彼が亡くなったのはもっと後のことだった
this place in this villa
このヴィラのこの場所
where is the empress dowager of civilization
文明の皇太后はどこですか
it's here
ここにあります
where is empress dowager lin
林太后はどこですか
where is the branch
支店はどこですか
his aunt is here
彼の叔母がここにいます
After Empress Dowager Wenming married Brother Xuanwu
文明皇太后が宣武兄と結婚した後
gave birth to younger brother Xiaomin
生了孝敏弟
Empress Dowager Civilization
皇太后文明
The Empress Dowager of Civilization is also good
文明の太后もいいですね
Empress Dowager Lin is also good
林太后もいいですね
we can say
と言えます
Empress and heroine are
皇后とヒロインは、
The people Chen Dongyuan doesn't want to talk about
陳東源が話したくない人々
Wu Zetian's predecessor
武則天の先代
they are actually very important
それらは実際にはとても重要です
It's all because of the role of mother
それはすべて母親の役割のせいです
gave birth to a good son
良い息子を産んだ
son made emperor
息子が皇帝になった
then he can come
そうすれば彼は来られるよ
social affairs queen
社会問題の女王
So the role of mother
じゃあ母親の役割は
Actually there are many
実はたくさんあるんですよ
as a family
家族として
The Transitional Role of the Ruler
支配者の過渡的な役割
In the past, Chen Dongyuan felt that
陳東元さんはかつて、次のように感じていました。
they are like normal people
彼らは普通の人々と同じです
women don't matter
女性は関係ない
But if we take the heroine
しかし、ヒロインを取り上げると、
It's the empress dowager
皇太后です
When we put it in the family relationship we just talked about in the whole speech
これを、スピーチ全体でお話しした家族関係に置き換えると、
You will find that the heroine is actually a family role
ヒロインが実は家族役だったことがわかる
She's actually one because if it's my father it's the same father's family
彼女は実際に一人です、なぜならそれが私の父親なら、それは同じ父親の家族だからです
As far as family and country are concerned, a country is actually governed by one family.
家族と国に関して言えば、国は実際には一つの家族によって運営されています。
That's what the Emperor's House is in charge of.
天皇家がそれを担当しているのです。
When there is a loophole in the succession order of the emperor
天皇の継承順位に抜け穴がある場合
There are not enough people to inherit. No heir or the inheritance is too small
相続人が足りない、相続人がいない、または相続財産が少なすぎる
when you need help
助けが必要なとき
This mother believes that she is the most trustworthy and will not usurp the throne
この母親は自分が最も信頼できると信じており、王位を奪うことはしない
Of course, before Wu Ze, I never thought about it
もちろん、Wu Ze の前にはそんなこと考えたこともなかった
Somebody's going to literally throw their own son away and usurp her son's tail
誰かが文字通り自分の息子を捨てて、息子の尻尾を横取りするつもりだ
But at least not before
しかし、少なくとも以前は
Therefore, since the Han Dynasty, my mother
したがって、私の母は漢の時代から、
It's always been a time of succession crisis
いつの時代も後継者危機の時代だった
very important a substitute a transition
非常に重要な代替品、移行
The heroine is also in the context of such a family inheritance
ヒロインもそんな家督相続の文脈の中にいます
become a politician
政治家になる
Plus what we are reading now includes Yuan Chuntou
さらに、私たちが今読んでいる内容には、袁春頭も含まれています
I just said that his original surname is Tuo
彼の本姓は佗だと言いました。
There are so-called women's schemes to use Furen
風連を利用したいわゆる女性スキームがある
Just listen to women's schemes, it's rare to fight a war
女性の戦略に耳を傾けてください、戦争をすることはまれです
But how to strategize is to listen to this tradition of women
しかし、戦略を立てるには、この女性の伝統に耳を傾けることです
So before the old men came in to rule
つまり、老人たちが統治してくる前に
When they were in the grassland, there was already a so-called women's country
彼らが草原にいた頃、そこはすでに女性の国だった
It is the history and experience of women as rulers
それは統治者としての女性の歴史と経験です
under this context
この文脈の下で
When the Empress Dowager Civilization came in, she became a very important
皇太后文明が到来すると、彼女は非常に重要な人物になりました。
This is the research of other scholars
これは他の学者の研究です
Put it in this context and share with you
この文脈にそれを入れて、あなたと共有してください
If we know that the Sinicization of Emperor Xiao Wen is the Northern Wei Dynasty of China
蕭文帝の中国化が中国の北魏王朝であることがわかれば
very important word for a development
開発にとって非常に重要な言葉
In fact, there is a very important prerequisite to be able to Sinicize
実際、中国化するには非常に重要な前提条件があります。
It was the reign of the Empress Dowager Civilization before him
それは皇太后の治世でした。
has laid the foundations of the so-called domination of farming nations
農耕民族に対するいわゆる支配の基礎を築いた
a foundation of farming culture
農耕文化の基礎
In the age of the Empress Dowager of Civilization
文明開化太后の時代
He established the Fenglu of the ancestors of the Northern Wei Dynasty.
北魏の祖先である風魯を建立した。
That is to say he is no longer feudal
つまり彼はもはや封建的ではないということだ
Not that I'm a monarch or that I'm a noble leader
私が君主であるとか、高貴な指導者であるということではありません
The following are my men
以下は私の部下です
Then I will eat this piece of grass
じゃあこの草を食べるよ
Instead, it becomes a centralized ruling monarch.
その代わりに、中央集権的な統治君主となる。
Let's manage my bureaucrats by paying salaries
給料を払って官僚を管理しましょう
This was established during the time of the Empress Dowager Civilization
これは皇太后文明の時代に確立されました。
Sanchangzhi
三長志
The so-called administrative bureaucrats at different levels at the local level
地方レベルのさまざまなレベルのいわゆる行政官僚
It was also established during the time of the Empress Dowager Civilization
皇太后文明の時代にも設立されました
The other one is the so-called Kimita Osamu
もう一人はいわゆる君田治です。
everyone knows this
誰もがこれを知っています
make everyone sweeter
みんなをもっと優しくする
Then the sweet tax is paid to the central government
そして甘い税金が中央政府に支払われる
After all is paid to the central
すべて中央に支払われます
Then I pay the officers
それから私は役員に支払います
Under this monarch-subject relationship
この君主と大臣の関係のもとで
It turns out that feudal lords had their own soldiers and horses
封建領主は独自の兵と馬を持っていたことが判明
Then do not listen to the phenomenon of central government
それなら中央政府の現象に耳を傾けないでください
will gradually become less
徐々に少なくなっていきます
So the Empress Dowager Civilization passed through his
したがって、皇太后の文明は彼の時代を通過しました。
in his social age
彼の社会年齢では
these political reforms
こういった政治改革は
institutional reform
制度改革
Emperor Xiaowen
孝文帝
Have the opportunity to do so-called Chinese
いわゆる中国語をする機会がある
That is to say, wearing Han Chinese clothes
つまり漢民族の服を着ているということです。
Learn the language of Chinese Han people
中国の漢民族の言語を学ぶ
Or change it from Tuoba to Yuan, etc.
または拓跋から元などに変更します。
Empress Dowager of Civilization
文明の皇太后
Another heroine is the so-called
もう一人のヒロインはいわゆる
Queen Mother Lin is actually a typical
リン王太后は実際には典型的な人物です
Use the role of mother to set up witness
証人を立てるために母親の役割を利用する
or a person who takes power
または権力を握る人
Because in the Northern Wei Dynasty
北魏の時代だから
I'm afraid that the Queen Mother will set up a witness and rob power.
ただ、皇太后が証拠を整えて権力を奪うのではないかと心配です。
So once a certain prince is established
それで、ある王子が確立されると、
will kill this mother
この母親を殺すだろう
lest in the future this mother will take this child
将来この母親がこの子を引き取ることのないように
After the son becomes the emperor, he will take charge of the affairs
息子が皇帝になった後は政務を担当することになる
Early Northern Wei Dynasty
北魏初期
There has always been such a tradition
昔からそういう伝統があったんだね
Then Empress Dowager Lin's husband Xuanwu Emperor
そして林太后の夫、宣武帝。
never had an heir
後継者がいなかった
Because the harem is very afraid of children
ハーレムは子供をとても怖がるので、
In case I have a son
息子がいる場合
i might be killed
殺されるかもしれない
so the harem prays to each other
それでハーレムはお互いに祈ります
or ask
または尋ねてください
when were you pregnant
いつ妊娠しましたか
when did i conceive
私はいつ妊娠しましたか
if i found out i was pregnant a little earlier than you
もし私があなたよりもう少し早く妊娠に気づいていたら
then watch this
それからこれを見てください
This is related to the medical book I just talked about
これは先ほど話した医学書に関連しています
Because traditional medical texts believe that
なぜなら、伝統的な医学書は次のように信じているからです。
If you are three months pregnant
妊娠3ヶ月の場合
calling you from behind
後ろからあなたを呼んでいます
real
本物
if you turn to the right
右に曲がると
it will be a girl
それは女の子になります
if you turn your head to the left
左に曲がると
it will be a boy
男の子になります
Why male left female right
なぜ男性が左、女性が右なのか
there are various
いろいろあります
So I discussed with you again that you got pregnant last month
それで先月妊娠したことをもう一度話しました
I just got pregnant this month
今月妊娠したばかりです
As a result, when I call you, turn around
その結果、私があなたを呼ぶとき、振り向いてください
he will be male
彼は男性になります
then i can continue to conceive
そうすれば妊娠を続けることができます
So if I say I'm pregnant this month
それで、私が今月妊娠していると言ったら
I got pregnant earlier than him
私は彼より早く妊娠しました
Then I call me back
それからまた電話します
i will have a boy
私は男の子を産みます
I will open
開けます
i want to be later than you
私はあなたより遅くなりたいです
or if i turn around
あるいは振り向いたら
i will give birth to girls
私は女の子を産みます
It does not matter
それはどうでもいい事です
I will continue to conceive
これからも妊娠していきます
Because my child will not experience the crown prince
うちの子は皇太子を経験しないから
i won't be killed
私は殺されません
So the harem of the Northern Wei Dynasty
つまり北魏のハーレム
When such stories are spread like this
こういった話が広まると
Queen Mother Lin said that in the middle of the night
リン王太后は夜中にこう言いました。
pray that i would rather die
むしろ死んだほうがいいと祈ってください
I also hope to help my husband pass on the family line and receive
私も夫が家系を継承し、受け取ることができるよう手助けしたいと思っています。
you see how important it is
それがいかに重要かわかりますか
understand
理解
a solid woman
しっかりした女性
She prayed silently alone in the middle of the night
彼女は真夜中に一人で静かに祈った
I don't know why this word comes out
なぜこの言葉が出てくるのか分かりません
Of course she came out by herself
もちろん彼女は一人で出てきました
let everyone know she prays in the middle of the night
彼女が真夜中に祈っていることをみんなに知らせてください
I don't want to be like other concubines
他の側室のようになりたくない
I am not afraid of death
私は死を恐れていません
I would rather have a son
むしろ息子が欲しい
so that my husband can pass on
夫が世を継げるように
I also want to be able
私もできるようになりたいです
I would also like
私も欲しいです
she looks like this
彼女はこんな感じです
that aspect
その側面
According to the biography of Empress Dowager Lin
林太后の伝記によると
She is full of talents
彼女は才能に満ちています
Why does he have a little understanding of the Buddhist scriptures?
なぜ彼は仏典をあまり理解していないのでしょうか？
Because his aunt is a nun
彼の叔母は修道女なので
bonus nun
比丘尼のボーナス
And his martial arts are also very powerful
そして彼の武術も非常に強力です
He once called a group of ministers to shoot arrows together
彼はかつて大臣のグループを呼んで一緒に矢を射ろうとしたことがある
everyone shoots well
みんな上手に撃てます
Then he shoots a real hole
それから彼は本物の穴を撃ちます
set over there
そこに設置
One shot hits the real hole
一発で本当の穴に当たる
So all the ministers assisted him
それで大臣全員が彼を助けた
So the heroine is not just relying on
だからヒロインはただ頼るだけではない
Affiliation with groups or politics
団体や政治との関わり
In Beihui, these heroines all had their own talents
北匯では、これらのヒロインは皆、独自の才能を持っていました
We just talked about the political strategy of the Empress Dowager Civilization
先ほど、皇太后文明の政治戦略についてお話しました。
You can see his establishment of this system
彼のこのシステムの確立がわかります
Later Sinicization of Facts
その後の事実の中国化
Very important foundation for success
成功のための非常に重要な基盤
Empress Dowager Lin has such martial arts
林太后にはそのような武術があります
Then we can engage in mother-child kindness politics
そうすれば母子に優しい政治ができる
So then on the other hand
それで、一方で
The history books say that he personally writes the handwriting of Wanji
歴史書には万吉の筆跡を自ら書いたと記されている。
He's actually the one who judges.
実は彼は裁判官なのです
I won't talk about the details today
今日は詳細については話しません
Another little book called The Words of the Princess
『プリンセスの言葉』という別の小さな本
Just the one introduced by Mr. Wu Xianwu
呉仙呉氏が紹介したものだけ
It's just talking about how he judged the case
それは彼がその事件をどのように判断したかについて話しているだけです
Of course, at the end of the sentence, he was partial to girls.
もちろん、文の最後には、彼は女の子に好意的でした。
this is nonsense
これはナンセンスです
Well, he's not alone anyway.
まあ、とにかく彼は一人ではありません。
What's the meaning
どのような意味です
don't rule alone
一人で統治しないでください
There are supporters next to him
隣にはサポーターがいる
These supporters, apart from the ministers who admire him,
これらの支持者たちは、彼を賞賛する閣僚は別として、
or afraid of him
あるいは彼が怖い
In fact he has female staff
実は女性スタッフもいる
Our subsequent research found
その後の調査で判明したのは、
Actually he has some princesses
実は彼には何人かのプリンセスがいる
He has a good relationship with the princess
彼はお姫様と良い関係を築いている
This is appeasement
これは宥和策だ
what is this called
これは何と呼ばれていますか
Good relationship between walk away
ウォークアウェイとの良好な関係
He has a good relationship with the princess
彼はお姫様と良い関係を築いている
He used the princess as a lady in a letter
彼はお姫様を女官の手紙として使った
to help him with the paperwork
彼の書類手続きを手伝うために
help him pass the message
彼がメッセージを伝えるのを手伝ってください
Discuss things with him
彼といろいろ話し合う
Do you guys think this is weird?
皆さん、これは変だと思いますか？
It's not surprising at all
まったく驚くべきことではない
if you go back and see
戻って見たら
Ban Zhao who wrote this female world
この女性の世界を書いた潘昭
In fact, when he was in Donghan
実は彼が東漢にいた時、
It's the staff of Empress Dowager He Xideng
何熙登皇太后の杖です
the same
同じ
He Xi but Empress Dowager Deng is in power
何熙、しかし鄧太后が権力を握っている
while in power
権力を握っている間
when being a hostess
ホステスをしているとき
have all kinds of problems
あらゆる種類の問題を抱えている
He will discuss it with Ban Zhao
彼は潘昭とそれについて話し合うつもりだ
Ban Zhao suggested to him
潘昭は彼にこう提案した。
Because Ban Zhao came from
潘昭は出身だから
big family
大家族
who wrote this Hanshu
この漢書を書いたのは誰ですか
he knows many things
彼はたくさんのことを知っています
just discuss with him
彼と話し合ってください
So the heroine is never alone
だからヒロインは決して一人ではない
But of course he depends on
しかし、もちろん彼は依存しています
he's the mother thing
彼は母親そのものだ
climb up step by step
一歩一歩登っていく
get this
これを取れ
dominant position
支配的な地位
But he needs to be able to rule
しかし彼は統治できる必要がある
It's definitely not just cruel and easy to kill
それは決して残酷で簡単に殺すだけではありません
or wait wait
それとも待て待て
None of that kind came later
そのようなものは後から来ませんでした
The so-called fox girl can be the culprit
いわゆるキツネ娘が犯人の可能性もある
in this slanderous language
この中傷的な言葉で
so you can get the truth
そうすれば真実を知ることができます
In fact, these heroines have staff beside them
実はこのヒロイン達の傍には杖がいるのです
There are people who help her
彼女を助けてくれる人がいる
It's hard not to say
言わないのは難しい
Female staff actually have
女性スタッフが実際に持っている
And the staff of Queen Mother Lin
そしてリン王妃のスタッフたち
Many of them came from the princess
それらの多くは王女からのものでした
then this is an interesting place
それならここは面白い場所だよ
In fact, this research of the princess
実はこのプリンセスの研究は、
We used to study women's political history
私たちは女性の政治史を研究していました
They are all research heroines
全員研究ヒロインです
They are all studying the female emperor, social and political empress dowager
彼らは皆、女性天皇、社会的、政治的な皇太后について研究しています。
Few people study the princess
王女を研究する人はほとんどいません
i have a student
私には生徒がいます
He thinks I wrote Death of a Princess
彼は私が『王女の死』を書いたと思っている
he is not convinced
彼は納得していない
he thought he was going to write about the living princess
彼は生きている王女について書こうと思った
what good things did you do
あなたはどんな良いことをしましたか
He wrote a book called
彼はという本を書きました
Princess politics without the Southern and Northern Dynasties
南北朝のない王女政治
The result is well written
結果はちゃんと書いてあるよ
In fact, these princesses who have not lived in the Northern and Southern Dynasties
実はこの王女たちは南北朝時代には生きていないのです。
It's not that you can't get involved in politics at all.
全く政治に参加できないわけではありません。
And when they get involved in politics
そして彼らが政治に関与すると、
all successful
すべて成功しました
The reason is that they use the so-called
その理由は、いわゆる
Physical Discourse on Liquid and Air
液体と気体の物体についての議論
It is absolutely impossible for a princess to become an emperor
皇女が皇帝になるのは絶対に無理
Except that the 50% daughter wants to become the emperor
50％の娘が皇帝になりたいということ以外は
No other princess has the courage to become emperor
他の王女には皇帝になりたいという勇気がなかった
no idea
そんな発想すらない
But what about them and their emperor brothers
しかし、彼らと彼らの皇帝の兄弟はどうなるでしょうか？
between us
私たちの間
It can be said with this body discourse of so-called liquid with air
いわゆる液体と空気のこの身体的言説で言えること
The princess also cares about the country
王女も国のことを思っている
so the princess has her own
だからお姫様は自分のものを持っています
untouched beauty princess
手付かずの美姫
has his own house, has his own residence
自分の家がある、自分の住居がある
Of course, father horses are miserable.
もちろん父馬は可哀想だ。
In some books of that time
当時のいくつかの本には
In that file it will be written
そのファイルには次のように書かれます
Father and horse are afraid to go home
両親は家に帰るのが怖い
Because the princess, that's his princess' home
だってプリンセス、そこが彼のプリンセスの家だから
The father horse seems to have been married instead
父馬は代わりに結婚したようだ
The princess sometimes calls him
王女は時々彼に電話します
tell him to come tell him to go tell him to go
彼に来るように言ってください、彼に行くように言ってください、彼に行くように言ってください
He doesn't seem to be his family
彼は家族ではないようです
So, the princess is the head of the family.
つまり、王女は家族の長です。
that from a negative point of view
それはネガティブな観点から見ると
father horse is in pain
父馬は苦しんでいます
But because the princess has her own home
でもお姫様には自分の家があるから
And the housework, the student
そして家事、学生
I made this location map of the residence of this princess
この王女の邸宅の位置図を作りました
In fact, it's just a little bit outside the imperial city.
実際、ここは帝都から少し離れたところにあります。
Therefore, the residence of the princess is often the so-called
したがって、王女の住居はしばしばいわゆる
soft politics
軟性政治
To kill a dragon is to kill a dragon, not to kill a dragon politically to kill a dragon
ドラゴンを殺すことはドラゴンを殺すことであって、ドラゴンを殺すために政治的にドラゴンを殺すことではない
where soft politics are enforced
ソフトな政治が施行される場所
That is to say, when the monarch and his kings or ministers
つまり、君主とその王や大臣が、
Fry and tear face in the palace
宮殿で顔を揚げて引き裂く
There's no way to pull down my face anymore, there's no way to deal with it
もう私の顔を引き下げる方法はありません、それに対処する方法はありません
a case can't be solved
事件が解決できない
or someone is going to be killed
さもなければ誰かが殺されるだろう
At this time, the princess will have a waist inkstone
この時、姫は腰硯を持ちます。
Waist they come to eat at home
腰 彼らは家に食べに来ます
This time it is his brother who is the king
今度は彼の弟が王です
sometimes even his brother
時には彼の兄弟さえも
Then he will act like a sister
そうしたら彼は妹のように振る舞うでしょう
sometimes his brother
時々彼の兄弟
Sometimes he'll use the phrase that we're all the same parents.
時々、彼は「私たちは皆同じ親だ」というフレーズを使います。
born of this soft gesture
この柔らかなジェスチャーから生まれました
to intercede
とりなす
then come to lobby
それからロビーに来てください
and then to solve some
そしていくつかを解決するために
Seems like it can't be returned
返品不可のようです
But in the end it was transferred to Princess Juli
でも最終的にはジュリ姫に譲渡されました
something like this
このようなもの
So after doing this
それでこれをやった後
we discover
私たちは発見します
women's politics
以前女性政治
We all feel like we're going to be queen mothers
私たちは皆、自分たちが女王の母になるような気がしています
Only female emperors and heroines can study
女性皇帝とヒロインだけが勉強できる
Actually no
実は違う
Princess politics can actually be studied
プリンセスの政治を実際に勉強できる
That means the identity of the daughter
それは娘の正体を意味する
the same person
同じ人
In fact, it is worth studying
実際、勉強する価値はある
Another student recently wrote an article
別の学生が最近記事を書きました
that is a college student
それは大学生です
I really admire him and work hard
私は彼を本当に尊敬しており、一生懸命働いています
And smart, I think female students in Taiwan
そして賢い、台湾の女子学生だと思います
They're all smart, beautiful, and hardworking
彼らは皆賢くて美しくて勤勉です
It makes people happy when they see it, the more they interact, the happier they are
見る人は幸せになり、交流すればするほど幸せになります。
This female student just wrote an article
この女子学生はたった今記事を書きました
write what? write
何を書く？書く
The tomb of Li Jingxun was excavated in 1957
李景勲の墓は1957年に発掘された
Since it was excavated
発掘されてから
because it has so many beautiful things in it
素敵なものがたくさん入っているから
So there have always been archaeologists or historians
考古学者や歴史家は常に存在していました
In fact, few historians
実際、歴史家はほとんどいない
Archaeologists do more than scholars of cultural relics and archaeology
考古学者は文化遺物や考古学の学者以上のことをします
because it's these things
これらのことだから
Li Jingxun is with the generation
李京勲は世代とともにあります
Sui Dai, his surname is Li
隨代,他姓李
But his grandmother is the daughter of Emperor Suiwen
しかし、彼の祖母は綏文帝の娘です。
Yang Lihua
楊麗華
His father's surname is Li, of course
彼の父親の姓はもちろん李です
Otherwise call me Li Jingxun
それ以外の場合は、リー・ジンシュンと呼んでください
His mother is the Yang family
母親は楊家。
He came down with Emperor Wen's family.
彼は文帝の家族とともにやって来た。
So there are so many beautiful things in his tomb
彼の墓にはとても美しいものがたくさんあります
Scholars of the past, after this tomb was dug up in 1957
1957 年にこの墓が掘り起こされてからの過去の学者たち
there have always been scholars
いつの時代にも学者はいた
From the shape of these cups
このカップの形からして
The bath food of the necklace
ネックレスのバスフード
or shape
または形
to study
勉強する
For example, these arts and crafts that come with the class
たとえば、授業で持ち寄られたこんな美術品や工芸品。
Is it influenced by the West, including Persia?
ペルシャなど西洋の影響を受けているのでしょうか？
all kinds of these
これらすべての種類
where did these things come from
これらのものはどこから来たのですか
Is it made in China itself?
それ自体は中国製ですか？
Or was it sent by someone else?
それとも他の人から送られてきたのでしょうか？
buried as a gift
贈り物として埋葬された
Look at how old this girl died
この女の子が何歳で亡くなったか見てください
died at nine
9時に亡くなった
A nine-year-old girl came out with a lot of
9歳の女の子がたくさん持ってきました。
amazingly beautiful thing
驚くほど美しいもの
Of course it will arouse the interest of many scholars.
もちろん、多くの学者の興味を引くだろう。
fifty years of research
50年の研究
is studying each of these utensils
これらの道具をそれぞれ研究しています
Cultural traceability Art form and so on and so on and so on
文化のトレーサビリティ、芸術的形式などなど
Until recently because of gender
最近まで性別のせいで
realized
気がついた
Why are these nine year old girls
なぜこの9歳の女の子たちは
worthy of so many amazing things
たくさんの素晴らしいことに値する
Let's go back and find out
戻って調べてみましょう
His grandmother is Yang Lihua
彼の祖母は楊麗華です。
Who is Yang Lihua's father
楊麗華の父親は誰ですか
Emperor of Hydrology
水文学の皇帝
Why did the daughter of Emperor Water Wen
なぜ皇帝ウォーターウェンの娘は
so important
ものすごく大事
In fact, Emperor Shuiwen took his daughter Yang Lihua
実際、水文帝は娘の楊麗華を連れて行きました。
Married to the last emperor of the Northern Zhou Dynasty
北周王朝最後の皇帝と結婚
Then put the North Zhou
次に北周を置きます
Give the state a string
状態に文字列を与える
so understand what
それで何を理解するか
So Yang Lihua is very painful to her father
だから楊麗華さんは父親にとってとても辛いことだ
just embarrassing
ただ恥ずかしいだけ
An awkward and painful relationship with a woman
女性とのぎこちなくて苦しい関係
Yang Lihua is actually a princess
楊麗華は実は王女だった
but she wasn't a princess when she married
でも結婚したとき彼女はプリンセスではなかった
she is queen
彼女は女王です
she was married to be queen
彼女は女王になるために結婚した
But after marrying the queen
しかし、女王と結婚した後、
Her own father took her husband's
彼女自身の父親が夫のものを奪った
Stringed by the state
国家の監視下にある
Then she becomes a weed
そうしたら彼女は雑草になる
like a princess
プリンセスみたいに
She's not in the mood for a princess
彼女はお姫様の気分ではない
Because she's actually the father of the kingdom
だって彼女は実は王国の父だから
her mood is kingdom father
彼女の気分は王国の父です
She loves her granddaughter very much
彼女は孫娘をとても愛しています
This is Li Jingxun
リー・ジンシュンです
take her with you
彼女を連れて行ってください
when her granddaughter is dying
彼女の孫娘が亡くなったとき
she died at the age of nine
彼女は9歳で亡くなりました
In fact, everything in it
実際、その中にあるものはすべて
It is likely that they are all collected by Yang Lihua
おそらく全部楊麗華が集めたものだと思われる
Not necessarily the collection of nine-year-old Li Jingxun
必ずしも9歳のリー・ジンシュン君のコレクションではない
And that wooden or those wooden cups
そしてあの木製の、あるいはあの木製のカップ
or those recorded in
またはに記録されているもの
source
ソース
The main numbers are from the Northern Zhou Dynasty
主な数字は北周時代のもの
Then talk about how the Li family
次に、李家の様子について話します。
I don't want to say that he is Yang Lihua and the daughter of Emperor Shuiwen.
彼が楊麗華であり、水文帝の娘であるとは言いたくありません。
you can see it from here
ここから見ることができます
If you understand the barrier in terms of gender
ジェンダーの壁を理解していれば
To understand this barrier from a daughter's point of view
娘の視点からこの壁を理解する
It’s not just about cultural exchanges, artworks, public welfare or things.
それは文化交流や芸術作品、公共の福祉などだけではありません。
what touches this topic
この話題に触れるもの
In fact, it also includes the mood of a daughter
実は娘の気分も含まれています
Use her granddaughter to express herself
孫娘を使って自分自身を表現する
An attitude towards her addition and addition
彼女の追加と追加に対する態度
So it's interesting that the study is the latest one
この研究が最新のものであることは興味深いことです
We haven't done enough research on daughters.
私たちは娘たちについて十分な調査を行っていません。
There are many things worth studying
勉強する価値のあることがたくさんあります
in other words
言い換えると
The last name of Yuan Cuntuo
原存坨的最後名的最後
Painted crouching blue bowl
ペイントされた青いしゃがむボウル
Although it's all in the past
すべては過去のことなのに
But it can inspire us
しかし、それは私たちにインスピレーションを与えることができます
In fact, it's been a long way
実際、長い道のりでした
This division is not over yet
この分裂はまだ終わっていない
still going on
まだ続いている
We got some inspiration from Yuan Cuntuo's life
袁存多の人生からインスピレーションを得ました
History also learns from gender
歴史はジェンダーからも学ぶ
And in the process we found
そしてその過程で私たちが見つけたのは、
people of different classes different ethnic groups
さまざまな階級の人々 さまざまな民族グループ
For example, ancestors of different classes
たとえば、異なるクラスの祖先
For example, something like Yuan Cun Tuo
たとえば、袁存佗のようなもの。
banned like this
このように禁止されています
Or what we just said to help people produce
あるいは、人々が生産するのを助けるために私たちが今言ったこと
This different class of midwives and stable women
この異なるクラスの助産師と安定した女性
In fact there is age and backup
実際には年齢とバックアップがあります
will lead us to some of the past
私たちを過去の一部に導いてくれるでしょう
New perspectives on subjects taken for granted
当たり前のことと思われている事柄に対する新しい視点
So if we can combine the empress with the heroine
それで皇后とヒロインを組み合わせられたら
When put into context to understand
理解するために文脈に当てはめると
In fact, there is no need to be so repulsive
実はそこまで嫌悪感を抱く必要はないのです
That is actually like
それは実際には次のようなものです
The Story of Huiming Empress Dowager
恵明皇太后の物語
Empress Dowager Lin's Story
林太后の物語
including Wu Zetian
武則天も含めて
Or Yang Lihua and his granddaughter
あるいは楊麗華とその孫娘
these stories
これらの物語
Stories from the royal family
王室からの物語
In fact, I put it in the vein
実は静脈に入れたんです
in the vein of the family
家族の血脈の中で
in the context of political operations
政治活動の文脈で
or in the context of empire building
または帝国建設の文脈において
In fact, there are many things to talk about
実は、話したいことがたくさんあるのですが、
and see something new
そして何か新しいものを見る
Not necessarily with ordinary people
必ずしも一般人とは限らない
Women's life in general doesn't matter
一般的に女性の人生は重要ではありません
may still be related
まだ関係があるかもしれない
that apart from gender
それは性別とは別に
I just said class and ethnicity
私は階級と民族性を言っただけです
we've always been like this
私たちはいつもこうだった
I think this should refer to each other
これはお互いを参照すべきだと思います
studied the 1986 scholar proposed
1986年の学者の提案を研究した
It has been more than 30 years since I did this from a gender perspective
ジェンダーの観点からこの取り組みを始めてから 30 年以上が経ちました
After 30 years, in fact, we also found that as we just said
実際、30 年後、先ほども述べたように、次のようなことが分かりました。
Class and ethnicity other than gender
性別以外の階級と民族
In addition, age and backup in Chinese history
また、中国の歴史における年齢とバックアップ
is often well worth digging up
多くの場合、掘り出す価値があります
So let’s continue to do it. Now some scholars have proposed the so-called multiple intertwined historical research.
さて、一部の学者は、いわゆる複数の絡み合った歴史研究を提案しています。
In fact, historical research is inherently diverse and intertwined, and it is impossible to talk about it from only one angle.
実際、歴史研究は本質的に多様かつ複雑に絡み合っており、単一の角度からのみ語ることは不可能です。
Today I'm just starting with a gender perspective
今日はジェンダーの観点から始めます
Then use the round-lipped camel as an example
次に、丸い唇のラクダを例として使用します。
I hope to share with you what we have done in the past 30 years
私たちが過去 30 年間に何をしてきたかを皆さんと共有できればと思っています
What is the outcome of historical research on gender studies?
ジェンダー研究の歴史的研究の成果は何ですか?
Then also as a congratulatory gift to celebrate the 90th anniversary of the Academia Sinica and the Eleventh Institute
また、中央研究院と第11研究所の創立90周年を祝うお祝いの品としても贈られました。
hope to
願う
Let everyone be able to hear and be happy
みんなが聴いて幸せになれますように
History is basically a broken mirror and everything is actually broken
歴史は基本的に壊れた鏡であり、実際にはすべてが壊れています
We are fighting together
私たちは一緒に戦っています
Let's see if we can spell it out
それを詳しく説明できるかどうか見てみましょう
Sometimes it can look like a mess of refracted reflections
場合によっては、乱反射したように見えることもあります
But it still looks a little bit
でもまだ少し見える
The same is true for the study of gender or women's history
ジェンダーや女性の歴史の研究にも同じことが当てはまります
thank you for listening
ご聴取ありがとうございました
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you very much Mr. Li for your wonderful speech today
李さん、今日は素晴らしいスピーチをしていただき、本当にありがとうございました
That's because we have limited time now
今は時間が限られているからです
Teacher Li just mentioned that
リー先生が先ほどおっしゃいました
This year is actually the 90th anniversary of Academia Sinica
実は今年は中央研究院創立90周年です
So we will prepare a
そこで、
A special coaster for the 90th anniversary of Academia Sinica
中央研究院90周年記念特製コースター
Wait a minute and open up to friends who have problems
少し待って、問題を抱えている友達に心を開いてください
that's because of time
それは時間のせいだ
We might just open up and ask three questions today, okay?
今日は心を開いて 3 つの質問をしてみませんか?
ok first
はい、まずは
hey ask the professor
ねえ、教授に聞いてください
the one you just mentioned
あなたが今言ったもの
There are six kinds of women
女性には6種類ある
ask that toothmaid
あの侍女に聞いてください
what with that ex-wife
あの元妻はどうしたの
do something
何かをする
Thanks
ありがとう
intermediary
仲介者
A broker is a middleman
ブローカーは仲介者です
The kind that sells as an intermediary
仲介販売するタイプ
According to the ex-wife
元妻の言葉が踊るという
Actually it's kind of like
実はそれは似たようなものです
wife
妻
The old castle, he said it was the old castle
古い城、彼はそれが古い城だと言った
That means they are all that
つまり、それらはすべてです
Wang Kilometer's
王キロメートルさん
no no no no
いやいやいやいや
Three aunts and six wives are not kings
3人の叔母と6人の妻は王ではない
If we want to say three aunts and six wives, we should say she is a professional woman.
3 人の叔母と 6 人の妻と言いたい場合は、彼女はプロフェッショナルな女性であると言うべきです。
It may be said that it is an ancient professional woman
古代のプロフェッショナルウーマンと言えるでしょう
However, the third aunt and the sixth wife
しかし、三番目の叔母と六番目の妻は
Fighting together is to make these nine kinds of people
共に戦うというのはこの9種類の人間を作ることだ
Get together and talk about them like this
集まってこうやって話しましょう
They are three aunts and six wives. This is after the Yuan Dynasty.
彼らは3人の叔母と6人の妻で、これは元の時代以降のことです。
in the age of what we do
私たちがやっていることの時代に
I have sent every water hall
あらゆる水場を送りました
Basically these people are normal working women
基本的にこの人たちは普通に働いている女性です
But when someone thinks these women
しかし、誰かがこれらの女性たちのことを考えるとき、
Ordinary women from good families should not talk to these outsiders
良家の出身の普通の女性は、このような部外者と話すべきではありません
when women walking around are together
歩いている女性が一緒にいるとき
From Yuan Dynasty to Ming Dynasty
元の時代から明の時代へ
start like a scholar
学者のように始める
put some working women outside
働く女性を外に出す
become a group
グループになる
call it three aunts and six wives
3人の叔母と6人の妻と呼んでください
Then he said that women from good families had better not follow
それから彼は、良家の出身の女性は従わないほうがよいと言いました。
Three aunts and six wives together
3人の叔母と6人の妻が一緒に
But in fact it is impossible
でも実際には無理だよ
Because our case in the Ming and Qing Dynasties is also good
明清時代の私たちのケースも良いからです
or
また
note novel or art inside
小説やアートをメモしてください
still see like this
まだこのように見えます
Mrs. Wen will still go into the house
ウェン夫人はまだ家に入ります
help give birth
出産を手伝う
Grandma will still help the broker to do business
おばあちゃんは今後もブローカーの取引を手伝うだろう
Matchmaker is still needed
仲人はまだ必要です
possible today
今日は可能です
probably not today
おそらく今日ではないでしょう
at least when i was a kid
少なくとも私が子供の頃は
It seems that they are still needed
まだまだ必要とされているようです
so this is
それでこれは
It's just that Rusheng doesn't like this kind of women outside
ただ、ルシェンは外にいるこの種の女性が好きではありません
This is the division between male and female
これが男性と女性の分かれ目です
more and more
だんだん
After the room between men and women became more and more strict
男女の壁が厳しくなってから
just some people who work outside
外で働く一部の人たちだけ
female becomes a
女性がなる
anonymous group
匿名グループ
But in fact they are
しかし実際には彼らは
Women who work outside are like this
外で働く女性はこんな感じ
that mistress is
その愛人は
The so-called Ning just mentioned that
いわゆるニンが先ほど言った
to be the family dancers
ファミリーダンサーになるために
I'm sorry
ごめんなさい
dancing witch
踊る魔女
What is dancing witch
ダンシングウィッチとは
dancing witch is
踊る魔女は
go block
ブロックに行く
Find a way to summon the soul, what, what?
魂を呼び出す方法を考えて、何、何？
kind of religious
一種の宗教的な
this is possible
これは可能です
It means that we boys serve wine and leave wine behind
それは、私たち少年がワインを出し、ワインを残すことを意味します
Those three aunts and six women stink
あの三人の叔母と六人の女性は臭い
just had nine
ちょうど9つあった
It means to drink and stay
飲んで泊まるという意味です
This master feels here
このマスターはここを感じます
ok thank you thank you
わかりました、ありがとう、ありがとう
There is a picture of Beizhong military uniform you just mentioned
先ほどおっしゃった北中の軍服の写真があります
You said he himself had guarded his father for thirteen years
あなたは、彼自身が父親を13年間守ってきたと言いました
But I see his eldest son in the picture below is also three years old
しかし、下の写真の長男も3歳です。
what happened
どうしたの
That's why the patrilineal family is so important
だからこそ父系家族が重要なのです
Dad is the eldest son
お父さんは長男です
Because if the eldest son lives in the future,
だって、将来長男が生きていたら、
should i die
死んだほうがいいでしょうか
he wants to inherit me
彼は私を受け継ぎたいと思っています
is the main axis of this paternal family is on him
この父方の家族の軸は彼にあります
In the end he died before me
結局彼は私より先に亡くなりました
So I'm not for the love of children
だから私は子供たちの愛には向いていない
I do it to honor the patrilineal lineage.
父系を尊重するためにそうしているのです。
So I have also been rotten for him for three years
だから私も彼のために3年間腐っていました
also the worst injury
最悪の怪我でもある
so this father
それでこの父親は
That's why it's called the patrilineal family system
それが父系家族制度と呼ばれる理由です
Paternal haircut, paternal why is it called paternal paternal
父性の髪型、父性 なぜそれが父性、父性と呼ばれるのですか
Dad is the core
お父さんが中心です
Everyone revolves around this man who is a father
誰もがこの父親を中心に回っている
To regulate or regulate the relationship between relatives and inferiors
親族と目下の関係を規制したり規制したりすること
A child with his mother
母親と一緒の子供
not because you gave birth to me
あなたが私を産んだからではない
I'm the closest relationship with you
私はあなたの一番近くにいます
It depends on your relationship with my father
それはお父さんとの関係次第です
You and my father are the wife's relationship
あなたと私の父は妻の関係です
you are my aunt
あなたは私の叔母です
After you passed away, I just played for your husband for three years
あなたが亡くなった後、私はあなたの夫のために3年間プレーしただけです
you gave birth to me
あなたは私を産んだ
But your relationship with my dad is just bad
でもお父さんとの関係は最悪です
my dad's concubine
私の父の妾
If you die, there's nothing you can do
死んだら何もできない
I have fewer husbands
夫の数が少なくなった
Because all our relationships revolve around Dad
私たちの関係はすべてお父さんを中心に展開しているからです
This so-called traditional Chinese patrilineal family society means
このいわゆる伝統的な中国の父系家族社会は、
Okay, let me recall what you just said
さて、あなたが今言ったことを思い出させてください
That production that vertical production
その生産、その垂直生産
I traveled to Argentina last year
去年アルゼンチンに旅行しました
their aboriginal local aborigines
彼らの地元の先住民
The localization of their production is on the wall
生産のローカライズは困難に直面しています
on their original wall
元の壁に
vertical production
垂直生産
that knowledge
その知識
and when he gave birth
そして彼が出産したとき
His arms are still on that wall
彼の腕はまだその壁にあります
Said that there was that cruel hand on the wall
壁にはあの残酷な手があったと言った
plug it in like this
このように差し込みます
just like this
ちょうどこのような
then your side
それからあなたの側
Because you're all in Europe and look like that
だって君たちはヨーロッパにいてあんな風に見えるから
But that's from Argentina
でもそれはアルゼンチン産
I echo your matter
あなたの件に共感します
OK
OK
Ask our colleagues who have done archaeological and anthropological surveys
考古学および人類学の調査を行った同僚に尋ねてください。
I said you stepped on the Amis
あなたはアミ族を踏んだと言った
How about it
どうでしょうか
He said I went and when I came back he told me
彼は私が行ったと言いました、そして私が戻ってきたとき彼は私に言いました
I asked and my interviewer said
私が尋ねると、インタビュアーはこう言いました
Yes, yes, I squat down and get down
はい、はい、しゃがんで降ります
So actually by the end of the twenty-four seasons
だから実際には二十四節気の終わりまでに
Taiwan is still like this
台湾はまだこんな感じ
So the one who was lying in the hospital gave birth
それで、病院に横たわっていた人が出産しました
Then let the doctor do this
じゃあ医者にやってもらいましょう
All are medical
全て医療用です
very late quiet on human power
とても遅くまで人力で静かに
very short period of time
非常短的一段時間
Now actually because
さて、実際のところ、なぜなら
The relationship between the industry and the city movement
産業と都市の動きの関係
Or a home birth, or a gentle birth
それとも自宅出産か、穏やかな出産か
Various sports appear
各種運動出現
So actually a while ago this topic
で、実は少し前にこの話題が
The group I'm currently in tender production with
私が現在入札制作に参加しているグループ
Told once, all the midwives
すべての助産師に一度言ってください
Everyone came to me
みんなが私のところに来ました
Come and take a photo with me holding the cup
カップを持って写真を撮りに来てください
I am also very happy
私もとても嬉しいです
So now it's back again
それで今、実際にまた戻ってきました
Hope to take this living person as the main body
この生きている人を本体にしてほしい
See how comfortable he is and how easy he is to move around
彼がどれだけ快適で、どれだけ動きやすいかを見てください。
Instead of this one that is mainly based on the convenience of doctors
医師の都合を主としたこれではなく
In fact, it is revival
実は復活です
ask the teacher
先生に尋ねる
teacher
教師
The last word is Broken Mirror Temporary
最後の言葉は Broken Mirror Temporary
remind me to say
言うことを思い出させて
Teachers can use this pedal
教師はこのペダルを使用できます
then about sex
それから性別について
And then there are many places
それから、いろんな場所があります
Many items are available
多くのアイテムが利用可能です
Can do research on science
科学の研究ができる
reminds me of being in that
その中にいたことを思い出します
There are many steps in the forest of steles
石碑の森には段差が多い
In fact, using this site analogy
実際、このサイトのたとえを使用すると、
In fact, it is tantamount to making a fuss out of a molehill
実際、それはモグラ塚で大騒ぎするのと同じです
is that we can communicate with many
それは、多くの人とコミュニケーションが取れるということです
different categories
さまざまなカテゴリ
As a result, such research can be done
その結果、このような研究ができるようになります
Is it this way
こうですか
ok thank you teacher
わかりました、先生ありがとう
Materials actually help us understand
資料は実際に私たちの理解に役立ちます
Many handed down documents above
上記の多くの伝承文書
no way of knowing
知る由もありません
The problem with the pedals
ペダルの問題
just say sometimes context
時々文脈を言うだけです
not very clear
あまり明確ではない
if you know where it comes from
それがどこから来たのか知っていれば
then what is the context
それでは文脈は何ですか
Then make the content
あとはコンテンツを作る
Just like Yuan Chuntuo
袁春佛みたいに
there must be many things
たくさんのことがあるはずです
will help us open our eyes
私たちが目を開けるのを助けてくれるでしょう
It's something we couldn't imagine
それは私たちには想像もできなかったことです
thanks for your test
テストお疲れ様でした
I will let you know before the end
終了前にお知らせします
Feast of Knowledge in October
10月の知識の饗宴
back to our tree science group
私たちの樹木科学グループに戻る
Director Chen Guixian of Fate Institute
運命研究所所長 陳桂賢氏
Tell us about thermoelectric technology
熱電技術について教えてください
Topics from domestic refrigerators to space communications
家庭用冷蔵庫から宇宙通信まで
Everyone is welcome to sign up
どなたでもご登録いただけます
Then we thank Teacher Li again
それでは、リーさんにもう一度感謝します。
Thanks
ありがとう